<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:12:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation Proclamation</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-emancipation-proclamation/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation ProclamationThe White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation ProclamationThe White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation ProclamationThe White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

On January 1, 1863, President Abraham Lincoln signed the legendary Emancipation Proclamation—one of the most significant documents in human history and a grand edict that paved the way to the liberation of millions of slaves and the full glory of the American promise.

As the bloody Civil War raged into its second year and the Nation fought to preserve the Union, President Lincoln made a “fit and necessary” military decree that would redefine the entire conflict.  With the Emancipation Proclamation declaring that those held in slavery in the

rebellious states “shall be then, thenceforward, and forever free,” the purpose of the war shifted—and every Union advance now carried with it the blazing torch of liberty, justice, and dignity for all.

The Emancipation Proclamation set the stage for the ultimate abolition of slavery, culminating in the ratification of the Thirteenth Amendment nearly 2 years later.  It endures to this day as a monumental testament to the divine truth that equality is a sacred birthright granted not by government but by the hand of Almighty God.  It signaled the dawn of a new day in our Nation’s journey toward liberty and the inalienable rights of every citizen.  Its signing remains a morally defining moment in our national story and an enduring legacy of President Lincoln’s conviction that our country—which launched a revolution in the pursuit of freedom and human dignity—is “the last best hope of Earth.”

Today, in President Lincoln’s honor, we recommit to the eternal truth that the United States of America is blessed by God; is bound together by justice; and was, is, and will forever be a great Nation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-emancipation-proclamation/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of Princeton</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-princeton/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of PrincetonThe White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of PrincetonThe White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of PrincetonThe White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

On January 3, 1777, General George Washington and his battle-hardened Continental Army secured a decisive victory over the formidable British garrison at the Battle of Princeton—an epic clash that reignited the Revolution and steered the Patriots back on the path to independence.

During the “Ten Crucial Days” following General Washington’s legendary crossing of the Delaware River, Continental soldiers once again answered the call of liberty in extraordinary fashion.  After fending off a hard-pressed British attack at the Second Battle of Trenton, under the cover of darkness, General Washington led thousands of American soldiers in a careful evasion of the British Army, leaving campfires burning and sentries posted to disguise their departure.  In the light of daybreak, the enemy found an empty camp at Trenton—outwitted once again by the cunning and courage of General Washington—while the Continental Army were miles away confronting the British garrison at Princeton.

As battle was joined, the British initially gained the upper hand.  Charging with fixed bayonets, they overran an American position, and viciously stabbed Brigadier General Hugh Mercer, one of Washington’s closest aides, seven times, fatally wounding him.  As fresh Continentals and militia arrived, though, General Washington himself courageously rode to the front lines, rallying his troops to stand firm and press forward, before going on to break the British line and send the enemy reeling back into town and beyond.  Defeated, the British hoisted a white flag of surrender into the cold morning air—signaling that the Continental Army had reigned victorious once again.

That day, General Washington’s men won a crucial victory, revived our national spirit, and breathed new life into the cause of independence throughout the Colonies.  Nearly two and a half centuries later, the patriots’ renewed spirit of determination remains an enduring symbol of American strength, resilience, and grit.  Today, we pledge to continue the work of saving our country with the courage that burned in the hearts of the warriors at Princeton 249 years ago.  We honor their valiant legacy.  We vow to protect our inheritance of liberty against all enemies and to forge a future worthy of their sacrifice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-princeton/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Epiphany</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-epiphany/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on EpiphanyThe White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on EpiphanyThe White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on EpiphanyThe White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

Today, I join the millions of Christians in the United States and around the world celebrating the Epiphany—a joyous feast day commemorating the glorious manifestation of Jesus Christ as the Redeemer of mankind, Prince of Peace, and Savior of the world.

This sacred feast is one of the oldest and holiest days of the Christian faith.  Centuries before the birth of Jesus, the prophet Isaiah foretold the miracle of the Epiphany when, according to Holy Scripture, he declared:  “Nations shall walk by your light, and kings by your shining radiance.”  That ancient promise was fulfilled in glory when three wise men journeyed from the east, guided by a magnificent star that would lead them to the infant Son of God in the humble surroundings of a stable.

The wise men’s journey first led them to King Herod in Jerusalem, where they asked, “Where is the newborn king of the Jews?”  Dismissed by Herod, they journeyed on to the small town of Bethlehem, following the heavenly sign that drew them to the Messiah.  As the Bible tells us, “they were overjoyed” at the sight of the star.  Their joy deepened when they entered the birthplace of God Himself—who, in the most revolutionary act of love in all of history, took on human flesh to dwell among His creation.  In humble adoration, the wise men offered gifts of gold, frankincense, and myrrh—symbolizing Christ’s role as king of the universe, His divinity, and His incarnate mission as Savior of mankind.

Just as the star pierced the stillness of the night sky thousands of years ago, the light of Christ continues to shine through forces of darkness.  Every day, the life and divine teachings of Jesus continue to call all people—and all nations—to live in truth and courage.

Over the last year, the peace, hope, and love of Jesus Christ has touched our Nation and the world in extraordinary ways.  Before our very eyes, a new era of peace is sweeping across the globe.  Faith in God is resurging on American shores.  Religious freedom is coming back like never before.  As we celebrate 250 years of the United States of America—a Nation forged in faith, sacrifice, and an enduring trust in God’s divine providence—we thank our Creator for His extraordinary blessings and ask for a continued outpouring of grace upon our Nation and the world.

More than 2,000 years after His birth, Jesus Christ remains a guiding light for our country and for all of the human race.  This Epiphany, the First Lady and I join Christians in praying that the light of Jesus Christ will lead us ever closer to a future filled with justice, generosity, prosperity, and peace.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-epiphany/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Slavery and Human Trafficking Prevention Month</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-national-slavery-and-human-trafficking-prevention-month/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Slavery and Human Trafficking Prevention MonthThe White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Slavery and Human Trafficking Prevention MonthThe White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Slavery and Human Trafficking Prevention MonthThe White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 6, 2026

This National Slavery and Human Trafficking Prevention Month, my Administration renews our commitment to end the evil of human trafficking, restore law and order across our country, protect the most innocent among us, and ensure that every trafficker faces the full force of American justice.

Under the previous administration, hundreds of thousands of unaccompanied children who entered our country were lost, with many being placed in the hands of smugglers and sex traffickers.  This was not only a failure of policy—it was a moral catastrophe that allowed perpetrators of modern-day slavery to exploit our country and our borders.  Since returning to office, I have taken unprecedented action to shut down these human trafficking pipelines, rescue the innocent children put in harm’s way, and end the reckless policies that enabled this crisis.

On my first day in office, I immediately declared a national emergency at our southern border to stop the invasion of illegal immigrants and cut off the human trafficking routes that have devastated countless families.  I designated the criminal cartels—the primary trafficking networks—as Foreign Terrorist Organizations and initiated the largest mass deportation operation in American history.

Last summer, I signed the One Big Beautiful Bill into law, a landmark piece of legislation that dramatically expands the Department of Homeland Security and Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), secures historic funding for our Border Patrol, and authorizes the construction of hundreds of miles of new border wall.  My Administration launched a fund for sex trafficking survivors exploited through online advertisements to seek compensation from forfeited assets.  We have sanctioned more than 100 online scam operators, many of which used forced labor to seize billions of dollars from defrauded Americans and others worldwide.  We increased funding for the National Human Trafficking Hotline.  I signed the TAKE IT DOWN Act and Trafficking Survivors Relief Act to modernize our tools to fight human trafficking and enable survivors to rebuild their lives.  With these enhanced resources, our great law enforcement officers are now equipped with the tools needed to remove dangerous illegal aliens from our streets and dismantle human trafficking networks.

As a result of these decisive actions, our border has been secured, and the flood of illegal aliens entering our country has stopped.  For the seventh consecutive month, Border Patrol has released zero illegal aliens into our country.  ICE has also launched the Unaccompanied Children Safety Verification Initiative, partnering with local law enforcement to ensure that the unaccompanied minors abandoned by the previous administration are safe, cared for, and not being exploited by traffickers.

This month, we continue our resolve to secure a future where American families can live safely and freely, without the threat of criminal aliens who have no right to be in our country.  We are shutting down human trafficking rings, securing our borders, and deporting dangerous criminals to protect our people, communities, and great Nation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-national-slavery-and-human-trafficking-prevention-month/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of New Orleans</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-new-orleans/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of New OrleansThe White HouseJanuary 8, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of New OrleansThe White HouseJanuary 8, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of New OrleansThe White HouseJanuary 8, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 8, 2026

Today, our Nation remembers one of the greatest American tales of might and one of the grandest displays of American resolve in the history of our country—the legendary Battle of New Orleans.

As our last major engagement in the War of 1812 and our epic final struggle against the tyranny of the British empire, the Battle of New Orleans ensured the hard-fought flame of American liberty would never extinguish.  Following a series of skirmishes throughout December of 1814, in which the British sought to break the defenses of the revered Major General Andrew Jackson, Major General Sir Edward Pakenham committed 8,000 seasoned British regulars to overwhelm the smaller American force of just 5,700 outside the city.  The British objective:  Steal the vital commercial and defensive strongpoint situated at the mouth of the mighty Mississippi River—the city of New Orleans—for the crown.

The morning of January 8, 1815, dawned damp and foggy as British soldiers formed long, neat rows of crimson along the swampy marshes of southern Louisiana.  As the British began their attack, tradition holds that General Jackson—bracing behind a small canal and several hundred yards of defensive works—bellowed to his men:  “Give it to them, my boys!  Let us finish the business today!”

His men did just that.  In less than an hour, American fighters—with nothing but courage, confidence, and faith—killed, wounded, or captured more than 2,000 hardened British veterans.  The fog Sir Edward Pakenham hoped would conceal his attack lifted at the last moment, and his artillery bombardment from across the river materialized too late.  Sir Edward himself fell during the battle, and soon after, General Jackson’s force reigned triumphant with only 71 American casualties as the British made their retreat.  By the time the smoke cleared, New Orleans was safe.  The British were forever expelled from American soil.  And General Jackson was immortalized as an American hero and would later ascend to the Presidency.

To this day, January 8, 1815, remains one of the most significant days in our great national story.  More than 200 years later, as we celebrate our 250th year of American independence, we pay tribute to the heroes who defied every odd to secure our birthright of liberty.  We honor their immortal legacy of courage and resilience.  Above all, we vow that the triumphant spirit of the Battle of New Orleans—and our victory over foreign influence in the War of 1812—will forever live on in every American heart.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-new-orleans/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill S. 222 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-s-222-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 222 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 222 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 222 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

On Wednesday, January 14, 2026, the President signed into law:

S. 222, the “Whole Milk for Healthy Kids Act of 2025,” which modifies the requirements for milk provided by schools participating in the National School Lunch Program.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-s-222-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-1783-treaty-of-paris/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of ParisThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of ParisThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of ParisThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

On January 14, 1784, the Second Continental Congress ratified the decisive Treaty of Paris—the binding accord that ended the Revolutionary War, secured American independence, and triumphantly declared all 13 colonies “to be free sovereign and Independent States.”  Today, we celebrate this monumental milestone, and we pay tribute to the grit, greatness, and unyielding resolve of the patriots of 1776 who pledged their lives, fortunes, and sacred honor for freedom’s cause.

The cessation of hostilities with the British Empire, proclaimed on April 11, 1783, ended 8 years of brutal warfare and the most significant struggle for freedom the world had ever seen.  After the fighting ended, the difficult and lengthy peace talks required strategic negotiation, moral clarity, and skillful diplomacy.  To achieve lasting peace, the Second Continental Congress sent a trio of true American titans—Benjamin Franklin, John Jay, and John Adams—who defended American interests and fortified our fledgling Republic.  The treaty, signed on September 3, 1783, nearly 2 years after the epic British surrender at Yorktown, resulted in a glorious affirmation of American sovereignty.

Under the Articles of Confederation, then the governing framework of the United States, ratification of the treaty required a quorum of nine States.  On this day 242 years ago, the delegates convened in a State House in Annapolis, Maryland, and with the final vote from South Carolina, the treaty was unanimously ratified, and our birthright of freedom was finally secured.

This year—our 250th year of glorious American independence—we reaffirm the righteous principles that breathed life into our Republic more than two centuries ago.  We renew our resolve to uphold and defend peace through strength, the rule of law, loyalty to our citizens, and faith in Almighty God.  Above all, we vow that the timeless truths forged by our forefathers will forever remain a mighty beacon of hope, prosperity, and liberty to the entire world.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-1783-treaty-of-paris/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career Ambitions</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-inspires-americas-children-to-be-curious-use-ai-to-achieve-their-career-ambitions/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career AmbitionsThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career AmbitionsThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career AmbitionsThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump advanced her mission to improve America’s children’s understanding of artificial intelligence (AI) today. Her goal to empower the next generation with AI and education reached thousands of schools nationwide, in partnership with Zoom Communications.

America’s First Lady inspired participants, “The Age of Imagination is a new era, powered by artificial intelligence, where one’s curiosity can be satisfied almost magically, in seconds.”

The First Lady also emphasized that curiosity optimizes AI use, “History reminds us that curiosity is the driving force behind every great achievement. The world’s greatest minds – our writers, architects, scientists, and painters – all had endless interest about human nature, and they all questioned that which was yet to be answered.”

Zoom’s CEO &amp; Founder Eric Yuan, a clear leader in the TechEd space, stressed the need for AI safety, “AI is changing how we learn, work, and connect every day. That’s why it’s so important to help students and educators build AI literacy and feel confident using these tools in thoughtful, creative, and ethical ways.”

Mrs. Trump concluded, “Although artificial intelligence can generate images and information, only humans can generate meaning and purpose. Choose to let your imagination drive your intellectual progress. But never use AI as a quick solution. Be intellectually honest with yourself – use AI as a tool – but do not let it replace your personal intelligence.”

Mrs. Trump called on the international community to join her mission to empower children with technology and education during the 2025 United Nations General Assembly. The First Lady, Melania Trump, will be hosting the inaugural meeting of Fostering the Future Together at the White House this spring.

Remarks by First Lady Melania Trump (as prepared for delivery)

Curiosity For Intellectual Freedom

Thank you, Mr. Yuan, Zoom’s leadership in the TechEd space is unmatched. Your support directly advances my mission to prepare America’s next generation to use AI to enhance their education, and ultimately their careers. Indeed, this is an incredible time.

We are living in the Age of Imagination.

The Age of Imagination is a new era, powered by artificial intelligence, where one’s curiosity can be satisfied almost magically, in seconds. You are fortunate to have the capability to fulfill your dreams through the power of learning, with AI serving as the primary engine for creative exploration.

History reminds us that curiosity is the driving force behind every great achievement.  The world’s greatest minds – our writers, architects, scientists, and painters – all had endless interest about human nature, and they all questioned that which was yet to be answered.

Are you ready to produce your own movie? Do you want to build the next Dress to Impress empire? Have you ever wondered how to become the next master artist? Create your own song?

Every giant, at some point in time, questions the status quo. Their singular vision pushes humanity in a new direction.

Artificial intelligence is changing today’s world, and your curiosity should serve as the driving force. For the first time in history, the young girl dreaming of becoming a fashion designer and the young boy who wants to stand-up his cool animated superhero series can do so, from their own home.

Artificial Intelligence provides all the tools needed to implement your creative vision – today. You can develop movie characters, scripts, fashion, music, art – the entire ecosystem. All with AI.

But, what do you need to start? You need to harness your Imagination. In the new AI era, the most powerful skill is knowing what to ask, why it matters, and how to think beyond the first answer.

I encourage you to be stubbornly curious, think outside the box, and question everything.

Creators must stretch their minds to think differently. The world of possibility is endless, and AI is extending the conceptual in ways never dreamed of before. In the past, memorization unlocked opportunity. Today, your curiosity will open new doors to meaning, innovation, and leadership.

But we must remember, although artificial intelligence can generate images and information, only humans can generate meaning and purpose. Deep thinking, patience, and staying curious are where purpose begins.

Today, I urge you to take action: use AI to unlock new parts of your imagination. Lead with your id...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-inspires-americas-children-to-be-curious-use-ai-to-achieve-their-career-ambitions/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza Conflict</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/statement-on-president-trumps-comprehensive-plan-to-end-the-gaza-conflict/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsStatement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza ConflictThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsStatement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza ConflictThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsStatement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza ConflictThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Yesterday, President Donald J. Trump congratulated the formation of the National Committee for the Administration of Gaza (NCAG), a vital step forward in implementing Phase Two of his Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza Conflict—a 20-point roadmap for lasting peace, stability, reconstruction, and prosperity in the region.

The NCAG will be led by Dr. Ali Sha’ath, a widely respected technocratic leader who will oversee the restoration of core public services, the rebuilding of civil institutions, and the stabilization of daily life in Gaza, while laying the foundation for long-term, self-sustaining governance. Dr. Sha’ath brings deep experience in public administration, economic development, and international engagement, and is widely respected for his pragmatic, technocratic leadership and understanding of Gaza’s institutional realities.

This milestone perfectly aligns with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2803 (2025), which endorsed President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan and welcomed the establishment of the Board of Peace. The Board of Peace will play an essential role in fulfilling all 20 points of the President’s plan, providing strategic oversight, mobilizing international resources, and ensuring accountability as Gaza transitions from conflict to peace and development.

To operationalize the Board of Peace’s vision—under the chairmanship of President Donald J. Trump—a founding Executive Board has been formed, composed of leaders with experience across diplomacy, development, infrastructure, and economic strategy. The appointed members are:

Each Executive Board member will oversee a defined portfolio critical to Gaza’s stabilization and long-term success, including, but not limited to, governance capacity-building, regional relations, reconstruction, investment attraction, large-scale funding, and capital mobilization.

In support of this operating model, the Chairman has appointed Aryeh Lightstone and Josh Gruenbaum as senior advisors to the Board of Peace, charged with leading day-to-day strategy and operations, and translating the Board’s mandate and diplomatic priorities into disciplined execution.

H.E. Nickolay Mladenov, an Executive Board member, will serve as the High Representative for Gaza. In this capacity, he will act as the on-the-ground link between the Board of Peace and the NCAG. He will support the Board’s oversight of all aspects of Gaza’s governance, reconstruction, and development, while ensuring coordination across civilian and security pillars.

To establish security, preserve peace, and establish a durable terror-free environment, Major General Jasper Jeffers has been appointed Commander of the International Stabilization Force (ISF), where he will lead security operations, support comprehensive demilitarization, and enable the safe delivery of humanitarian aid and reconstruction materials.

In support of the Office of the High Representative and the NCAG, a Gaza Executive Board is being established. The Board will help support effective governance and the delivery of best-in-class services that advance peace, stability, and prosperity for the people of Gaza. The appointed members are:

The United States remains fully committed to supporting this transitional framework, working in close partnership with Israel, key Arab nations, and the international community to achieve the objectives of the Comprehensive Plan. The President calls on all parties to cooperate fully with the NCAG, the Board of Peace, and the International Stabilization Force to ensure the swift and successful implementation of the Comprehensive Plan.

Additional Executive Board and Gaza Executive Board members will be announced over the coming weeks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/statement-on-president-trumps-comprehensive-plan-to-end-the-gaza-conflict/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin Franklin</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-benjamin-franklin/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin FranklinThe White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin FranklinThe White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin FranklinThe White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Today, we celebrate the towering life and legacy of Benjamin Franklin—printer and philosopher, inventor and diplomat, public servant and patriot, and one of the most consequential Americans to ever live.  On what would have been his 320th birthday, we honor his restless genius, his steadfast devotion to liberty, and his legendary contributions to our national story.

Born on January 17, 1706, in Boston, Massachusetts, Franklin grew up the 15th of 17 children.  Raised with little formal education, he taught himself how to read and write, emerging at age 23 as one of the most successful and influential publishers in the Colonies.  He was also a passionate innovator, always striving to improve the lives of his fellow citizens through public service and the marvels of science.  Throughout his life, he invented the lightning rod and the first bifocal glasses, harnessed the power of electricity with his famous “key and kite” experiment, established the first public library and volunteer fire department, and served as the first Postmaster General, binding the Colonies together with an organized mail system long before they were bound together as one Nation.

Of his countless triumphs and successes, his most epic contributions to our Republic were those that fortified the cause of freedom.  While living in England as an ambassador for the Pennsylvania Assembly, Franklin witnessed firsthand the growing British hostility toward the Colonies.  In 1775, Franklin was selected as a delegate to the Second Continental Congress, where, together with fellow patriots John Adams and Thomas Jefferson, he helped draft the Declaration of Independence, suggesting to Jefferson that he include the immortal phrase:  “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal.”

Franklin’s unshakable commitment to the causes of the Revolution ultimately led him across the Atlantic once more, where he played a pivotal role in securing French support for the patriot cause against the British Empire and acted as a principal negotiator of the 1783 Treaty of Paris, which ended the Revolutionary War.  After American independence was finally won, he played a vital role in rallying support for the ratification of the Constitution in 1788.  Franklin is one of only six men to have signed both the Declaration of Independence and the Constitution.

Benjamin Franklin is often remembered as the “First American”—a title that reflects a life devoted to curiosity, industry, and the cause of human freedom.  His intellect and character helped shape an American identity grounded in courage, self-reliance, and civic duty.  Franklin gave the young country confidence and direction, demonstrating how knowledge and public service could advance the cause of liberty.  His legacy endures in our institutions, our Constitution, and the very character of our Republic—a testament to how one man’s ideas and actions can echo through the history of a nation for 250 glorious years.

Happy birthday, Benjamin Franklin!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-benjamin-franklin/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
