<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 20:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on Framework for United States-Guatemala Agreement on Reciprocal Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-guatemala-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-GUATEMALA AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-GUATEMALA AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-GUATEMALA AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 13, 2025

The United States of America (United States, or U.S.) and the Republic ofGuatemala(Guatemala) have agreed to aFrameworkfor anAgreement on Reciprocal Trade(Agreement) that further strengthens and builds upon our long-standing economic relationship, including the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA-DR), which entered into force for the United States and Guatemala in 2006.

Key terms of the Agreement between the United States and Guatemala will include:

In the coming weeks, the United States and Guatemala will work to finalize the Agreement, prepare the Agreement for signature, and undertake domestic formalities in advance of the Agreement entering into force. Given Guatemala’s commitment to take significant steps to advance a stronger and more reciprocal trade relationship, the United States will remove the reciprocal tariffs on Guatemala’s exports to the United States for certain qualifying exports that cannot be grown, mined, or naturally produced in the United States in sufficient quantities, as well as certain products, such as textiles and apparel products, originating under the CAFTA-DR. The United States and Guatemala look forward to closing the Agreement soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-guatemala-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on Framework for United States-Ecuador Agreement on Reciprocal Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-ecuador-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-ECUADOR AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-ECUADOR AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-ECUADOR AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 13, 2025

President Donald J. Trump and President Daniel Noboa affirm a shared vision of growth for both of our countries, grounded in democratic values, private initiative, and a rules-based environment for commerce and innovation.  Seeking to strengthen our commercial and economic relationship, the United States of America (United States, or U.S.) and the Republic of Ecuador (Ecuador) have agreed to a Framework for an Agreement on Reciprocal Trade (Agreement) that will provide access to each other’s markets and increase alignment on economic and national security matters.

The Agreement will build upon longstanding economic engagement, including under the U.S.-Ecuador Trade and Investment Council Agreement, which was signed in 1990 and updated in 2020, expanding opportunities and fueling long-term growth.

Key terms of the Agreement between the United States and Ecuador will include:

The United States and Ecuador are working to finalize the Agreement, prepare the Agreement for signature, and undertake domestic formalities in advance of the Agreement entering into force.  Given Ecuador’s commitments to take significant steps to advance a more reciprocal trade relationship, the United States will remove its reciprocal tariffs on certain qualifying exports from Ecuador to the United States.

The United States and Ecuador will review progress on implementation of the Agreement and continue close coordination on trade and investment matters through their Trade and Investment Council.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-ecuador-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on Framework for United States-El Salvador Agreement on Reciprocal Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-el-salvador-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-EL SALVADOR AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-EL SALVADOR AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-EL SALVADOR AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseNovember 13, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 13, 2025

The United States of America (United States, or U.S.) and the Republic of El Salvador (El Salvador) have agreed to aFrameworkfor anAgreement on Reciprocal Trade(Agreement) that further strengthens and builds upon our longstanding economic relationship, including the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA-DR), which entered into force for the United States and El Salvador in 2006.

Key terms of the Agreement between the United States and El Salvador will include:

In the coming weeks, the United States and El Salvador will work to finalize the Agreement, prepare the Agreement for signature, and undertake domestic formalities in advance of the Agreement entering into force.  Given El Salvador’s commitment to take significant steps to advance a stronger and more reciprocal trade relationship, the United States will remove the reciprocal tariffs on El Salvador’s exports to the United States for certain qualifying exports that cannot be grown, mined, or naturally produced in the United States in sufficient quantities, as well as certain products, such as textiles and apparel products, originating under the CAFTA-DR.  In addition, the United States may positively consider the effect that the Agreement has on national security, including taking the Agreement into consideration when taking trade action under Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1862).  The United States and El Salvador look forward to closing the Agreement soon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-el-salvador-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on a Framework for a United States – Switzerland – Liechtenstein Agreement on Fair, Balanced, and Reciprocal Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-a-framework-for-a-united-states-switzerland-liechtenstein-agreement-on-fair-balanced-and-reciprocal-trade/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsJoint Statement on a Framework for a United States – Switzerland – Liechtenstein Agreement on Fair, Balanced, and Reciprocal TradeThe White HouseNovember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJoint Statement on a Framework for a United States – Switzerland – Liechtenstein Agreement on Fair, Balanced, and Reciprocal TradeThe White HouseNovember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsJoint Statement on a Framework for a United States – Switzerland – Liechtenstein Agreement on Fair, Balanced, and Reciprocal TradeThe White HouseNovember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 14, 2025

Today, the United States of America (United States), the Swiss Confederation (Switzerland), and the Principality of Liechtenstein (Liechtenstein) (collectively, Participants) express through this Framework their intention to negotiate an Agreement on Fair, Balanced, and Reciprocal Trade (Agreement). Through the Agreement, the Participants intend to create a dynamic and balanced trading relationship on a reciprocal and mutually advantageous basis, with a view toward creating good, high-paying jobs and economic growth in their markets. The Participants share a desire to make trade fairer, easier, and more substantial. The Participants further share a desire to foster secure and resilient supply chains and a conducive business environment to attract high-quality and trusted investment. Switzerland intends to take action to balance its trade with the United States, including by purchasing U.S. goods, facilitating investment in the United States, and removing tariff and non-tariff barriers for U.S. goods. The Participants intend to immediately begin negotiations of the Agreement with the aim to make significant progress, and if possible conclude the Agreement, by the first quarter of 2026, subject to their respective domestic processes.

The Participants intend for the negotiations of the Agreement to focus on the following key areas:

3.Non-Tariff Barriers and Related Matters

4.Digital Trade and Technology

The Participants intend to coordinate the timing of their respective domestic processes for the entry into force and implementation of the Agreement.

This document does not constitute a legally binding instrument creating or affecting any rights or obligations under international law.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-a-framework-for-a-united-states-switzerland-liechtenstein-agreement-on-fair-balanced-and-reciprocal-trade/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on American Education Week</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/presidential-message-on-american-education-week/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on American Education WeekThe White HouseNovember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on American Education WeekThe White HouseNovember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on American Education WeekThe White HouseNovember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 17, 2025

A great country demands a great education system—one that prepares our children to lead, innovates, and secures a stronger future for America.  This American Education Week, my Administration is committed to building an education system that empowers our students and families, prioritizes choice, and always pursues the good, the true, and the beautiful.

Since its creation in 1979, the Department of Education has spent over $3 trillion on “education” with virtually nothing to show for it.  Instead of building a more literate country, seven out of ten eighth graders today cannot read proficiently.  Instead of preparing future generations for careers in science and technology, math scores for 13-year-olds this year are at their lowest level in decades.  Instead of building a better education system, unaccountable bureaucrats dictated what children learn, which left our students further behind than ever before.  Schools designed for teaching became burdened by regulations and paperwork, and classrooms designed for discovery became laboratories for deranged social experiments, socialist political agendas, and divisive ideologies.  This national disgrace ended on January 20, 2025.

By dismantling the Department of Education, my Administration has returned control of education to where it belongs—with States, local communities, and parents who are best equipped to meet the needs of their students.  My Administration is also providing every available opportunity for parents to enrich the education of their children through individual choice.  We are rooting out the poisonous influence of gender ideology, Critical Race Theory, and the hollow dogmas of so-called diversity, equity, and inclusion from the halls of our educational institutions and in their place, we are restoring truth, merit, and patriotism.

As we fix failures of the past, we are also looking forward to the future.  With the support and leadership of First Lady Melania Trump, we are advancing artificial intelligence (AI) education for America’s youth and educators.  Through the Nationwide Presidential AI Challenge, our students and teachers will cultivate the skills and understanding necessary to use and create the next generation of technology.  And dozens of leading American businesses, non-profits, and educational institutions have stepped up to help our Nation win the AI race, committing billions of dollars of investment in AI education programs.

Every American student deserves a high-quality education.  Through these actions, my Administration is restoring common sense to classrooms, returning real authority to parents, and building a generation of thinkers, builders, and leaders who are ready to carry our Nation forward.  America’s Golden Age begins in the classroom, and by restoring the greatest education system in the world, we are building a stronger future for our culture, our children, and our beloved country.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/presidential-message-on-american-education-week/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Gettysburg Address</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-gettysburg-address/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Gettysburg AddressThe White HouseNovember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Gettysburg AddressThe White HouseNovember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Gettysburg AddressThe White HouseNovember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 19, 2025

Today, our Nation marks the 162nd anniversary of the Gettysburg Address, the brief yet immortal speech through which President Abraham Lincoln transformed a battlefield of sacrifice into a hallowed testament to our enduring principles and the nation built to defend them.  In honoring that day of solemn dedication, we reflect on what it means to be a country united by liberty, tested by conflict, and strengthened by the conviction that our best days will always lie ahead.

In July of 1863, a fierce battle that determined the fate of our Union unfolded in the hills and fields of Gettysburg, Pennsylvania.  Commanded by Union General George Meade and Confederate General Robert E. Lee, soldiers from the North and South fought relentlessly in the most consequential battle of the Civil War.  After a brutal three-day struggle, Confederate forces were defeated at an immense price, and the battlefield was scarred by the loss of more than 7,000 men from all walks of life.  When President Lincoln visited the battlefield on November 19th to commemorate those who had perished in the fight, he did not boast of Union victory or vengeance.  He spoke instead of renewal, hope, and the debt our Nation owed to those who had given the last full measure of devotion.

In his address, President Lincoln dedicated a cemetery and reconsecrated a Nation to its founding promise.  He proclaimed that beyond the challenges that pitted a nation against itself, Americans are bound by a shared history and commitment to preserving our hard-won freedom.  His words lifted the gaze of an embattled Nation from the graves at Gettysburg to the horizon of a more perfect Union.  He reminded Americans that liberty is never self-sustaining—rather, it survives only through the courage and conviction of those willing to fight for it.  President Lincoln’s address transformed sorrow into strength and loss into purpose, binding the Nation’s wounds and reminding Americans that those who fought and perished did not die in vain, but fought to secure a new birth of freedom for our country.

More than two and a half centuries later, President Lincoln’s message still reaches across time to remind us of our proud history, our common bond, and our duties as Americans.  He called upon the people of this country in every age to stand as one Nation, preserve our liberty, and always defend our God-given right to self-government.  As we prepare to celebrate 250 glorious years of American independence, we renew our commitment to those timeless principles and continue our work to ensure that our great Nation remains worthy of the ultimate sacrifices that built and preserved it.  We will always remember our fallen heroes, cherish our freedom, honor our heritage, and forever uphold that a government of the people, by the people, and for the people, shall not perish from the earth.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-gettysburg-address/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 4405 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bill-h-r-4405-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4405 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4405 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4405 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 19, 2025

On Wednesday, November 19, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 4405, the “Epstein Files Transparency Act,” which requires the Attorney General to release all documents and records in possession of the Department of Justice relating to Jeffrey Epstein, and for other purposes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bill-h-r-4405-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North Carolina</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/first-lady-melania-trump-and-second-lady-usha-vance-visit-camp-lejeune-and-marine-corps-air-station-new-river-in-north-carolina/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North CarolinaThe White HouseNovember 21, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North CarolinaThe White HouseNovember 21, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North CarolinaThe White HouseNovember 21, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseNovember 21, 2025

On Wednesday this week, First Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance visited Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station (MCAS) New River in North Carolina, where they spent the day meeting with students, educators, military families and Service members from both installations.

Mrs. Trump and Mrs. Vance began the day at Lejeune High School where they joined a classroom to observe presentations by high school students on social media, artificial intelligence (AI), and technology. The engagement was linked to the First Lady’s emphasis on AI education through efforts like the Presidential AI Challenge and Fostering the Future Together, a BE BEST initiative. Mrs. Trump and Mrs. Vance then delivered brief comments and participated in a photo opportunity with students and United Service Organizations (USO) volunteers who were working to assemble care packages for deployed Service members with families on base.

Next, Mrs. Trump and Mrs. Vance visited an DeLalio Elementary School to visit kindergarten and 1st grade classrooms and observe reading and writing lessons. They finished their visit to the school by participating in arts-and-craft activities 3rd, 4th, and 5th grade students.

The visit concluded with a gathering at MCAS New River, where Mrs. Vance expressed gratitude to the Marines and Service members at Camp Lejeune. She touched on the Vice President’s service and Marine Corps’ strong traditions he proudly upholds. She highlighted the strength of Department of Defense Education Activity (DoDEA) schools and military families, praising their commitment to community and children’s education. She introduced the First Lady, commending her dedication to supporting children and families through Fostering the Future, a BE BEST initiative.

Mrs. Trump honored the Marine Corps’ recent 250th birthday, touched on the impact that artificial intelligence is having on modern warfare, and recognized outstanding Marines for their leadership and service. As the holiday season approaches—a time when many military families will celebrate with an empty seat at the table—the First Lady and Second Lady expressed their deep gratitude for the strength, resilience, and sacrifice of those who serve and the loved ones who care, love, support, and serve alongside them. Both ladies shared their heartfelt appreciation to military personnel, educators, students, and families at MCAS New River and Camp Lejeune for their warm welcome and for their steadfast service to the United States.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/first-lady-melania-trump-and-second-lady-usha-vance-visit-camp-lejeune-and-marine-corps-air-station-new-river-in-north-carolina/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on United States-Ukraine Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-united-states-ukraine-meeting/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyJOINT STATEMENT ON UNITED STATES-UKRAINE MEETINGThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Office of the First LadyJOINT STATEMENT ON UNITED STATES-UKRAINE MEETINGThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Office of the First LadyJOINT STATEMENT ON UNITED STATES-UKRAINE MEETINGThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseNovember 23, 2025

On 23 November 2025, representatives of the United States and Ukraine met in Geneva for discussions on the U.S. peace proposal. The talks were constructive, focused, and respectful, underscoring the shared commitment to achieving a just and lasting peace.Both sides agreed the consultations were highly productive. The discussions showed meaningful progress toward aligning positions and identifying clear next steps. They reaffirmed that any future agreement must fully uphold Ukraine’s sovereignty and deliver a sustainable and just peace. As a result of the discussions, the parties drafted an updated and refined peace framework.The Ukrainian delegation reaffirmed its gratitude for the steadfast commitment of the United States and, personally, President Donald J. Trump for their tireless efforts aimed at ending the war and the loss of life.Ukraine and the United States agreed to continue intensive work on joint proposals in the coming days. They will also remain in close contact with their European partners as the process advances.Final decisions under this framework will be made by the Presidents of Ukraine and the United States.Both sides reiterated their readiness to continue working together to secure a peace that ensures Ukraine’s security, stability, and reconstruction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-united-states-ukraine-meeting/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readout of Peace Talks in Geneva</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/readout-of-peace-talks-in-geneva/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsReadout of Peace Talks in GenevaThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsReadout of Peace Talks in GenevaThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsReadout of Peace Talks in GenevaThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Between Secretary Rubio, Special Envoy Witkoff, Mr. Kushner, Secretary Driscoll, and the Ukrainian Delegation

Today, Secretary Rubio, Special Envoy Witkoff, Mr. Jared Kushner, and Secretary Driscoll held an extensive and productive meeting with the Ukrainian delegation to review the latest draft agreements under discussion. The conversation was candid, detailed, and conducted in a spirit of partnership and shared purpose.The Ukrainian delegation affirmed that all of their principal concerns—security guarantees, long-term economic development, infrastructure protection, freedom of navigation, and political sovereignty—were thoroughly addressed during the meeting. They expressed appreciation for the structured approach taken to incorporate their feedback into each component of the emerging settlement framework.Ukrainian representatives stated that, based on the revisions and clarifications presented today, they believe the current draft reflects their national interests and provides credible and enforceable mechanisms to safeguard Ukraine’s security in both the near and long term. They underscored that the strengthened security guarantee architecture, combined with commitments on non-aggression, energy stability, and reconstruction, meaningfully addresses their core strategic requirements.Secretary Rubio and his team reiterated the United States’ firm commitment to ensuring that Ukraine’s sovereignty, security, and future prosperity remain central to the ongoing diplomatic process. They emphasized that this work is driven by President Trump’s goal of ending a war that has taken the lives of millions of people and preventing further loss of life through a durable and enforceable peace. Both sides welcomed the steady progress made and agreed to continue consultations as the agreements move toward final refinement.The meeting concluded with a shared understanding that today marked a significant step forward, and that continued close coordination will be essential as the Parties work toward a durable, comprehensive peace.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/readout-of-peace-talks-in-geneva/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
