<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 13:33:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on a Framework for United States-North Macedonia Agreement on Reciprocal, Fair, and Balanced Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/joint-statement-on-a-framework-for-united-states-north-macedonia-agreement-on-reciprocal-fair-and-balanced-trade/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON A FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-NORTH MACEDONIA AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL, FAIR, AND BALANCED TRADEThe White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON A FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-NORTH MACEDONIA AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL, FAIR, AND BALANCED TRADEThe White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ON A FRAMEWORK FOR UNITED STATES-NORTH MACEDONIA AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL, FAIR, AND BALANCED TRADEThe White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

The United States of America (United States) and the Republic of North Macedonia (North Macedonia) have agreed to a Framework for an Agreement on Reciprocal, Fair, and Balanced Trade (Agreement) to strengthen our bilateral economic relationship, which will provide both countries’ exporters expanded access to each other’s markets. The Agreement will strengthen our trade relationship, support shared strategic interests, promote economic growth, and deepen our transatlantic partnership.

Key terms of the Agreement will include:

• North Macedonia will eliminate customs duties for all U.S. industrial and agricultural goods exported to North Macedonia.

• The United States will maintain at 15 percent the reciprocal tariffs, as set forth in Executive Order 14257 of April 2, 2005, as amended, on originating goods of North Macedonia, and will also identify products from the list set out in Annex III to Executive Order 14346 of September 5, 2025, Potential Tariff Adjustments for Aligned Partners, as amended, to receive a zero percent reciprocal tariff rate. The United States and North Macedonia may consider other tariff modifications following conclusion of the Agreement, taking into account trade balances and other appropriate factors.

• The United States and North Macedonia will work to address U.S. concerns with non-tariff barriers imposed by North Macedonia that affect bilateral trade in priority areas.

• The United States and North Macedonia commit to hold consultations to address and prevent barriers to U.S. agricultural products in the Macedonian market.

• The United States and North Macedonia have committed to strengthen economic and national security cooperation to enhance supply chain resilience and innovation through complementary actions to address non-market policies of other countries, as well as to combat duty evasion and cooperate on investment reviews and export controls. This commitment includes cooperating to ensure that international procurement obligations benefit only those countries that have taken on the same commitments.

• The United States and North Macedonia note their intention to facilitate and enhance commercial ties.

• On energy sector opportunities, the United States and North Macedonia take note of the construction of an important new gas interconnector between North Macedonia and Greece, which will allow North Macedonia to enhance energy security and diversify energy sources, including through purchases of U.S. liquefied natural gas (LNG). North

Macedonia will commence purchase of U.S. LNG upon completion of the new gas interconnector.

• North Macedonia commits to adopt and maintain high levels of environmental protections and to effectively enforce its environmental laws.

• The United States and North Macedonia will discuss commitments on intellectual property protection and enforcement, including on geographical indications.

• The United States and North Macedonia will engage to address labor issues.

• The United States and North Macedonia recognize the importance of high-standard commitments on digital trade in order to foster an open and competitive digital economy. North Macedonia has committed not to impose a digital service tax and to support adoption of a permanent moratorium on customs duties on electronic transmissions at the World Trade Organization (WTO).

• The United States and North Macedonia recognize the importance of facilitating trade in services. North Macedonia reaffirms its commitment to the WTO Joint Initiative on Services Domestic Regulation.

The United States and North Macedonia will work to finalize the Agreement, prepare the Agreement for signature, and undertake domestic formalities in advance of the Agreement entering into force.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/joint-statement-on-a-framework-for-united-states-north-macedonia-agreement-on-reciprocal-fair-and-balanced-trade/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on American Heart Month</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-american-heart-month/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on American Heart MonthThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on American Heart MonthThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on American Heart MonthThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

This American Heart Month, my Administration renews our pledge to protect the American heart and to keep the American people safe, strong, healthy, and free.

Sadly, one of the gravest threats to American lives today is the deadly affliction of heart disease, which imposes hardship on untold numbers of families.  For this reason, as President, I urge every American to take charge of their health to decrease the possibility of a heart attack or stroke.  Genetics play a role in cardiovascular disease, but implementing targeted lifestyle choices and preventative measures—such as getting regular check-ups, exercising, controlling blood pressure and cholesterol, and maintaining a balanced diet—can improve the odds against illness, disability, and death for any individual regardless of family history.

Under my leadership, the Make America Healthy Again Commission is working tirelessly to improve the quality of life and longevity for every American and to ensure our healthcare system addresses the root causes of chronic disease.  My Administration has secured historic agreements with pharmaceutical manufacturers to significantly lower the price Americans pay for some of the world’s most popular drugs that can help with heart disease, obesity, and other conditions, and launched TrumpRx.gov to ensure American patients can access those lower prices.  We have also introduced the Great Healthcare Plan, building on our historic efforts to provide Most-Favored-Nation price relief for prescription drugs.  I urge Congress to enact this comprehensive plan, which will substantially benefit millions of Americans.

This American Heart Month, I encourage every citizen to make lifestyle changes and take preventative measures to improve the odds against illness, disability, and death.  We pray for the families devastated by loss, we honor the resilience of the survivors of heart disease, and above all, we rededicate ourselves to working toward a future where heart disease does not deprive the American people of long, productive, and fulfilling lives.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-american-heart-month/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Career and Technical Education Month</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-career-and-technical-education-month/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Career and Technical Education MonthThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Career and Technical Education MonthThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Career and Technical Education MonthThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

For 250 years, our Nation has been built by the hard work, ingenuity, and unwavering determination of patriots who work with their skilled hands and brilliant minds to make our country strong.  This Career and Technical Education Month, we reaffirm our commitment to preparing American workers and students to carry this proud tradition forward and to equipping them with the skills they need to forge a great American future.

Every day, my Administration is working to promote and expand career and technical education to increase employment opportunities, boost productivity, and usher in a new era of economic growth marked by emerging industries and cutting-edge technologies.  Today, Americans have more pathways than ever before to develop the skills they need for success.  As the economy roars back with explosive job growth and unprecedented investments in science and technology, America’s competitiveness depends on our ability to close the gap between the demand for skill and the qualified workers ready to step up and lead.  A strong workforce drives economic growth and national innovation—creating a stronger, more secure, and more prosperous America.

My Administration is committed to increasing and enhancing career education opportunities to equip millions of workers and students with practical skills to thrive in their careers.  To advance this goal, last April, I proudly signed an Executive Order to realign federal priorities with the need for skilled and highly trained workers. Building on this effort, last July, I signed into law a new student aid program, known as Workforce Pell Grants, to support learners who want to use Federal financial assistance to enroll in short-term, in-demand fields. Then, in August, my Administration releasedAmerica’s Talent Strategyto provide a blueprint for aligning our education and workforce systems to unleash the unbridled potential of American talent. In addition, we took several actions to advance artificial intelligence education for American youth.

We are slashing ineffective programs, investing in better employment and earning outcomes, and identifying alternative methods for workers to receive credentials of value beyond a traditional higher education degree.  Through our historic Trump Accounts initiative, we are expanding financial literacy and teaching our young people the virtues of capitalism.  And we have implemented a bold plan to expand apprenticeships with the ambitious goal of reaching and surpassing one million active registered apprentices.

This month, we honor the hardworking men and women who stand at the center of American innovation, ingenuity, and determination.  My Administration will never waver in preparing our workers and students to lead our Nation into a radiant American future defined by skill, tenacity, excellence, and strength.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-career-and-technical-education-month/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Embraces Love of Country &amp; Family to United States Armed Forces</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-embraces-love-of-country-family-to-united-states-armed-forces/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Embraces Love of Country &amp; Family to United States Armed ForcesThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Embraces Love of Country &amp; Family to United States Armed ForcesThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Embraces Love of Country &amp; Family to United States Armed ForcesThe White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseFebruary 13, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump shared a nostalgia-filled message about the role love letters have played in America’s military community in her remarks to military families and service members at Pope Army Airfield and Fort Bragg in North Carolina.

Mrs. Trump said, “Love letters have symbolized the union of patriotism and family devotion among our soldiers for 250 years. The harmony of love of country and love of family is what makes us uniquely American. It is this very balance which strengthens our military and builds our communities.”

President Trump and the First Lady joined the military and their families at Fort Bragg and Pope Army Airfield the day before Valentine’s Day. The First Lady added, “The President and I are grateful to be with you—to honor the passion you share through unmatched bravery, resilience, and service to our great Nation.”

President Trump and the First Lady saluted military families and the heroic members of the United States Army Special Forces who carried out the successful mission in Venezuela to bring Nicolas Maduro to justice. First Lady Melania Trump has long been an ardent supporter of America’s military.

Full Remarks by First Lady Melania Trump (As Prepared for Delivery)

On Love of Country and Love of Family

Good afternoon and thank you for your warm welcome.

The President and I are grateful to be with you—to honor the passion you share through unmatched bravery, resilience, and service to our great Nation.

Thank you for defending our freedom.

It is with immense pleasure for me to address the Fort Bragg and Pope Army Airfield community today. To our great armed forces of the United States stationed all over the world, I have a nostalgia-filled message: Happy Valentine’s Day!

Love letters have symbolized the union of patriotism and family devotion among our soldiers for 250 years. The harmony of love of country and love of family is what makes us uniquely American. It is this very balance which strengthens our military and builds our communities.

And now, it is my distinct honor to introduce your Commander-in-Chief—our leader who maintains a mission of peace through strength—President Donald J. Trump.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-embraces-love-of-country-family-to-united-states-armed-forces/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on the Daytona 500</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-the-daytona-500/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Daytona 500The White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Daytona 500The White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Daytona 500The White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

As we await the roar of engines at the starting line of the Daytona 500, we celebrate the “Great American Race” as an iconic showcase of our Nation’s ingenuity, competitive spirit, and proud tradition of excellence.

Throughout our Nation’s 250-year history, Americans have pushed boundaries, built boldly, and steered our country toward victory.  The Daytona 500 reflects the hard work and determination that have driven our Nation forward by transforming ambition into action and innovation into progress.  America’s drive to win will continue to fuel our Nation for generations to come because we will never stop building, never stop dreaming, and never stop striving for greatness.

While NASCAR brings millions of fans together, they are united by something greater than who wins the race:  faith in God, love of family, and pride in our great American Flag.  These great American ideals extend far beyond the race track—they guide us as one Nation under God.  As the cheers of patriots echo in honor of this glorious national tradition, we are reminded of the enduring spirit of freedom that makes America strong.

Melania and I send our best wishes to all those gathered at the “World Center of Racing” for a safe and fun race, and we give thanks to the men and women of our Armed Forces, whose selflessness and devotion to duty protect the freedoms we hold dear.  May God bless you, and may He continue to bless the United States of America.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-the-daytona-500/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Susan B. Anthony Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-susan-b-anthony-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Susan B. Anthony DayThe White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Susan B. Anthony DayThe White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Susan B. Anthony DayThe White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 15, 2026

Today, we honor the life and legacy of Susan B. Anthony—a true American giant and an unwavering advocate for the cause of human dignity.  On what would have been her 206th birthday, we recommit to the timeless truth she spent her life defending:  that every human being is made in the holy image of God.

Susan B. Anthony was a champion for women’s suffrage, abolition, the sanctity of life, and the dignity of work.  During her storied life, she co-founded the National Woman Suffrage Association, traveled the Nation delivering inspiring speeches to crowds of thousands, and never stopped fighting to advance the cause of liberty.  Her tireless efforts later laid the foundation for the ratification of the 19th Amendment—securing women’s right to vote.  Anthony is also remembered for her fierce moral clarity in condemning abortion and her steadfast work to end slavery.

My Administration is proudly carrying forth the torch of Anthony’s legacy by fearlessly protecting life, women, and families.  We are bolstering federal support for adoption, expanding vital resources for expectant mothers, defending equal opportunities for women and girls in athletics, ending taxpayer-funded abortion, and upholding the First Amendment freedoms that made Anthony’s extraordinary advocacy possible.

As we honor the monumental contributions of Susan B. Anthony to our great American story, we recommit as one people to building a Nation where every citizen can thrive, every child is cherished, and the blessings of liberty and justice are secured for all.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-susan-b-anthony-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Lunar New Year</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-lunar-new-year/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Lunar New YearThe White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Lunar New YearThe White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Lunar New YearThe White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Today, I send my best wishes to the millions of people of Asian heritage in the United States and around the world observing Lunar New Year and celebrating the Year of the Horse.

Lunar New Year is an ancient holiday marked by thanksgiving and joy.  It is a time to acknowledge the blessings of family and friends, reflect on the accomplishments and challenges of the past year, and plan for the future with anticipation and renewed hope.  Around the globe, Lunar New Year is ushered in with spectacular firework displays, festivals, traditional music, feasts, and gatherings, which strengthen community and family bonds.  It is also a fitting time to recognize the contributions of many legendary Asian Americans for their contributions to our culture, our prosperity, and our way of life.

Tradition holds that the horse represents momentum, vitality, passion, freedom, and adventure—traits that our Nation has embodied for 250 glorious years of American independence.  On this Lunar New Year, we celebrate these enduring virtues and carry them with us as we continue building upon America’s Golden Age.  As family, friends, and communities gather to welcome the start of Lunar New Year, the First Lady and I join in wishing you a year filled with health, happiness, good fortune, and peace.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-lunar-new-year/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Ramadan</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-ramadan-ecc0/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on RamadanThe White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on RamadanThe White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on RamadanThe White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 17, 2026

Today, I send my greetings and best wishes to all those celebrating Ramadan.

Every Ramadan stands as a reverent season of spiritual renewal, reflective meditation, and appreciation for God’s countless blessings.  This sacred time for many Americans emphasizes prayer and fasting, strengthens familial and community ties, and affirms our shared values of compassion, charity, mercy, and humility.

The God-given right to freely worship is a hallmark of our Nation and a pillar of our prosperity and strength.  For this reason, every day, my Administration is ensuring that all citizens can practice their faith, follow their conscience, and worship freely—because freedom of religion means the freedom to practice your religion proudly and without fear of persecution.

In this season of grace and goodwill, I offer my prayers for happiness and fulfillment at home, unity and peace throughout the world, and blessings in the year to come.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-ramadan-ecc0/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Ash Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-ash-wednesday/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Ash WednesdayThe White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Ash WednesdayThe White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Ash WednesdayThe White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

Today, the First Lady and I join the millions of Christians in the United States and around the world in observing Ash Wednesday—a solemn day of prayer and repentance and the beginning of the Lenten season.

Every Ash Wednesday, Christians receive ashes in the shape of a cross on their foreheads as a visible reminder of our belonging to Jesus Christ and our enduring need for penance.  For the next 40 days, in remembrance of Jesus’ 40 days of temptation in the desert, followers of Christ will pray, fast, and give alms to deepen their faith, reflect on His redeeming Passion and death, and prepare their hearts for the coming Easter miracle.

As the holy season of Lent begins, we are reminded that the practices of prayer, fasting, and almsgiving have been foundational to our strength from the earliest days of our national story.  From the Colonists who turned to prayer and fasting in the heart of the Revolutionary War to the unmatched compassion and generosity of America’s churches, hospitals, and charitable institutions, these righteous acts of faith over the centuries have always stood at the center of our identity, our heritage, and our way of life.

This Ash Wednesday, as we remember the Passion and ultimate sacrifice of Christ on the cross, we send our best wishes for a meaningful Lenten season.  Above all, as we prepare for the triumphant resurrection of Jesus Christ on Easter Sunday—the greatest miracle in the history of mankind—we pause to remember those sacred words:  “This is the time of fulfillment.  The Kingdom of God is at hand.  Repent, and believe in the Gospel.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-ash-wednesday/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.J.Res. 142 and S. 3705 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bills-h-j-res-142-and-s-3705-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J.Res. 142 and S. 3705 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J.Res. 142 and S. 3705 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J.Res. 142 and S. 3705 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 18, 2026

On Wednesday, February 18, 2026, the President signed into law:

H.J.Res. 142, which nullifies legislation enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia (D.C.) on December 20, 2025, titled D.C. Income and Franchise Tax Conformity Revision Temporary Amendment Act of 2025; and

S. 3705, the “Semiquincentennial Congressional Time Capsule Act,” which requires the Architect of the Capitol to create a congressional time capsule in commemoration of the Semiquencentennial of the United States.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bills-h-j-res-142-and-s-3705-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
