<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 13:16:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th Amendment</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-13th-amendment/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th AmendmentThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th AmendmentThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th AmendmentThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 6, 2025

On this day 160 years ago, the United States of America ratified the 13th Amendment of the Constitution, immortalizing a self-evident principle that stirred the hearts of patriots and forever changed the course of history:  “Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, except as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly convicted, shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to their jurisdiction.”

Today, our Nation proudly recognizes the ratification of the 13th Amendment as a morally defining moment in our great American story—and we recommit to upholding our country’s long-cherished principles of freedom, equal justice under the law, and the God-given dignity of the human person.

In his legendary Gettysburg Address, President Abraham Lincoln proclaimed that our Nation was “conceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.”  Guided by this principle, on January 1, 1863, he formally issued the Emancipation Proclamation to declare freedom for enslaved people.  Yet, the abolitionist cause was not fully complete without a constitutional solution.

Tragically, President Lincoln’s devotion to our founding principles cost him his life 8 months before the amendment to formally abolish slavery was ratified by three-fourths of the states—and he never lived to see the end of slavery on our shores.  Today, his immortal memory continues to live on in our hearts—and his timeless example of justice, unity, and statesmanship continues to inspire citizens all across our country.  To further President Lincoln’s vision, my Administration is working tirelessly to ensure that America will always be guided by the principles he cherished so deeply and that we will remain the freest, safest, and most prosperous Nation in the history of the world.

As we prepare to celebrate 250 years of glorious American independence, we honor the heroes who paved the path for the end of slavery on our land—and we applaud the brave men and women of the abolitionist movement who dedicated their lives to upholding the American promise.  Above all, we acknowledge that freedom’s triumph over tyranny on December 6, 1865, stands as an enduring reminder that America was, is, and will forever be a great Nation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-13th-amendment/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate Conception</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-feast-of-the-immaculate-conception/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate ConceptionThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate ConceptionThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate ConceptionThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Today, I recognize every American celebrating December 8 as a Holy Day honoring the faith, humility, and love of Mary, mother of Jesus and one of the greatest figures in the Bible.

On the Feast of the Immaculate Conception, Catholics celebrate what they believe to be Mary’s freedom from original sin as the mother of God.  She first entered recorded history as a young woman when, according to Holy Scripture, the Angel Gabriel greeted her in the village of Nazareth with news of a miracle: “Hail, favored one!  The Lord is with you,” announcing that “you will conceive in your womb and bear a son, and you shall name him Jesus.”

In one of the most profound and consequential acts of history, Mary heroically accepted God’s will with trust and humility:  “Behold, I am the handmaid of the Lord.  May it be done to me according to your word.”  Mary’s decision forever altered the course of humanity.  Nine months later, God became man when Mary gave birth to a son, Jesus, who would go on to offer his life on the Cross for the redemption of sins and the salvation of the world.

For nearly 250 years, Mary has played a distinct role in our great American story.  In 1792, less than a decade after the end of the Revolutionary War, Bishop John Carroll—the first Catholic bishop in the United States and cousin of signer of the Declaration of Independence Charles Carroll—consecrated our young Nation to the mother of Christ.  Less than a quarter-century later, Catholics attributed General Andrew Jackson’s stunning victory over the British in the climactic Battle of New Orleans to Mary.  Every year, Catholics celebrate a Mass of Thanksgiving in New Orleans on January 8 in memory of Mary’s assistance in saving the city.

Over the ages, American legends like Elizabeth Ann Seton, Frances Xavier Cabrini, and Fulton Sheen, who spent their lives glorifying God in service to others, have held a deep devotion to Mary.  The Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception, located in the heart of our Nation’s Capital, honors Mary as the largest church in North America.  The timeless hymn “Ave Maria” remains beloved by countless citizens.  She has inspired the establishment of countless churches, hospitals, and schools.  Nearly 50 American colleges and universities bear Mary’s name.  And, just days from now, on December 12, Catholics in the United States and Mexico will celebrate the steadfast devotion to Mary that originated in the heart of Mexico—a place now home to the beautiful Basilica of Our Lady of Guadalupe—in 1531.  As we approach 250 years of glorious American Independence, we acknowledge and give thanks, with total gratitude, for Mary’s role in advancing peace, hope, and love in America and beyond our shores.

More than a century ago, in the midst of World War I, Pope Benedict XV, the leader of the Roman Catholic Church, commissioned and dedicated a majestic statue of Mary, Queen of Peace, bearing the infant Christ with an olive branch so that the Christian faithful would be encouraged to look to her example of peace by praying for a stop to the horrific slaughter.  Just a few months later, World War I ended.  Today, we look to Mary once again for inspiration and encouragement as we pray for an end to war and for a new and lasting era of peace, prosperity, and harmony in Europe and throughout the world.

In her honor, and on a day so special to our Catholic citizens, we remember the sacred words that have brought aid, comfort, and support to generations of American believers in times of need:

Hail, Mary, full of grace, the Lord is with thee.  Blessed art thou among women and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.  Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners, now and at the hour of our death.  Amen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-feast-of-the-immaculate-conception/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military Families</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-calls-for-love-during-the-holiday-season-partners-with-toys-for-tots-supports-military-families/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military FamiliesThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military FamiliesThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military FamiliesThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 8, 2025

“This Christmas season, you, your friends, and your families should wish for the ultimate gift – love. After all, love travels further than Santa’s sleigh and America’s Ospreys,” affirmed First Lady Melania Trump.

Mrs. Trump arrived with Santa Claus at Marine Corps Base Quantico with Santa Claus aboard a V-22 Osprey today. To the delight of United States Marines, volunteers, and military families, Mrs. Trump, Toys for Tots, and the Toy Association continued their +75-year tradition, bringing extra joy to millions of children across America.

The First Lady framed the courage and resilience of military children, telling them, “You are the heart of today’s celebration.” She delivered remarks to hundreds of children inside a decorated and historic hangar, helped distribute toys, visited activity stations, and spent time with families whose loved ones serve both at home and abroad.

Mrs. Trump concluded by wishing all military families a Merry Christmas and expressing the Nation’s gratitude for the strength, generosity, and patriotism they share with their communities.

First Lady Melania Trump’s full remarks, as prepared for delivery:

Thank you, General Anderson.  It’s wonderful to join everyone here at Marine Corps Base Quantico.

You might be wondering why Santa asked me to bring him here today.  Well—this wonderful adventure is filled with Christmas sparkle and lots of love.

Santa’s reindeer—Rudolph, Dasher, Comet—all of them—they are resting in the North Pole.  They need to save all of their energy for their great flight around the world on Christmas Eve.  Santa told me they’re snuggled beneath warm, fluffy blankets, sipping candy-cane cocoa feeling the joy and love that will soon be shared with amazing children everywhere.

So, with his sleigh parked safely with his reindeer, Santa climbed aboard my Osprey and couldn’t stop smiling. I watched him gazing out of the window, grinning at all the wonderful American families below. Santa told me that the Osprey floated through the sky like a giant snowflake—but it is WAY faster than his sleigh could ever fly.

Today, we are here for one of the most beloved traditions of the holiday season: Toys for Tots, led by the United States Marine Corps Reserves. For more than 75 years, Marines and volunteers across America collect and deliver new toys to children who need a little extra joy during Christmas. All wrapped with love, and great care.

To everyone here at Quantico, and all those who support the Toys for Tots Foundation, thank you. This includes the Toy Association’s generous support. I am grateful for your partnership and dedication to promoting fun and creativity. You help bring the delight of Christmas morning to millions of children, and you remind us that: of all American traditions, kindness and love remain among our most powerful.

To the families of military personnel: you are the heart of today’s celebration. Your strength in the face of adversity is inspirational. Some of the children here today have a parent stationed away from home right now. I know this can be difficult. On behalf of our Nation, thank you.

And thank you to the parents and guardians who are here today. Your support and resilience empower our Marines to serve with honor and distinction. Whether near or far, you illuminate every occasion, enriching everyone’s life.

This Christmas season, you, your friends, and your families should wish for the ultimate gift—love. After all, love travels further than Santa’s sleigh and America’s Ospreys.

Thank you and Merry Christmas!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-calls-for-love-during-the-holiday-season-partners-with-toys-for-tots-supports-military-families/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American War</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-spanish-american-war/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 10, 2025

On December 10, 1898, the United States signed a historic peace treaty to end the momentous Spanish-American War.  The treaty reaffirmed the “Monroe Doctrine” by ending the age-old European foothold in the Western Hemisphere and signaled to the entire world that America was emerging as a major superpower not to be underestimated.  Today, we honor the unwavering courage, conviction, and sacrifice of every hero of liberty who fearlessly confronted forces of tyranny to defend our honor, our sovereignty, and our birthright of freedom.

As Cuba’s fight for independence escalated under King Alfonso XIII’s rule—leading to violent unrest that endangered American lives—the United States deployed the battleship USS MAINE to Havana, the capital of Cuba.  On February 15, 1898, a devastating explosion sank the ship, claiming the lives of more than 260 Americans.  This tragedy propelled the United States toward a momentous struggle for justice and ignited our Nation’s righteous determination to defend our interests and maintain our dominance in the Western Hemisphere.

The war swiftly unfolded as American troops and sailors advanced with decisive strength, securing victories from Cuba to the Philippines.  At the Battle of Manila Bay, United States forces destroyed the entire royal Spanish fleet within mere hours.  Additional fighting in Cuba was backed by Theodore Roosevelt’s legendary regiment of “Rough Riders,” a volunteer cavalry made up of cowboys, miners, and college athletes, who embodied the full measure of American strength, resilience, and grit.  These triumphant victories across land and sea brought the Spanish Empire to its breaking point and solidified the United States of America as the greatest military force in the world.

On this day 127 years ago, the Treaty of Paris formally ended the conflict and Spain relinquished its claim to Cuba and ceded Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Philippines to the United States—a pivotal moment that marked not only the conclusion of the war but the dawn of America’s role as a military superpower unlike anything the world had ever seen.

Today, we recognize the territories and partnerships forged by the Treaty of Paris, where the full force of American freedom has taken root.  Above all, we renew our commitment to a simple truth:  Peace is maintained through strength.  My Administration is proudly upholding this America First vision through our negotiations of historic peace deals in regions marked by decades of conflict—proving to nations around the world that we can turn the page on the days of endless wars and usher in a future defined by everlasting peace.

As we commemorate this anniversary of our victory in the Spanish-American War, we stand united in our unwavering commitment to peace, military strength, and the enduring principles that define the American spirit.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-spanish-american-war/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-104-105-106-130-and-131-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 11, 2025

On Thursday, December 11, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.J. Res. 104, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Miles City Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan Amendment”;

H.J. Res. 105, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “North Dakota Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan”;

H.J. Res. 106, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Central Yukon Record of Decision and Approved Resources Management Plan”;

H.J. Res. 130, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Buffalo Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resources Management Plan Amendment”; and

H.J. Res. 131, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Coastal Plain Oil and Gas Leasing Program Record of Decision.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-104-105-106-130-and-131-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John Jay</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-john-jay/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John JayThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John JayThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John JayThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Today, our Nation celebrates the 280th birthday of John Jay—the first Chief Justice of the United States, a titan of American sovereignty, and a key architect of our laws, our foreign policy, and our glorious American independence.

Born in New York City and raised with the timeless values of faith and civic duty, John Jay answered the call to public service at a moment when America was still fighting for its right to define itself.  As President of the Second Continental Congress, he played a central role in America’s struggle for independence, and after our victory in the Revolutionary War Jay helped to negotiate the Treaty of Paris—freeing us from tyranny and ensuring that American sovereignty was recognized all around the world.

Jay was also a central figure in molding the American constitutional order.  In 1787 and 1788, he took up his pen to author five essays ofThe Federalist Papers, articulating the eternal principles of justice that have defined our federal laws, our system of government, and our foreign policy for nearly 250 years—including his belief in a centralized Federal Government to protect the American people from the influence of nations overseas.  As the first Chief Justice appointed to the Supreme Court, he set in motion a judicial framework grounded in integrity, fairness, and the immortal promise of equal justice under the law.  And as one of our nation’s first great diplomats, the Treaty of Amity, Commerce, and Navigation that he negotiated with Great Britain kept America out of the French Revolutionary Wars and ensured a decade of peace for our fledgling nation.

He carried this same conviction from the national stage and into State governance as the second Governor of New York, where he oversaw the construction of roads and canals that supported the state’s early growth—laying a foundation that would shape major developments and lead to New York’s legendary skyline and resilient character in the generations that followed, a legacy I was proud to build upon.

As we prepare to celebrate 250 glorious years of American independence next year, we recognize John Jay’s lasting contributions to our government, our traditions, and our national character.  My Administration remains committed to preserving the principles he cherished so deeply—including that peace is preserved through strength, that our Nation’s foreign policy must always put America first, and that a nation without the rule of law ceases to be a nation at all.  Today, in John Jay’s honor, we reaffirm our commitment to liberty and justice for all and to carrying his extraordinary vision forward for years to come.

Happy birthday, John Jay!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-john-jay/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 12, 2025

On Friday, December 12, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 452, the “Miracle on Ice Congressional Gold Medal Act,” which awards three Congressional Gold Medals to members of the 1980 U.S. Olympic Men’s Ice Hockey team;

H.R. 970, the “Fairness for Servicemembers and their Families Act of 2025,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to periodically review the automatic maximum coverage under the Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance program and the Veterans’ Group Life Insurance program;

H.R. 983, the “Montgomery GI Bill Selected Reserves Tuition Fairness Act of 2025,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to disapprove courses of education provided by educational institutions that charge higher than in-state tuition to members of the Selected Reserves living in the state;

H.R. 1912, the “Veteran Fraud Reimbursement Act of 2025,” which improves repayment of veterans’ benefits misused by a fiduciary; and

S. 616, the “Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2025,” which revises the Federal charter for the Foundation of the Federal Bar Association by allowing certain corporate requirements to be determined by the bylaws of the Foundation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Hanukkah</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-hanukkah/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 14, 2025

I extend my warmest greetings to the Jewish community in the United States and all around the world as they begin their celebration of Hanukkah—the Festival of Lights and a joyous season of reflection and hope.

More than 2,000 years ago, the Jewish people rose up against the forces of tyranny and restored their freedom to worship and live according to their faith, fighting for the inalienable rights endowed by our Creator.  Following their tremendous victory, they sought to rededicate their Holy Temple.  As tradition tells us, although they only had enough oil to light the lamp in the Temple for one night, in a glorious sign of the Almighty’s divine providence, it remained aflame for 8 days.  In remembrance of this great miracle, over the next 8 days, families and loved ones will gather to light the menorah, which serves as an enduring symbol of light’s victory over darkness and the eternal triumph of good over evil.  Hanukkah is a thanksgiving for these miracles.

To this day, the menorah stands as an enduring symbol of liberty, of the idea that each citizen, in the words that George Washington wrote to the Hebrew Congregation in Newport, “shall sit in safety under his own vine and fig tree and there shall be none to make him afraid.”

This holiday season, my Administration continues to stand firmly with the Jewish people and defend the right of every believer to worship freely and without fear of persecution.  The flames of Hanukkah stand as a reminder of the strength and resilience of the Jewish people and of the spirit that continues to guide our Nation toward a brighter future.

Just as the grace of the Almighty brought the Maccabees to victory, it has sustained the miracle of America—a shining light to the entire world—for nearly 250 years.  As we continue to usher in the Golden Age, may the blessings of this season bring renewed peace, joy, and warmth to all those who celebrate.  Happy Hanukkah!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-hanukkah/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the Bulge</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-the-bulge/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Today, we commemorate the 81st anniversary of the legendary Battle of the Bulge—the largest and deadliest battle fought by American forces in the Second World War, which culminated in a blistering, brutal, and breakthrough Allied victory that ultimately forced the Nazi regime into total surrender.

After a series of sweeping victories across Western Europe—including the D-Day landings of American, British, and Canadian forces in Normandy, France—Allied forces were confident that the Nazi army was on the brink of collapse.  Desperate to halt the Allied advance and reverse their momentum, Adolf Hitler ordered a massive surprise offensive through the Ardennes Forest, aiming to split the Allied lines, capture a vital port, and force peace negotiations on more favorable terms for Germany.

On the frigid morning of December 16, 1944, Nazi troops numbering approximately 200,000 men launched their full-scale assault on Allied personnel resting in the Ardennes Forest.  Though they initially gained ground, the Germans soon encountered the unbreakable resolve and overwhelming strength of the Allied armies.  With reinforcements pouring in, more than 500,000 German and 600,000 Allied troops—including 500,000 American soldiers—battled in blinding snow and sub-zero temperatures for 41 excruciating days, including Christmas, as soldiers held the front lines in defense of our freedom far away from home.

The American-led Allies held firm and withstood relentless assaults, halting the German advance and inflicting devastating casualties.  They secured a crucial victory, shattering the resources and manpower of the enemy and setting the stage for the Allied invasion of Germany and the eventual collapse and surrender of the Nazi regime.  With 19,000 American soldiers tragically killed during the battle, the Battle of the Bulge stands as the single deadliest American military engagement of World War II—a testament to the indispensable role the United States played in securing the victory of the Allied powers and ending the war.  Without the sacrifice of our American soldiers, the war would not have been won, and our world today would look drastically different.

On the anniversary of the Battle of the Bulge, we honor the legacy of the soldiers who fought to save the world from tyranny, destruction, and evil.  And as we approach 250 years of American independence, we renew our resolve that the blessings of freedom are only secured by the devotion and sacrifices of the patriots willing to defend it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-the-bulge/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Wright Brothers Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-wright-brothers-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Today our Nation celebrates the heroic moment America took to the skies when Orville and Wilbur Wright launched the first controlled, machine-powered aircraft on December 17, 1903.  This Wright Brothers Day, we honor the genius and bravery of two pioneers from Dayton, Ohio, and we proudly carry their legacy forward by championing the imagination, perseverance, and bold ambition that gave rise to their magnificent achievement.

What the Wright brothers lacked in formal education, they matched with unrelenting drive.  Despite not earning high school degrees, Orville and Wilbur taught themselves the mechanical and engineering skills they needed to build their first aircraft.  They drew inspiration from European gliders and soon after attempted their own leap into the uncharted frontier of powered flight.  After 4 years of relentless research, design, and testing, their work paid off on a cold, gray day near Kitty Hawk when Orville lifted theirFlyerinto the air for 12 seconds, traveling 120 feet at just under 7 miles per hour.  Orville and Wilbur’s feat marked the first time in history that man lifted off the ground in a piloted, mechanized flying machine.

The Wright brothers’ epic feat on the windswept shores of North Carolina opened a new chapter of innovation for all mankind and began a new era of American aviation power that continues to propel our country upwards among the clouds and beyond.  Since that historic day in North Carolina, the United States has remained the world leader in flight and aviation.  Less than seven decades later, the Wright brothers’ triumph at Kitty Hawk led Americans to the moon, and my Administration is focused on returning there, and beyond to Mars.

We are also continuing the Wright brothers’ proud legacy by presiding over a new Golden Age of air travel and innovation.  Shortly after I returned to office, I signed an Executive Order restoring excellence and safety within the Federal Aviation Administration.  We are ending disastrous so-called “Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion” programs that put Americans at risk and restoring the sacred principle of merit to hiring practices.  Through the passage of the One Big Beautiful Bill, we are investing $12.5 billion to modernize air traffic control with cutting-edge technology.

America is also leading the way in supersonic flight.  I have ordered the administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to conduct groundbreaking levels of research and development into commercial supersonic flight, driving new advances in air travel that will incorporate the latest Artificial Intelligence technologies.

In the 122 years since the Wright brothers’ revolutionary flight, our Nation has never stopped gazing upward in wonder and hope.  As we commemorate Orville and Wilbur’s legendary achievement today, we pledge to carry their vision into every new frontier and keep America’s skies bright with the innovation, discovery, and unstoppable spirit that drive our Nation to new heights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-wright-brothers-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
