<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 13:15:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>White House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable Experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/white-house-christmas-2025-volunteer-performers-and-decorators-share-excitement-and-memorable-experiences/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyWhite House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable ExperiencesThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Office of the First LadyWhite House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable ExperiencesThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Office of the First LadyWhite House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable ExperiencesThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 19, 2025

First Lady Melania Trump and President Donald J. Trump continued the cherished annual tradition of welcoming volunteer performers and decorators from across the country to Washington, D.C., for White House Christmas 2025: Home Is Where The Heart Is.

A select number of volunteer decorators and performers representing communities nationwide were invited to take part in this historic celebration. Over Thanksgiving week, 150 volunteer decorators from 50 states and 2 territories traveled to our Nation’s Capital to help transform the White House for the holiday season. Ranging in age from 19 to 76 and representing a wide array of professions and backgrounds, these volunteers contributed their time, talent, and creativity in service to the People’s House.

In addition, over 25 volunteer performer groups from 22 states were selected to share their music throughout the season. Group sizes ranged from solo performers to ensembles of more than 30 members, featuring choirs, jazz bands, and instrumentalists whose performances reflected the diversity and richness of American musical traditions. Through their participation, these volunteers became a special part of White House history—sharing their artistry and service with visitors and helping create a Christmas experience defined by joy, creativity, and community.

Below is a brief summary of what communities across America are saying about their local performers and decorators selected to take part in White House Christmas 2025.

WVTM– Alabama decorator brings holiday cheer to the White House

WIAT (CBS 42)– Tuscaloosa florist chosen as White House volunteer Christmas decorator

Yellowhammer News– Alabama florist selected for prestigious White House Christmas decorating team

Alaska Watchman– Alaskans join faith-filled patriots to adorn White House in traditional Christmas décor

KAIT– Jonesboro florist selected to decorate White House for Christmas

Bakersfield.com– Local woman helps decorate the White House for the holidays

KDVR– Colorado woman chosen to help decorate the White House for the holidays

House.gov– Diaz-Balart Presents Congressional Record Celebrating Ave Maria Parish Choir

WINK– Naples worship team to bring Christmas spirit to White House Dec 2

@tkajazz on Instagram– The King’s Academy Jazz Ensemble Performs at the White House

Covenant Church of Naples | PCA on Facebook– Covenant Church Worship Team Performs at White House Christmas Event

Idaho News 6– Meridian woman heads to the White House to help deck the halls for Christmas

Idaho News 6– Meridian woman shares once-in-a-lifetime trip to decorate the White House for Christmas

Swinford Media Group– Market Street Music Conservatory choir to sing at the White House

Advantage News– Local decorator brings Christmas to life at The White House

KWCH– Kansas woman selected to decorate White House for the holidays

KSN– Retired Kansas teacher picked to decorate White House for Christmas

Owensboro Times– Owensboro musicians selected to perform at White House Christmas Open House

WEHT / CMH23– “Such an honor:” Owensboro musicians selected to perform at the White House

Owensboro Times– Lanham &amp; Malone reflect on surreal White House performance

The News Journal– WIS teacher discusses experience as White House volunteer holiday decorator

WYMT– Williamsburg teacher selected to decorate White House for holidays

The BayNet– Calvert County Youth Choir Selected To Perform At The White House Holiday Celebration

@kharmony_children_choir on Instagram– K-Harmony Children’s Choir

Manna24(in Korean) – K-Harmony Children’s &amp; Youth Choir Performs at the White House

East Wing Magazine– A Historic Home Buff’s Moment of Awe

The Parkersburg News and Sentinel– Executive Branches: Washington County woman thrilled to be among 2025 White House Christmas tree decorators

SuperTalk Mississippi News Facebook– Southwest Mississippi Community College Stage Band chosen to perform at the White House

SMCC Music Department on Facebook– White House performance announcement

WAPT– Brandon shop owner selected as White House volunteer decorator for 2025 Christmas season

KSNF– Missouri woman to help decorate White House for Christmas

Ozarksfirst.com– White House Christmas decorating volunteer chosen from Lamar

KRTV– Great Falls woman fulfills dream of decorating the White House for holidays

WOWT– Nebraska Gold Star mother helps decorate official White House Christmas tree

@mhchoirs ...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/white-house-christmas-2025-volunteer-performers-and-decorators-share-excitement-and-memorable-experiences/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 165 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-165-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL H.R. 165 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL H.R. 165 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL H.R. 165 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 19, 2025

On Friday, December 19, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 165, the “Wounded Knee Massacre Memorial and Sacred Site Act,” which directs the Secretary of the Interior to take actions necessary to place certain land in South Dakota into restricted fee status for the Oglala and Cheyenne River Sioux Tribes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-165-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on the Sixth Birthday of the United States Space Force</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-sixth-birthday-of-the-united-states-space-force/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Sixth Birthday of the United States Space ForceThe White HouseDecember 20, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Sixth Birthday of the United States Space ForceThe White HouseDecember 20, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Sixth Birthday of the United States Space ForceThe White HouseDecember 20, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 20, 2025

On December 20, 2019, I established the United States Space Force—America’s Guardians of the High Frontier—as the sixth branch of our Armed Forces.  Today, our Nation thanks the incredible Guardians who serve with honor and distinction and protect our people, our homeland, and our glorious way of life beyond the bounds of Earth.

Since the dawn of space exploration, America has been the world leader in technology, innovation, and discovery.  Every day, the heroic members of the Space Force carry out this legacy with precision and unrelenting expertise to ensure that the United States is always prepared to confront threats originating both on our planet and beyond our skies.  Through their selfless service, Guardians solidify America’s continued space superiority by deterring counterspace threats from our adversaries; delivering space capabilities like satellite communications, navigation, and missile defense, which empowers the greatest economy and military in the world; and ensuring safe and fair access to space for our American businesses and Armed Forces.  From fortifying our economy to defending our homeland and strengthening our military, the Space Force is indispensable to our security, our sovereignty, and our beloved way of life.

By establishing the United States Space Force, my first Administration took bold action to strengthen America’s ability to compete, deter, and win in space.  Today, with adversaries embarking on a relentless crusade to destroy American space capabilities with counterspace weaponry, the high frontier is emerging as the next domain in modern warfare.  For this reason, America’s Guardians and the civilian employees who support their mission play a crucial role in meeting these threats—including through the development and implementation of the Golden Dome, a cutting-edge missile defense shield to safeguard our citizens and infrastructure from aerial attack, which received federal funding from this year’s historic One Big Beautiful Bill.  As a result of our strong leadership, enthusiasm to serve has surged, with the Space Force shattering expectations by meeting its annual recruiting goals three months early this summer.  When America leads in space, America wins—and our military remains the strongest, most feared, and most lethal in every sphere of battle.

As Commander in Chief, I join the Nation in celebrating the sixth birthday of the United States Space Force.  Our Guardians keep our country safe, strong, and free both on our shores and in the vast domain of space, and we offer our endless gratitude for their service and sacrifice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-sixth-birthday-of-the-united-states-space-force/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-christmas/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on ChristmasThe White HouseDecember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on ChristmasThe White HouseDecember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on ChristmasThe White HouseDecember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 25, 2025

The First Lady and I send our warmest wishes to all Americans as we share in the joy of Christmas Day and celebrate the birth of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ.

The story of the Christmas miracle begins more than 2,000 years ago in Bethlehem, when angels appeared to humble shepherds to share the good news of a child born to bring hope to the world, declaring, “Glory to God in the highest.”  Guided by a magnificent star, the shepherds traveled a great distance to gather around a crowded manger where, in the dark of night alongside Mary and Joseph, they knelt before the Light of the World, the source of eternal salvation, and the living Son of God.

The birth of Jesus revealed the perfect expression of God’s boundless love and His desire to be close to His people.  More than two centuries later, we continue to rejoice in the gift of God’s only begotten Son as the graces of Christ’s life, death, and resurrection continue to pour out upon all who believe.

This Christmas, we also give thanks for the many blessings that God has bestowed upon our great Nation.  For nearly 250 years, the principles of faith, family, and freedom have remained at the center of our way of life.  As President, I will never waver in defending the fundamental values that make America the greatest country in the history of the world—and we will always remain one Nation under God.

Today, especially, we also remember the brave men and women of our Armed Forces who are unable to be with their families.  While their solemn mission keeps them far from home this Christmas, their service and sacrifice protect our freedom and allow Americans all across our country to celebrate in safety and peace.  We are grateful for their devotion, and we keep them and their loved ones close in our hearts.

During the Christmas season, we pray for an outpouring of God’s abiding love, divine mercy, and everlasting peace upon our country and the entire world.  To every American, and to those celebrating around the globe, we wish you a very Merry Christmas!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-christmas/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-216-s-284-s-2878-h-r-187-h-r-410-h-r-1491-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 26, 2025

On Friday, December 26, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 216, the “Save Our Seas 2.0 Amendments Act,” which authorizes appropriations for the Marine Debris Program through Fiscal Year (FY) 2029 and the Marine Debris Foundation for FY 2025; and modifies the administrative requirements of the Program and Foundation;

S. 284, the “Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act,” which retroactively reauthorizes the Congressional Award Board, which administers the Congressional Awards Program to recognize the achievements of young people, effective as if enacted on October 1, 2023, through October 1, 2028;

S. 2878, the “Great Lakes Fishery Research Reauthorization Act,” which reauthorizes funding to monitor, assess, and research fisheries in the Great Lakes Basin through Fiscal Year 2030;

H.R. 187, the “Modernizing Access to our Public Waters Act of 2025” or the “MAPWaters Act of 2025,” which directs the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior to standardize and publish date relating to public outdoor recreational access of Federal waterways and Federal fishing restrictions;

H.R. 410, the “Alaska Native Vietnam Era Veterans Land Allotment Extension Act of 2025”, which extends the Alaska Native Vietnam Era Veterans Land Allotment Program through December 29, 2030; and

H.R. 1491, the “Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act,” which requires the Department of the Treasury to treat the postponement of the tax return deadline to a federally-declared disaster or certain other events as an extension of such deadline for purposes of calculating the limit on a tax refund.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-216-s-284-s-2878-h-r-187-h-r-410-h-r-1491-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Anniversary of the Battle of Trenton</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-trenton/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Anniversary of the Battle of TrentonThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Anniversary of the Battle of TrentonThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Anniversary of the Battle of TrentonThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 26, 2025

On December 26, 1776, the full might of General George Washington’s Continental Army was revealed along the frozen riverbanks of Pennsylvania when the Patriots triumphed at the Battle of Trenton—one of the most legendary battles in American history, which rescued the Revolution and rekindled the cause of independence in the heart of every American.

Just months after the signing of the Declaration of Independence, the Patriots’ rally for freedomhad nearly collapsed.  Driven from New York, beaten across New Jersey, and forced into Pennsylvania, the Continental Army was exhausted, undersupplied, and on the verge of breaking down.  General Washington determined that only a bold and decisive victory could reverse the tides of misfortune.  Across the Delaware River, he saw in the Hessian troops in Trenton, New Jersey—German soldiers fighting for the British—a desperately-needed opportunity to seize back momentum and change the course of the war and the course of history.

On Christmas night, as a fierce winter storm swept across the region, Washington ordered 2,400 weary soldiers into boats and began his epic crossing of the Delaware River—a moment now immortalized in the American imagination.  Despite extraordinary dangers, his men pushed artillery, horses, and provisions through ice-choked waters for 11 hours, then marched 9 gruelingmiles—many without boots on their feet—toward Trenton through unrelenting cold, leaving a trail of blood in the snowy hills.

At dawn, General Washington’s troops gathered in frigid darkness to prepare for a surprise strike against the Hessian auxiliaries hired by the British.  They advanced on the town from two directions.  American cannons opened fire, Patriot infantry pressed forward, and the Hessian defenders— caught off guard—struggled to mount an organized response.  After 2 hours of close fighting, the 900 Hessian mercenaries surrendered, and the Continental Army emerged triumphant.

The crossing of the Delaware and the victory at Trenton—steered by the fearless leadership of General Washington—restored confidence in the American cause and changed the Revolution. The Patriots’ victory proved that courage and determination could overcome fear and despair.  Despite being exhausted, unpaid, under-equipped, and teetering on the edge of defeat, they valiantly showed the world that they were not only capable of winning but also that they would never waver in their righteous crusade for independence and that the American spirit would always triumph over forces of anguish, adversity, and affliction.

In the harsh winter of 1776, our ancestors demonstrated that, when the future of our Nation is threatened, Americans endure and prevail.  Their endurance in the face of cold, hunger, and uncertainty laid the foundation for the country we now uphold.  Today, we salute the valiant men whose victory at Trenton secured our proud inheritance of liberty.  As we approach 250 glorious years of American independence and continue the work of saving our country, we look to their unwavering grit, valor, and patriotism—and in their honor, we vow to never stop fighting for the sacred causes that sustain our Republic, our way of life, and our birthright of freedom.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-trenton/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-pledge-of-allegiance-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance DayThe White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance DayThe White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance DayThe White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Today, our Nation proudly celebrates the Pledge of Allegiance—a solemn and glorious oath that unites every citizen under one God and our beloved banner of red, white, and blue.  This National Pledge of Allegiance Day, I encourage every American to rededicate themselves to our Flag, our heritage, and the eternal principles that have guided our Republic for nearly 250 years.

The Pledge of Allegiance has been a foundation of American life since it was first written in 1892.  Its words gave our growing Nation a shared expression of duty—reminding students, civic leaders, and new Americans that they were active participants in the American story.  By reciting it aloud, citizens declare their loyalty to our Flag and to the values it embodies:  freedom, the rule of law, the dignity of life, and the duty to serve our country and our communities.

Through the trials of war and economic upheaval, the Pledge has been a steady reminder of the commitments every citizen makes.  Its words have inspired soldiers defending freedom abroad, motivated Americans to safeguard our constitutional way of life here at home, and strengthened the bonds of patriotism that unite communities all across our land.  Every generation recites the Pledge grounded in the recognition that to honor the Flag is to honor the Nation for which it stands.

Today, my Administration is strongly defending the value of American citizenship and respect for the American Flag.  Last summer, I signed an Executive Order to preserve the dignity of our Stars and Stripes, including by vigorously enforcing accountability for acts of Flag desecration tied to violence and lawlessness—because those who hate our Flag resent the history, heritage, and heroes it represents even more.  We are also authorizing the revocation of visas, residency, and naturalization for foreign nationals who desecrate the banner under which millions of American heroes have fought and died.  We will never again allow those who hate our country to openly disrespect our Flag—and we will never waver in defending the sacred heritage that unites the American people beneath its banner.

On this National Pledge of Allegiance Day, we renew our devotion to the ideals that define the United States and to the Flag that symbolizes our shared destiny:  one Nation under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-pledge-of-allegiance-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-1043-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 29, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 29, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 29, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 29, 2025

On Monday, December 29, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 1043, the “La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act,” which directs the Department of the Interior to convey approximately 3,400 acres of federally-managed land in La Paz County, Arizona, to the county at fair market value.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-1043-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 504 Vetoed</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-504-vetoed/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 504 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 504 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 504 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 30, 2025

I am returning herewith without my approval H.R. 504, the Miccosukee Reserved Area Amendments Act.

The subject of this bill is a specific area in the Everglades National Park known as the “Osceola Camp.”  In 1998, the Congress passed the Miccosukee Reserved Area Act, which authorized the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida (Tribe) to permanently occupy a certain area within Everglades National Park.  The reserved area did not include the Osceola Camp.  Nonetheless, the Tribe has a residential community in that area, including infrastructure for wastewater treatment and water supply, and is experiencing periodic flooding.  H.R. 504 would require the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Tribe, to take appropriate actions to safeguard structures within the Osceola Camp from flooding events.

The Osceola Camp was constructed in 1935, without authorization, in a low area that was raised with fill material.  It served as a family residence and gift shop initially, and then later a site for air-boat rides.  None of the current structures in the Osceola Camp are over 50 years old, nor do they meet the other criteria to be considered for listing in the National Register of Historic Places.

The previous administration developed a plan to protect and replace unauthorized infrastructure at the Osceola Camp, which could cost up to $14 million.  But despite seeking funding and special treatment from the Federal Government, the Miccosukee Tribe has actively sought to obstruct reasonable immigration policies that the American people decisively voted for when I was elected.

My Administration is committed to preventing American taxpayers from funding projects for special interests, especially those that are unaligned with my Administration’s policy of removing violent criminal illegal aliens from the country.  Ending the massive cost of taxpayer handouts and restoring fiscal sanity is vital to economic growth and the fiscal health of the Nation.  This principle carries especially heavy weight here; it is not the Federal Government’s responsibility to pay to fix problems in an area that the Tribe has never been authorized to occupy.

For these reasons, I cannot support the Miccosukee Reserved Area Amendments Act.  Therefore, it is my duty to return H.R. 504 to the House of Representatives without my approval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-504-vetoed/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 131 Vetoed</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-131-vetoed/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 131 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 131 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 131 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 30, 2025

I am returning herewith without my approval H.R. 131, the Finish the Arkansas Valley Conduit Act.

The Arkansas Valley Conduit (AVC) is a water pipeline currently being built to provide municipal and industrial water to communities in southeastern Colorado.  It was originally authorized as part of the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project in a bill signed by President Kennedy in 1962.  For decades it was unbuilt, largely because the AVC was economically unviable.  Under the original plan, the costs of the project were to be initially funded by the Federal Government, but repaid by local users, with interest, over a 50-year period following completion of construction.  But participants were unable to comply with that repayment obligation.

In 2009, President Obama signed the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009, which not only reduced the repayment obligation from 100 percent to 35 percent but also provided that miscellaneous revenues from the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project at large would count towards the AVC cost share.  Even then, however, construction did not begin until 14 years later, after the State of Colorado authorized $100 million in loans and grants for the project.

The current bill would now have the Federal Government extend the repayment period (on the already-reduced repayment requirement) for an additional 25 years, creating a 75-year repayment period.  The bill would also cut the interest rate in half.

More than $249 million has already been spent on the AVC, and total costs are estimated to be $1.3 billion.  H.R. 131 would continue the failed policies of the past by forcing Federal taxpayers to bear even more of the massive costs of a local water project — a local water project that, as initially conceived, was supposed to be paid for by the localities using it.

Enough is enough.  My Administration is committed to preventing American taxpayers from funding expensive and unreliable policies.  Ending the massive cost of taxpayer handouts and restoring fiscal sanity is vital to economic growth and the fiscal health of the Nation.

For these reasons, I cannot support the Finish the Arkansas Valley Conduit Act.  Therefore, it is my duty to return H.R. 131 to the House of Representatives without my approval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-131-vetoed/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
