<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:02:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 12, 2025

On Friday, December 12, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 452, the “Miracle on Ice Congressional Gold Medal Act,” which awards three Congressional Gold Medals to members of the 1980 U.S. Olympic Men’s Ice Hockey team;

H.R. 970, the “Fairness for Servicemembers and their Families Act of 2025,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to periodically review the automatic maximum coverage under the Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance program and the Veterans’ Group Life Insurance program;

H.R. 983, the “Montgomery GI Bill Selected Reserves Tuition Fairness Act of 2025,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to disapprove courses of education provided by educational institutions that charge higher than in-state tuition to members of the Selected Reserves living in the state;

H.R. 1912, the “Veteran Fraud Reimbursement Act of 2025,” which improves repayment of veterans’ benefits misused by a fiduciary; and

S. 616, the “Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2025,” which revises the Federal charter for the Foundation of the Federal Bar Association by allowing certain corporate requirements to be determined by the bylaws of the Foundation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Hanukkah</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-hanukkah/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 14, 2025

I extend my warmest greetings to the Jewish community in the United States and all around the world as they begin their celebration of Hanukkah—the Festival of Lights and a joyous season of reflection and hope.

More than 2,000 years ago, the Jewish people rose up against the forces of tyranny and restored their freedom to worship and live according to their faith, fighting for the inalienable rights endowed by our Creator.  Following their tremendous victory, they sought to rededicate their Holy Temple.  As tradition tells us, although they only had enough oil to light the lamp in the Temple for one night, in a glorious sign of the Almighty’s divine providence, it remained aflame for 8 days.  In remembrance of this great miracle, over the next 8 days, families and loved ones will gather to light the menorah, which serves as an enduring symbol of light’s victory over darkness and the eternal triumph of good over evil.  Hanukkah is a thanksgiving for these miracles.

To this day, the menorah stands as an enduring symbol of liberty, of the idea that each citizen, in the words that George Washington wrote to the Hebrew Congregation in Newport, “shall sit in safety under his own vine and fig tree and there shall be none to make him afraid.”

This holiday season, my Administration continues to stand firmly with the Jewish people and defend the right of every believer to worship freely and without fear of persecution.  The flames of Hanukkah stand as a reminder of the strength and resilience of the Jewish people and of the spirit that continues to guide our Nation toward a brighter future.

Just as the grace of the Almighty brought the Maccabees to victory, it has sustained the miracle of America—a shining light to the entire world—for nearly 250 years.  As we continue to usher in the Golden Age, may the blessings of this season bring renewed peace, joy, and warmth to all those who celebrate.  Happy Hanukkah!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-hanukkah/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the Bulge</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-the-bulge/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Today, we commemorate the 81st anniversary of the legendary Battle of the Bulge—the largest and deadliest battle fought by American forces in the Second World War, which culminated in a blistering, brutal, and breakthrough Allied victory that ultimately forced the Nazi regime into total surrender.

After a series of sweeping victories across Western Europe—including the D-Day landings of American, British, and Canadian forces in Normandy, France—Allied forces were confident that the Nazi army was on the brink of collapse.  Desperate to halt the Allied advance and reverse their momentum, Adolf Hitler ordered a massive surprise offensive through the Ardennes Forest, aiming to split the Allied lines, capture a vital port, and force peace negotiations on more favorable terms for Germany.

On the frigid morning of December 16, 1944, Nazi troops numbering approximately 200,000 men launched their full-scale assault on Allied personnel resting in the Ardennes Forest.  Though they initially gained ground, the Germans soon encountered the unbreakable resolve and overwhelming strength of the Allied armies.  With reinforcements pouring in, more than 500,000 German and 600,000 Allied troops—including 500,000 American soldiers—battled in blinding snow and sub-zero temperatures for 41 excruciating days, including Christmas, as soldiers held the front lines in defense of our freedom far away from home.

The American-led Allies held firm and withstood relentless assaults, halting the German advance and inflicting devastating casualties.  They secured a crucial victory, shattering the resources and manpower of the enemy and setting the stage for the Allied invasion of Germany and the eventual collapse and surrender of the Nazi regime.  With 19,000 American soldiers tragically killed during the battle, the Battle of the Bulge stands as the single deadliest American military engagement of World War II—a testament to the indispensable role the United States played in securing the victory of the Allied powers and ending the war.  Without the sacrifice of our American soldiers, the war would not have been won, and our world today would look drastically different.

On the anniversary of the Battle of the Bulge, we honor the legacy of the soldiers who fought to save the world from tyranny, destruction, and evil.  And as we approach 250 years of American independence, we renew our resolve that the blessings of freedom are only secured by the devotion and sacrifices of the patriots willing to defend it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-the-bulge/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Wright Brothers Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-wright-brothers-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Today our Nation celebrates the heroic moment America took to the skies when Orville and Wilbur Wright launched the first controlled, machine-powered aircraft on December 17, 1903.  This Wright Brothers Day, we honor the genius and bravery of two pioneers from Dayton, Ohio, and we proudly carry their legacy forward by championing the imagination, perseverance, and bold ambition that gave rise to their magnificent achievement.

What the Wright brothers lacked in formal education, they matched with unrelenting drive.  Despite not earning high school degrees, Orville and Wilbur taught themselves the mechanical and engineering skills they needed to build their first aircraft.  They drew inspiration from European gliders and soon after attempted their own leap into the uncharted frontier of powered flight.  After 4 years of relentless research, design, and testing, their work paid off on a cold, gray day near Kitty Hawk when Orville lifted theirFlyerinto the air for 12 seconds, traveling 120 feet at just under 7 miles per hour.  Orville and Wilbur’s feat marked the first time in history that man lifted off the ground in a piloted, mechanized flying machine.

The Wright brothers’ epic feat on the windswept shores of North Carolina opened a new chapter of innovation for all mankind and began a new era of American aviation power that continues to propel our country upwards among the clouds and beyond.  Since that historic day in North Carolina, the United States has remained the world leader in flight and aviation.  Less than seven decades later, the Wright brothers’ triumph at Kitty Hawk led Americans to the moon, and my Administration is focused on returning there, and beyond to Mars.

We are also continuing the Wright brothers’ proud legacy by presiding over a new Golden Age of air travel and innovation.  Shortly after I returned to office, I signed an Executive Order restoring excellence and safety within the Federal Aviation Administration.  We are ending disastrous so-called “Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion” programs that put Americans at risk and restoring the sacred principle of merit to hiring practices.  Through the passage of the One Big Beautiful Bill, we are investing $12.5 billion to modernize air traffic control with cutting-edge technology.

America is also leading the way in supersonic flight.  I have ordered the administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to conduct groundbreaking levels of research and development into commercial supersonic flight, driving new advances in air travel that will incorporate the latest Artificial Intelligence technologies.

In the 122 years since the Wright brothers’ revolutionary flight, our Nation has never stopped gazing upward in wonder and hope.  As we commemorate Orville and Wilbur’s legendary achievement today, we pledge to carry their vision into every new frontier and keep America’s skies bright with the innovation, discovery, and unstoppable spirit that drive our Nation to new heights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-wright-brothers-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter to the Smithsonian: Review of Smithsonian Exhibitions and Materials</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/letter-to-the-smithsonian-review-of-smithsonian-exhibitions-and-materials/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsLetter to the Smithsonian: Review of Smithsonian Exhibitions and MaterialsThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsLetter to the Smithsonian: Review of Smithsonian Exhibitions and MaterialsThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsLetter to the Smithsonian: Review of Smithsonian Exhibitions and MaterialsThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 18, 2025

The Honorable Lonnie G. Bunch III

Secretary, Smithsonian Institution

Subject: Review of Smithsonian Exhibitions and Materials

Dear Secretary Bunch,

In our previous correspondence, we requested that the Smithsonian Institution provide us with certain documentation, including current exhibition descriptions, draft plans for upcoming shows, upcoming programming materials, and internal guidelines used in exhibition development as part of a comprehensive internal review of selected Smithsonian museums and exhibitions. As noted in that letter, dated August 12, 2025, we requested that the original materials be submitted no later than September 11, 2025. In recognition of ongoing staffing transitions at the Smithsonian, we happily extended the time period for response. While we received a partial production of materials from your office on September 18, no other material has been produced by your office to us in the more than 90 days since that September date.

While we appreciate receiving the initial document production, that submission fell far short of what was requested, and the overwhelming majority of requested items remain outstanding. For your reference, attached hereto asExhibit Ais an internal memorandum prepared by staff members of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) that outlines the partial set of materials received and what we are still requesting.

Current wall texts and didactics, exhibition proposals and budgets, object checklists for upcoming programming, internal governance manuals, and chain-of-command records for content approval are not obscure archival requests. These are the records that every accredited museum is expected to maintain and produce without delay, as they provide the basis for responsible stewardship of significant national collections and for meeting the rigorous transparency standards imposed by federal law, the Smithsonian’s own directives, and the professional standards of the museum field.

The American Alliance of Museums (AAM), the International Council of Museums (ICOM), and the Association of Art Museum Directors (AAMD) all maintain that having this information readily available is best professional practice.  And, indeed, the Smithsonian Charter—codified at 20 U.S.C. § 46—similarly requires that “a fair and accurate record” be made ofallthe Institution’s “proceedings.”  This statutory obligation was later carried forward in Smithsonian Directive 501, which eliminated any doubt that the Institution must “create and keep complete and accurate records of its activities; maintain the integrity of those records; and preserve records of enduring evidential or historical value.”

As officials designated by the President pursuant to Executive Order 14253, “Restoring Truth and Sanity to American History,” it is our job to ensure that the Smithsonian is meeting these high standards.

We write this follow up letter with particular urgency and concern that the museums of the Smithsonian Institution be well positioned to play an important role during the historic yearlong celebration of our Nation’s 250th birthday that is fast approaching. We wish to be assured that none of the leadership of the Smithsonian museums is confused about the fact that the United States has been among the greatest forces for good in the history of the world. The American people will have no patience for any museum that is diffident about America’s founding or otherwise uncomfortable conveying a positive view of American history, one which is justifiably proud of our country’s accomplishments and record.

We therefore ask for your personal attention to ensuring the fulfillment of the documents requested in our original letter, which are noted inExhibit A. We look forward to receiving the complete materials at the earliest possible date but hopefully no later than January 13, 2025. We think it would be helpful for you to establish a chain of custody protocol so that OMB staff can track what materials are uploaded to the Dropbox by which Smithsonian personnel for the purposes of our cataloging and processing various asset types (photos vs videos vs documents, etc.).

As you may know, funds apportioned for the Smithsonian Institution are only available for use in a manner consistent with Executive Order 14253, “Restoring Truth and Sanity to American History,” and the fulfillment of the requests set forth in our August 12, 2025 letter.

Thank you in advance for your partnership and urgency. We are confident that you share our view that the Smithsonian Instit...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/letter-to-the-smithsonian-review-of-smithsonian-exhibitions-and-materials/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law-ed35/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 18, 2025

On Thursday, December 18, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 2283, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 201 West Oklahoma Avenue in Guthrie, Oklahoma, as the Oscar J. Upham Post Office; and

S. 356, the “Secure Rural Schools Reauthorization Act of 2025,” which reauthorizes the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 through fiscal year 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law-ed35/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement by the President</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/statement-by-the-president-7598/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsSTATEMENT BY THE PRESIDENTThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsSTATEMENT BY THE PRESIDENTThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsSTATEMENT BY THE PRESIDENTThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Today, I have signed into law S. 1071, the “National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026” (the “Act”).  The Act authorizes fiscal year appropriations for the Department of War (DoW), the Department of Energy national security programs, the Department of State, the Department of Homeland Security, the Intelligence Community, and other executive departments and agencies.  The Act will enable the DoW to carry out my Peace Through Strength agenda, protect the homeland from domestic and foreign threats, and strengthen the defense industrial base, while eliminating funding for wasteful and radical programs that undermine the warfighting ethos of our Nation’s men and women in uniform.  Importantly, the Act codifies aspects of over a dozen Executive Orders and actions taken by my Administration, including those focused on warfighter lethality, advancing homeland missile defense by fully supporting the Golden Dome for America plan, restoring America’s airspace sovereignty, and providing Federal recognition of the Lumbee Tribe of North Carolina.

Over the next 3 years, the United States will host numerous major events that necessitate new authorities to combat emerging security threats.  The Act includes the critical SAFER SKIES Act, which provides State and local law enforcement with the authority to protect against unmanned aircraft when they present a threat to the public and creates a new felony offense for a second violation of national defense airspace.  In addition, the Act provides key resources to ensure the continued security of the southern border from illegal immigration and transnational criminal organizations.

Although I am pleased to support the critical objectives of the Act, I note that certain provisions of the Act raise concerns.

Certain provisions of the Act, including sections 343, 1032-1035, 1048(d)(4)(B), 1266, 5143, and 8304(a), purport to dictate the position of the United States in external military and foreign affairs.  My Administration will treat these provisions consistent with the President’s constitutional authority as Commander in Chief of the Armed Forces and the President’s constitutional authority to conduct the foreign affairs of the United States, which includes the authority to recognize foreign sovereigns.

Several provisions of the Act, including sections 364(a), 383(d), 737, 851, 1070, 1235, 1245, 1253, 1546, 1622, 1806(c), 3111, 6102(b)(3), 6303, 6502(b), 6521, 6524, 6712, 7213, 8102(b), 8315(1)(A)(iii), 8341(a), 8361(b)(3)(A), 8363(h), and 8521, purport to require the President to submit information to the Congress — such as deliberative process and national security information — protected by long-recognized legal privileges.  My Administration will treat these provisions consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to withhold information, the disclosure of which could impair foreign relations, national security, the deliberative processes of the executive branch, and the performance of the President’s constitutional duties.

Additionally, section 1622 of the Act purports to require my Administration to provide the Congress with sensitive national security information on programs, operations, actions, and activities that become compromised or fail, and section 6504 of the Act purports to require the granting of security clearances to certain persons.  My Administration will implement these provisions only to the extent that they are consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to control the dissemination of sensitive national security information.

Several provisions of the Act, including sections 915(a) and 1046(a), purport to restrict the President’s authority to control the personnel and materiel the President believes to be necessary or advisable for the successful conduct of military missions.  While I share the objectives of the Congress with respect to maintaining the strength and security of the United States, my Administration will implement these provisions consistent with the President’s authority as Commander in Chief.

Other provisions of the Act, including sections 1249, 1268, 1507, 1546, and 1655, purport to require that the Congress receive a certification, notification, or report before the President directs certain military or diplomatic actions, including the withdrawal of troops below a minimum number in particular theaters.  I reiterate the longstanding understanding of the executive branch that such provisions encompass only actions for which such advance certification, notification, or report is feasible and consistent with the President’s constitutional authorities as Commander in Chief and his authority to condu...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/statement-by-the-president-7598/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill S. 1071 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-s-1071-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL S. 1071 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL S. 1071 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL S. 1071 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 18, 2025

On Thursday, December 18, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 1071, the “National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026,” which authorizes fiscal year 2026 appropriations principally for Department of War programs and military construction, Department of Energy national security programs, Intelligence programs, and Department of State programs; supports a military basic pay increase and other authorities relating to the United States Armed Forces; and provides authorities related to and makes other modifications to national security, foreign affairs, homeland, commerce, judiciary, and other related programs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-s-1071-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable Experiences</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/white-house-christmas-2025-volunteer-performers-and-decorators-share-excitement-and-memorable-experiences/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyWhite House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable ExperiencesThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Office of the First LadyWhite House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable ExperiencesThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Office of the First LadyWhite House Christmas 2025: Volunteer Performers and Decorators Share Excitement and Memorable ExperiencesThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 19, 2025

First Lady Melania Trump and President Donald J. Trump continued the cherished annual tradition of welcoming volunteer performers and decorators from across the country to Washington, D.C., for White House Christmas 2025: Home Is Where The Heart Is.

A select number of volunteer decorators and performers representing communities nationwide were invited to take part in this historic celebration. Over Thanksgiving week, 150 volunteer decorators from 50 states and 2 territories traveled to our Nation’s Capital to help transform the White House for the holiday season. Ranging in age from 19 to 76 and representing a wide array of professions and backgrounds, these volunteers contributed their time, talent, and creativity in service to the People’s House.

In addition, over 25 volunteer performer groups from 22 states were selected to share their music throughout the season. Group sizes ranged from solo performers to ensembles of more than 30 members, featuring choirs, jazz bands, and instrumentalists whose performances reflected the diversity and richness of American musical traditions. Through their participation, these volunteers became a special part of White House history—sharing their artistry and service with visitors and helping create a Christmas experience defined by joy, creativity, and community.

Below is a brief summary of what communities across America are saying about their local performers and decorators selected to take part in White House Christmas 2025.

WVTM– Alabama decorator brings holiday cheer to the White House

WIAT (CBS 42)– Tuscaloosa florist chosen as White House volunteer Christmas decorator

Yellowhammer News– Alabama florist selected for prestigious White House Christmas decorating team

Alaska Watchman– Alaskans join faith-filled patriots to adorn White House in traditional Christmas décor

KAIT– Jonesboro florist selected to decorate White House for Christmas

Bakersfield.com– Local woman helps decorate the White House for the holidays

KDVR– Colorado woman chosen to help decorate the White House for the holidays

House.gov– Diaz-Balart Presents Congressional Record Celebrating Ave Maria Parish Choir

WINK– Naples worship team to bring Christmas spirit to White House Dec 2

@tkajazz on Instagram– The King’s Academy Jazz Ensemble Performs at the White House

Covenant Church of Naples | PCA on Facebook– Covenant Church Worship Team Performs at White House Christmas Event

Idaho News 6– Meridian woman heads to the White House to help deck the halls for Christmas

Idaho News 6– Meridian woman shares once-in-a-lifetime trip to decorate the White House for Christmas

Swinford Media Group– Market Street Music Conservatory choir to sing at the White House

Advantage News– Local decorator brings Christmas to life at The White House

KWCH– Kansas woman selected to decorate White House for the holidays

KSN– Retired Kansas teacher picked to decorate White House for Christmas

Owensboro Times– Owensboro musicians selected to perform at White House Christmas Open House

WEHT / CMH23– “Such an honor:” Owensboro musicians selected to perform at the White House

Owensboro Times– Lanham &amp; Malone reflect on surreal White House performance

The News Journal– WIS teacher discusses experience as White House volunteer holiday decorator

WYMT– Williamsburg teacher selected to decorate White House for holidays

The BayNet– Calvert County Youth Choir Selected To Perform At The White House Holiday Celebration

@kharmony_children_choir on Instagram– K-Harmony Children’s Choir

Manna24(in Korean) – K-Harmony Children’s &amp; Youth Choir Performs at the White House

East Wing Magazine– A Historic Home Buff’s Moment of Awe

The Parkersburg News and Sentinel– Executive Branches: Washington County woman thrilled to be among 2025 White House Christmas tree decorators

SuperTalk Mississippi News Facebook– Southwest Mississippi Community College Stage Band chosen to perform at the White House

SMCC Music Department on Facebook– White House performance announcement

WAPT– Brandon shop owner selected as White House volunteer decorator for 2025 Christmas season

KSNF– Missouri woman to help decorate White House for Christmas

Ozarksfirst.com– White House Christmas decorating volunteer chosen from Lamar

KRTV– Great Falls woman fulfills dream of decorating the White House for holidays

WOWT– Nebraska Gold Star mother helps decorate official White House Christmas tree

@mhchoirs ...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/white-house-christmas-2025-volunteer-performers-and-decorators-share-excitement-and-memorable-experiences/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 165 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-165-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL H.R. 165 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL H.R. 165 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL H.R. 165 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 19, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 19, 2025

On Friday, December 19, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 165, the “Wounded Knee Massacre Memorial and Sacred Site Act,” which directs the Secretary of the Interior to take actions necessary to place certain land in South Dakota into restricted fee status for the Oglala and Cheyenne River Sioux Tribes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-165-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
