<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:02:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair House</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-emphasizes-the-importance-of-upholding-americas-storied-institutions-at-the-blair-house/</link>
      <description>Office of the First ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair HouseThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair HouseThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair HouseThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First lady

The White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Today, First Lady Melania Trump delivered remarks at the Blair House for a holiday reception by the Blair House Foundation and the Friends of Blair House. The Blair House, originally constructed in 1824, is steeped in American tradition.

“The Blair House has hosted some of the world’s most influential leaders, including kings, queens, presidents, and prime ministers. As America’s 250th anniversary approaches, we must consider the important role our nation’s institutions have played in shaping our core values. The Blair House, in particular, has been a beacon of dignity, cultural awareness, and attention to detail. America’s institutions, including the Blair House, honor legacy while transcending generations,” said First Lady Melania Trump.

Blair House, known as the President’s Guest House, fills a central and historic role in welcoming foreign leaders as they prepare for engagements at the White House. Mrs. Trump emphasized its significant as a place where relationships begin, trust is built, and diplomatic partnerships take shape.

Full Remarks by First Lady Melania Trump, As Prepared for Delivery:

Good afternoon, and thank you all for being here. It is a pleasure to join you during this beautiful Christmas season, and it is an honor to welcome you to Blair House.

Blair House holds a special place in the life of our nation. For generations, this residence has been the quiet, dignified bridge between the White House and the world. It has offered warmth, security, and hospitality to kings and queens, presidents and prime ministers, and leaders from every corner of the globe.

Blair House is an American institution. Built in the 1800’s, this structure’s legacy transcends generations. As we prepare to celebrate America’s 250th anniversary, we should reflect on the important role our institutions play in shaping our nation’s values.  Moreover, we must strive to do more than merely preserve our institutions, we must grow them with innovation so that each can shine for future generations.

Today, we celebrate not only this historic home, but the people who make its mission possible. Your generosity preserves a tradition of American hospitality.

As First Lady, it is a privilege to once again be part of this special chapter of American history. Blair House represents grace, stability, and the confidence of a nation that leads with strength, courtesy and kindness.

I am grateful to each of you – including the Blair House Foundation Board of Trustees and Chair, Sarah Perot, for your dedication to this cause. You help protect a place where diplomacy begins long before the cameras arrive and where friendships between nations can begin to take root.

Thank you again and best wishes to you and your families for a very Merry Christmas, Happy Hannukah, and a joyful and peaceful New Year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-emphasizes-the-importance-of-upholding-americas-storied-institutions-at-the-blair-house/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-visits-childrens-national-hospital-in-washington-d-c/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Today, First Lady Melania Trump continued the longstanding annual tradition of first ladies visiting the Children’s National Hospital during the Christmas season. Mrs. Trump spent time with young patients and their families to support the courageous children receiving care.

Mrs. Trump began her visit in the hospital’s atrium and continued on to the Hematology and Oncology Unit. She readHow Does Santa Go Down the Chimney?to a small group of young patients and their families. Throughout her visit, Mrs. Trump spoke with patients, families, doctors, nurses, and administrative staff, offering words of encouragement during this special time of year.

Following her visit, the First Lady remarked, “Visiting Children’s National during the Christmas season is a tradition I cherish, and I am grateful for the opportunity to return again this year. Spending time with these brave children and their families is a reminder of the strength, hope, and love that define the holiday spirit. I want to thank the dedicated doctors, nurses, and staff at Children’s National for the exceptional care they provide during the holiday season and every day.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-visits-childrens-national-hospital-in-washington-d-c/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention Month</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-impaired-driving-prevention-month/</link>
      <description>Office of the First ladyPresidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention MonthThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First ladyPresidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention MonthThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First ladyPresidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention MonthThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First lady

The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Every year, thousands of Americans are injured or killed by reckless drivers under the influence of alcohol and drugs.  This National Impaired Driving Prevention Month, we send our prayers and unending support to every American who has lost a loved one—and we reaffirm our commitment to preventing drug and alcohol abuse on our roads, protecting American lives, and making America safe, healthy, and strong.

Drugs and alcohol distort judgment, reduce reaction time, and compromise the ability to make safe decisions behind the wheel.  Impaired driving tragically claims an American life every 42 minutes.  For this reason, my Administration is working tirelessly to end the substance abuse crisis once and for all.

Since I returned to office, I have taken a series of bold and unprecedented steps to halt the flow of illegal drugs into our country by securing our borders and increasing support for law enforcement.  Under my leadership, the Office of National Drug Control Policy is taking action to address and prevent substance use disorders and disrupt the criminal networks that fuel them.  We are investing hundreds of millions of dollars in programs like the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program and the Drug-Free Communities Support Program to dismantle drug trafficking organizations and restore order and safety to our streets.  My Administration is also working to increase access to treatment so that every American battling drug and alcohol use has a path to total recovery and we will continue working with our partners in the states to raise awareness through high visibility enforcement campaigns, such asDrive Sober or Get Pulled Over.

This month, we remember all those whose lives were stolen by impaired drivers.  We extend our gratitude to the heroic police officers, first responders, healthcare workers, and local organizations who are working on the front lines to prevent these catastrophes.  Above all, we recommit to preventing these senseless tragedies—and we renew our resolve to never waver in putting the safety, health, and well-being of the American people first.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-impaired-driving-prevention-month/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-j-res-80-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

On Friday, December 5, 2025, the President signed into law:

S.J.Res. 80, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska Integrated Activity Plan Record of Decision.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-j-res-80-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on the Eighth Anniversary of Recognizing Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of Israel</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-eighth-anniversary-of-recognizing-jerusalem-as-the-capital-of-the-state-of-israel/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Eighth Anniversary of Recognizing Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of IsraelThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Eighth Anniversary of Recognizing Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of IsraelThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Eighth Anniversary of Recognizing Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of IsraelThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 6, 2025

On December 6, 2017, during my first term in office, I proudly signed a proclamation to officially recognize Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and to relocate the United States Embassy to that marvelous city—a transformative step forward in the pursuit of peace in the Middle East.  Today, 8 years later, my Administration renews its commitment to ushering in a new era of peace, prosperity, and stability in the region and all around the world.

For centuries, Jerusalem has been a sacred city of pilgrimage and worship for Jews, Christians, and Muslims, revered for its rich history and deep biblical origins.  Since the establishment of the modern State of Israel in 1948, Jerusalem has served as its cultural and religious heart and the seat of its government.  However, for decades, weak politicians refused to formally recognize Jerusalem as Israel’s capital—despite Congress voting to support the action—because they believed that moving our embassy would harm the cause of peace in the region.  Yet delaying the recognition brought us no closer to a lasting peace agreement and showed that repeating the same approach to old challenges produces only the same failed results.  In recognizing Jerusalem as Israel’s capital and moving our embassy to that beautiful city, we acknowledged the rightful capital that stands at the heart of Israel’s traditions, government, and heritage—and now we stand on the doorstep of one of the greatest diplomatic achievements in history as a strong, durable, and everlasting peace is emerging across the Middle East.

We further strengthened this commitment to peace during my first term by brokering the historic Abraham Accords, acknowledging Israel’s sovereignty over the Golan Heights, and securing groundbreaking peace agreements between Israel and other Arab-Muslim countries.

Ever since I returned to office as the 47th President of the United States, my Administration has built upon these unprecedented achievements by once again leading the world with courage, strength, and resolve—setting the stage for lasting peace in regions around the world marked by long-standing conflict.  I am proud to have led a significant peace agreement between the State of Israel and Hamas to end more than 2 years of profound suffering and loss, secure the full liberation of all hostages, and deliver humanitarian relief to the communities affected by this deadly war.  This monumental agreement is a massive leap toward an enduring peace for the Israeli and Palestinian people—one that ensures security, brings stability, and offers hope for generations to come.

As President, I will always work tirelessly to bring peace to conflicts in every region and on every continent—and my Administration will never waver in promoting a foreign policy of peace through strength.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-eighth-anniversary-of-recognizing-jerusalem-as-the-capital-of-the-state-of-israel/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th Amendment</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-13th-amendment/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th AmendmentThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th AmendmentThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 13th AmendmentThe White HouseDecember 6, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 6, 2025

On this day 160 years ago, the United States of America ratified the 13th Amendment of the Constitution, immortalizing a self-evident principle that stirred the hearts of patriots and forever changed the course of history:  “Neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, except as a punishment for crime whereof the party shall have been duly convicted, shall exist within the United States, or any place subject to their jurisdiction.”

Today, our Nation proudly recognizes the ratification of the 13th Amendment as a morally defining moment in our great American story—and we recommit to upholding our country’s long-cherished principles of freedom, equal justice under the law, and the God-given dignity of the human person.

In his legendary Gettysburg Address, President Abraham Lincoln proclaimed that our Nation was “conceived in liberty and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.”  Guided by this principle, on January 1, 1863, he formally issued the Emancipation Proclamation to declare freedom for enslaved people.  Yet, the abolitionist cause was not fully complete without a constitutional solution.

Tragically, President Lincoln’s devotion to our founding principles cost him his life 8 months before the amendment to formally abolish slavery was ratified by three-fourths of the states—and he never lived to see the end of slavery on our shores.  Today, his immortal memory continues to live on in our hearts—and his timeless example of justice, unity, and statesmanship continues to inspire citizens all across our country.  To further President Lincoln’s vision, my Administration is working tirelessly to ensure that America will always be guided by the principles he cherished so deeply and that we will remain the freest, safest, and most prosperous Nation in the history of the world.

As we prepare to celebrate 250 years of glorious American independence, we honor the heroes who paved the path for the end of slavery on our land—and we applaud the brave men and women of the abolitionist movement who dedicated their lives to upholding the American promise.  Above all, we acknowledge that freedom’s triumph over tyranny on December 6, 1865, stands as an enduring reminder that America was, is, and will forever be a great Nation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-13th-amendment/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate Conception</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-feast-of-the-immaculate-conception/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate ConceptionThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate ConceptionThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the Feast of the Immaculate ConceptionThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Today, I recognize every American celebrating December 8 as a Holy Day honoring the faith, humility, and love of Mary, mother of Jesus and one of the greatest figures in the Bible.

On the Feast of the Immaculate Conception, Catholics celebrate what they believe to be Mary’s freedom from original sin as the mother of God.  She first entered recorded history as a young woman when, according to Holy Scripture, the Angel Gabriel greeted her in the village of Nazareth with news of a miracle: “Hail, favored one!  The Lord is with you,” announcing that “you will conceive in your womb and bear a son, and you shall name him Jesus.”

In one of the most profound and consequential acts of history, Mary heroically accepted God’s will with trust and humility:  “Behold, I am the handmaid of the Lord.  May it be done to me according to your word.”  Mary’s decision forever altered the course of humanity.  Nine months later, God became man when Mary gave birth to a son, Jesus, who would go on to offer his life on the Cross for the redemption of sins and the salvation of the world.

For nearly 250 years, Mary has played a distinct role in our great American story.  In 1792, less than a decade after the end of the Revolutionary War, Bishop John Carroll—the first Catholic bishop in the United States and cousin of signer of the Declaration of Independence Charles Carroll—consecrated our young Nation to the mother of Christ.  Less than a quarter-century later, Catholics attributed General Andrew Jackson’s stunning victory over the British in the climactic Battle of New Orleans to Mary.  Every year, Catholics celebrate a Mass of Thanksgiving in New Orleans on January 8 in memory of Mary’s assistance in saving the city.

Over the ages, American legends like Elizabeth Ann Seton, Frances Xavier Cabrini, and Fulton Sheen, who spent their lives glorifying God in service to others, have held a deep devotion to Mary.  The Basilica of the National Shrine of the Immaculate Conception, located in the heart of our Nation’s Capital, honors Mary as the largest church in North America.  The timeless hymn “Ave Maria” remains beloved by countless citizens.  She has inspired the establishment of countless churches, hospitals, and schools.  Nearly 50 American colleges and universities bear Mary’s name.  And, just days from now, on December 12, Catholics in the United States and Mexico will celebrate the steadfast devotion to Mary that originated in the heart of Mexico—a place now home to the beautiful Basilica of Our Lady of Guadalupe—in 1531.  As we approach 250 years of glorious American Independence, we acknowledge and give thanks, with total gratitude, for Mary’s role in advancing peace, hope, and love in America and beyond our shores.

More than a century ago, in the midst of World War I, Pope Benedict XV, the leader of the Roman Catholic Church, commissioned and dedicated a majestic statue of Mary, Queen of Peace, bearing the infant Christ with an olive branch so that the Christian faithful would be encouraged to look to her example of peace by praying for a stop to the horrific slaughter.  Just a few months later, World War I ended.  Today, we look to Mary once again for inspiration and encouragement as we pray for an end to war and for a new and lasting era of peace, prosperity, and harmony in Europe and throughout the world.

In her honor, and on a day so special to our Catholic citizens, we remember the sacred words that have brought aid, comfort, and support to generations of American believers in times of need:

Hail, Mary, full of grace, the Lord is with thee.  Blessed art thou among women and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.  Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners, now and at the hour of our death.  Amen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-the-feast-of-the-immaculate-conception/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military Families</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-calls-for-love-during-the-holiday-season-partners-with-toys-for-tots-supports-military-families/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military FamiliesThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military FamiliesThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Calls for Love During the Holiday Season, Partners with Toys for Tots &amp; Supports Military FamiliesThe White HouseDecember 8, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 8, 2025

“This Christmas season, you, your friends, and your families should wish for the ultimate gift – love. After all, love travels further than Santa’s sleigh and America’s Ospreys,” affirmed First Lady Melania Trump.

Mrs. Trump arrived with Santa Claus at Marine Corps Base Quantico with Santa Claus aboard a V-22 Osprey today. To the delight of United States Marines, volunteers, and military families, Mrs. Trump, Toys for Tots, and the Toy Association continued their +75-year tradition, bringing extra joy to millions of children across America.

The First Lady framed the courage and resilience of military children, telling them, “You are the heart of today’s celebration.” She delivered remarks to hundreds of children inside a decorated and historic hangar, helped distribute toys, visited activity stations, and spent time with families whose loved ones serve both at home and abroad.

Mrs. Trump concluded by wishing all military families a Merry Christmas and expressing the Nation’s gratitude for the strength, generosity, and patriotism they share with their communities.

First Lady Melania Trump’s full remarks, as prepared for delivery:

Thank you, General Anderson.  It’s wonderful to join everyone here at Marine Corps Base Quantico.

You might be wondering why Santa asked me to bring him here today.  Well—this wonderful adventure is filled with Christmas sparkle and lots of love.

Santa’s reindeer—Rudolph, Dasher, Comet—all of them—they are resting in the North Pole.  They need to save all of their energy for their great flight around the world on Christmas Eve.  Santa told me they’re snuggled beneath warm, fluffy blankets, sipping candy-cane cocoa feeling the joy and love that will soon be shared with amazing children everywhere.

So, with his sleigh parked safely with his reindeer, Santa climbed aboard my Osprey and couldn’t stop smiling. I watched him gazing out of the window, grinning at all the wonderful American families below. Santa told me that the Osprey floated through the sky like a giant snowflake—but it is WAY faster than his sleigh could ever fly.

Today, we are here for one of the most beloved traditions of the holiday season: Toys for Tots, led by the United States Marine Corps Reserves. For more than 75 years, Marines and volunteers across America collect and deliver new toys to children who need a little extra joy during Christmas. All wrapped with love, and great care.

To everyone here at Quantico, and all those who support the Toys for Tots Foundation, thank you. This includes the Toy Association’s generous support. I am grateful for your partnership and dedication to promoting fun and creativity. You help bring the delight of Christmas morning to millions of children, and you remind us that: of all American traditions, kindness and love remain among our most powerful.

To the families of military personnel: you are the heart of today’s celebration. Your strength in the face of adversity is inspirational. Some of the children here today have a parent stationed away from home right now. I know this can be difficult. On behalf of our Nation, thank you.

And thank you to the parents and guardians who are here today. Your support and resilience empower our Marines to serve with honor and distinction. Whether near or far, you illuminate every occasion, enriching everyone’s life.

This Christmas season, you, your friends, and your families should wish for the ultimate gift—love. After all, love travels further than Santa’s sleigh and America’s Ospreys.

Thank you and Merry Christmas!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-calls-for-love-during-the-holiday-season-partners-with-toys-for-tots-supports-military-families/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American War</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-spanish-american-war/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 10, 2025

On December 10, 1898, the United States signed a historic peace treaty to end the momentous Spanish-American War.  The treaty reaffirmed the “Monroe Doctrine” by ending the age-old European foothold in the Western Hemisphere and signaled to the entire world that America was emerging as a major superpower not to be underestimated.  Today, we honor the unwavering courage, conviction, and sacrifice of every hero of liberty who fearlessly confronted forces of tyranny to defend our honor, our sovereignty, and our birthright of freedom.

As Cuba’s fight for independence escalated under King Alfonso XIII’s rule—leading to violent unrest that endangered American lives—the United States deployed the battleship USS MAINE to Havana, the capital of Cuba.  On February 15, 1898, a devastating explosion sank the ship, claiming the lives of more than 260 Americans.  This tragedy propelled the United States toward a momentous struggle for justice and ignited our Nation’s righteous determination to defend our interests and maintain our dominance in the Western Hemisphere.

The war swiftly unfolded as American troops and sailors advanced with decisive strength, securing victories from Cuba to the Philippines.  At the Battle of Manila Bay, United States forces destroyed the entire royal Spanish fleet within mere hours.  Additional fighting in Cuba was backed by Theodore Roosevelt’s legendary regiment of “Rough Riders,” a volunteer cavalry made up of cowboys, miners, and college athletes, who embodied the full measure of American strength, resilience, and grit.  These triumphant victories across land and sea brought the Spanish Empire to its breaking point and solidified the United States of America as the greatest military force in the world.

On this day 127 years ago, the Treaty of Paris formally ended the conflict and Spain relinquished its claim to Cuba and ceded Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Philippines to the United States—a pivotal moment that marked not only the conclusion of the war but the dawn of America’s role as a military superpower unlike anything the world had ever seen.

Today, we recognize the territories and partnerships forged by the Treaty of Paris, where the full force of American freedom has taken root.  Above all, we renew our commitment to a simple truth:  Peace is maintained through strength.  My Administration is proudly upholding this America First vision through our negotiations of historic peace deals in regions marked by decades of conflict—proving to nations around the world that we can turn the page on the days of endless wars and usher in a future defined by everlasting peace.

As we commemorate this anniversary of our victory in the Spanish-American War, we stand united in our unwavering commitment to peace, military strength, and the enduring principles that define the American spirit.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-spanish-american-war/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-104-105-106-130-and-131-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 11, 2025

On Thursday, December 11, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.J. Res. 104, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Miles City Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan Amendment”;

H.J. Res. 105, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “North Dakota Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan”;

H.J. Res. 106, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Central Yukon Record of Decision and Approved Resources Management Plan”;

H.J. Res. 130, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Buffalo Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resources Management Plan Amendment”; and

H.J. Res. 131, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Coastal Plain Oil and Gas Leasing Program Record of Decision.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-104-105-106-130-and-131-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
