<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 13:17:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North Carolina</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/first-lady-melania-trump-and-second-lady-usha-vance-visit-camp-lejeune-and-marine-corps-air-station-new-river-in-north-carolina/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North CarolinaThe White HouseNovember 21, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North CarolinaThe White HouseNovember 21, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance Visit Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station New River in North CarolinaThe White HouseNovember 21, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseNovember 21, 2025

On Wednesday this week, First Lady Melania Trump and Second Lady Usha Vance visited Camp Lejeune and Marine Corps Air Station (MCAS) New River in North Carolina, where they spent the day meeting with students, educators, military families and Service members from both installations.

Mrs. Trump and Mrs. Vance began the day at Lejeune High School where they joined a classroom to observe presentations by high school students on social media, artificial intelligence (AI), and technology. The engagement was linked to the First Lady’s emphasis on AI education through efforts like the Presidential AI Challenge and Fostering the Future Together, a BE BEST initiative. Mrs. Trump and Mrs. Vance then delivered brief comments and participated in a photo opportunity with students and United Service Organizations (USO) volunteers who were working to assemble care packages for deployed Service members with families on base.

Next, Mrs. Trump and Mrs. Vance visited an DeLalio Elementary School to visit kindergarten and 1st grade classrooms and observe reading and writing lessons. They finished their visit to the school by participating in arts-and-craft activities 3rd, 4th, and 5th grade students.

The visit concluded with a gathering at MCAS New River, where Mrs. Vance expressed gratitude to the Marines and Service members at Camp Lejeune. She touched on the Vice President’s service and Marine Corps’ strong traditions he proudly upholds. She highlighted the strength of Department of Defense Education Activity (DoDEA) schools and military families, praising their commitment to community and children’s education. She introduced the First Lady, commending her dedication to supporting children and families through Fostering the Future, a BE BEST initiative.

Mrs. Trump honored the Marine Corps’ recent 250th birthday, touched on the impact that artificial intelligence is having on modern warfare, and recognized outstanding Marines for their leadership and service. As the holiday season approaches—a time when many military families will celebrate with an empty seat at the table—the First Lady and Second Lady expressed their deep gratitude for the strength, resilience, and sacrifice of those who serve and the loved ones who care, love, support, and serve alongside them. Both ladies shared their heartfelt appreciation to military personnel, educators, students, and families at MCAS New River and Camp Lejeune for their warm welcome and for their steadfast service to the United States.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/first-lady-melania-trump-and-second-lady-usha-vance-visit-camp-lejeune-and-marine-corps-air-station-new-river-in-north-carolina/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on United States-Ukraine Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-united-states-ukraine-meeting/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyJOINT STATEMENT ON UNITED STATES-UKRAINE MEETINGThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Office of the First LadyJOINT STATEMENT ON UNITED STATES-UKRAINE MEETINGThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Office of the First LadyJOINT STATEMENT ON UNITED STATES-UKRAINE MEETINGThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseNovember 23, 2025

On 23 November 2025, representatives of the United States and Ukraine met in Geneva for discussions on the U.S. peace proposal. The talks were constructive, focused, and respectful, underscoring the shared commitment to achieving a just and lasting peace.Both sides agreed the consultations were highly productive. The discussions showed meaningful progress toward aligning positions and identifying clear next steps. They reaffirmed that any future agreement must fully uphold Ukraine’s sovereignty and deliver a sustainable and just peace. As a result of the discussions, the parties drafted an updated and refined peace framework.The Ukrainian delegation reaffirmed its gratitude for the steadfast commitment of the United States and, personally, President Donald J. Trump for their tireless efforts aimed at ending the war and the loss of life.Ukraine and the United States agreed to continue intensive work on joint proposals in the coming days. They will also remain in close contact with their European partners as the process advances.Final decisions under this framework will be made by the Presidents of Ukraine and the United States.Both sides reiterated their readiness to continue working together to secure a peace that ensures Ukraine’s security, stability, and reconstruction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/joint-statement-on-united-states-ukraine-meeting/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Readout of Peace Talks in Geneva</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/readout-of-peace-talks-in-geneva/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsReadout of Peace Talks in GenevaThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsReadout of Peace Talks in GenevaThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsReadout of Peace Talks in GenevaThe White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 23, 2025

Between Secretary Rubio, Special Envoy Witkoff, Mr. Kushner, Secretary Driscoll, and the Ukrainian Delegation

Today, Secretary Rubio, Special Envoy Witkoff, Mr. Jared Kushner, and Secretary Driscoll held an extensive and productive meeting with the Ukrainian delegation to review the latest draft agreements under discussion. The conversation was candid, detailed, and conducted in a spirit of partnership and shared purpose.The Ukrainian delegation affirmed that all of their principal concerns—security guarantees, long-term economic development, infrastructure protection, freedom of navigation, and political sovereignty—were thoroughly addressed during the meeting. They expressed appreciation for the structured approach taken to incorporate their feedback into each component of the emerging settlement framework.Ukrainian representatives stated that, based on the revisions and clarifications presented today, they believe the current draft reflects their national interests and provides credible and enforceable mechanisms to safeguard Ukraine’s security in both the near and long term. They underscored that the strengthened security guarantee architecture, combined with commitments on non-aggression, energy stability, and reconstruction, meaningfully addresses their core strategic requirements.Secretary Rubio and his team reiterated the United States’ firm commitment to ensuring that Ukraine’s sovereignty, security, and future prosperity remain central to the ongoing diplomatic process. They emphasized that this work is driven by President Trump’s goal of ending a war that has taken the lives of millions of people and preventing further loss of life through a durable and enforceable peace. Both sides welcomed the steady progress made and agreed to continue consultations as the agreements move toward final refinement.The meeting concluded with a shared understanding that today marked a significant step forward, and that continued close coordination will be essential as the Parties work toward a durable, comprehensive peace.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/readout-of-peace-talks-in-geneva/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S.260, H.R. 998 and H.R. 2316 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bills-s-260-h-r-998-and-h-r-2316-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.260, H.R. 998 and H.R. 2316 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.260, H.R. 998 and H.R. 2316 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.260, H.R. 998 and H.R. 2316 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 25, 2025

On Tuesday, November 25, 2025, the President signed into law:

S.260, the “Bottles and Breastfeeding Equipment Screening Enhancement Act,” which amends the Bottles and Breastfeeding Equipment Screening Act to require hygienic handling of breast milk and baby formula by security screening personnel of the Transportation Security Administration and personnel of private security companies providing security screening, and for other purposes;

H.R. 998, the “Internal Revenue Service Math and Taxpayer Help Act,” which requires the Internal Revenue Service to provide specific information on a notice as a result of a mathematical or clerical error on a tax return, send a notice related to an abatement of taxes assessed due to error, and implement a pilot program for sending such notices; and

H.R. 2316, the “Wetlands Conservation and Access Improvement Act of 2025,” which extends through FY 2033, authority to spend interest from the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration fund to support certain projects.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bills-s-260-h-r-998-and-h-r-2316-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bills-s-2392-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 25, 2025

On Tuesday, November 25, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 2392, the “Veterans’ Compensation Cost-of-Living Adjustment Act of 2025,” which increases, effective as of December 1, 2025, the rates of compensation for veterans with service-connected disabilities and the rates of dependency and indemnity compensation for the survivors of certain disabled veterans, and for other purposes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bills-s-2392-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base Andrews</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/flotus_joins_military_spouses_american_red_cross/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base AndrewsThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base AndrewsThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base AndrewsThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 1, 2025

First Lady Melania Trump visited Joint Base Andrews to celebrate the beginning of the Christmas season and honor the strength and service of America’s military families. Mrs. Trump delivered brief remarks in a base hangar before joining military spouses to assemble holiday care packages for deployed Service members.

“Every package built here today is built with American values. Each represents liberty, love, community, and honor. Each is delivered with heart and love. The foundation of our great nation,” exclaimed America’s First Lady Melania Trump.

The event highlighted the resilience, sacrifice, and unwavering commitment of military families—particularly the spouses who shoulder the unique responsibilities of military life. Mrs. Trump expressed deep gratitude for their service to the Nation and emphasized the importance of supporting those who spend the holidays separated from loved ones.

The care-package project was made possible through a collaboration with the American Red Cross, which provides support to Service members and their families throughout the year.

The First Lady was joined by several Cabinet spouses, including: Mrs. Jennifer Hegseth, Mrs. Kathryn Burgum, Mrs. Cheryl Hines, Mrs. Liz Wright, Mrs. Lisa Collins, and Mrs. Marlo Greer.

The Office of the First Lady shared its appreciation with the leadership and personnel of Joint Base Andrews for facilitating this special event and for their year-round contributions to the mission success of countless trips and engagements by the President and the First Lady.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/flotus_joins_military_spouses_american_red_cross/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOME IS WHERE THE HEART IS – First Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas Theme</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/home-is-where-the-heart-isfirst-lady-melania-trumps-2025-white-house-christmas-theme/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyHOME IS WHERE THE HEART ISFirst Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas ThemeThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyHOME IS WHERE THE HEART ISFirst Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas ThemeThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyHOME IS WHERE THE HEART ISFirst Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas ThemeThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 1, 2025

First Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas theme,Home Is Where The Heart Is, illuminates the heartfelt character of America within the People’s House.

The First Lady’s creative inspiration is drawn from the joys, challenges, and frequent motion derived from motherhood and business. “The constant movement has taught me that home is not merely a physical space; rather, it is the warmth and comfort I carry within, regardless of my surroundings,” America’s First Lady reflects. “This Christmas, let’s celebrate the love we hold within ourselves, and share it with the world around us.  After all, wherever we are, we can create a home filled with grace, radiance, and endless possibilities.”

Fostering the Future Red RoomFirst Lady Melania Trump appointed renowned designer, Hervé Pierre, to oversee the implementation of her creative vision. Blue butterflies illuminate the “Fostering the Future Red Room,” a transformational experience dedicated to the foster-care community, a cause the First Lady has championed since 2021. The striking color combination coupled with the butterflies symbolic meaning of transformation and renewal capture the essence of Christmas.

Mr. Pierre also created a limited-edition tour booklet—an artful keepsake that captures the magic of this year’s White House’s holiday theme for guests to treasure.

Time-Honored TraditionHonoring tradition, 75 of Mrs. Trump’s signature wreaths with classic red bows adorn the White House windows, and more than 50 Christmas trees, 700 feet of garland, 25,000 feet of ribbon, and 10,000 butterflies fill the halls with holiday warmth.

Gold Star FamiliesIn the Blue Room, the official White House Christmas Tree, an 18-foot concolor fir from Sidney, Michigan, commemorates Gold Star Families with gold stars and ornaments representing the official bird and flower of every U.S. state and territory—a tribute to the resilience, bravery, and sacrifice of our military personnel and their families.

250th AnniversaryPatriotic exhibits featuring America’s signature red, white, and blue accentuate the upcoming 250th anniversary of the Nation in the East Room, while two presidential portraits created from over 6,000 puzzle pieces are presented in the Green Room, offering families the chance to be challenged, have fun, and use their imagination together.

120 Pounds of GingerbreadThe 2025 Gingerbread House is prominently displayed in the State Dining Room, highlighting the South Portico and offering a glimpse of the Yellow Oval Room—an artistic culinary triumph, boasting more than 120 pounds of gingerbread. The Grand Foyer features a section of the historic White House Crèche, which is currently undergoing meticulous restoration by the White House Curators. As Americans explore the historic rooms of the White House this holiday season, the 2025 Christmas decorations serve as a reminder that the strength of our Nation is found in its people—in our shared values, valued traditions, and the steadfast belief that home is where the heart is.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/home-is-where-the-heart-isfirst-lady-melania-trumps-2025-white-house-christmas-theme/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-695-and-h-r-2483-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 1, 2025

On Monday, December 1, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 695, the “Medal of Honor Act,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to increase the rate of the special monthly pension payable to living Medal of Honor recipients; and

H.R. 2483, the “SUPPORT for Patients and Communications Reauthorization Act of 2025,” which reauthorizes programs related to substance use disorder prevention, treatment, and recovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-695-and-h-r-2483-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-133-and-h-r-1512-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 2, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 2, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 2, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 2, 2025

On Tuesday, December 2, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.J. Res 133, which requests the Secretary of the Interior to authorize unique and one-time arrangements for displays on the National Mall and the Washington Monument during the period beginning on December 31, 2025, and ending on January 5, 2026; and

H.R. 1512, the “Taiwan Assurance Implementation Act,” which permanently extends existing requirements for the Department of State to review and report on its guidance to Executive Branch agencies and offices on relations with Taiwan.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-133-and-h-r-1512-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification Initiative</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/u-s-first-lady-melania-trump-welcomes-progress-in-russia-ukraine-childrens-reunification-initiative/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyU.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification InitiativeThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First LadyU.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification InitiativeThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First LadyU.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification InitiativeThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Seven additional children—six boys and one girl—have been reunited with their families in Ukraine. The following is a statement from the First Lady of the United States, Melania Trump, regarding the humanitarian efforts of all parties participating in this initiative.

“My dedication to guaranteeing the safe return of children to their families in this region is unwavering.

“I commend the leadership and persistent diplomacy of Russia and Ukraine in the pursuit of the reunification of children and families. Their bridge-building has created a tangible collaborative environment—an anchor for optimism. This cooperation will continue to drive the process forward through the next phase.

“In close partnership, my representative and I have provided humanitarian support from the United States to enhance the reunification initiative’s outcome. My hope is that, ultimately, our collective efforts will lead to broader regional stability.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/u-s-first-lady-melania-trump-welcomes-progress-in-russia-ukraine-childrens-reunification-initiative/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
