<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:17:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Christmas</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-christmas/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on ChristmasThe White HouseDecember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on ChristmasThe White HouseDecember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on ChristmasThe White HouseDecember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 25, 2025

The First Lady and I send our warmest wishes to all Americans as we share in the joy of Christmas Day and celebrate the birth of our Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ.

The story of the Christmas miracle begins more than 2,000 years ago in Bethlehem, when angels appeared to humble shepherds to share the good news of a child born to bring hope to the world, declaring, “Glory to God in the highest.”  Guided by a magnificent star, the shepherds traveled a great distance to gather around a crowded manger where, in the dark of night alongside Mary and Joseph, they knelt before the Light of the World, the source of eternal salvation, and the living Son of God.

The birth of Jesus revealed the perfect expression of God’s boundless love and His desire to be close to His people.  More than two centuries later, we continue to rejoice in the gift of God’s only begotten Son as the graces of Christ’s life, death, and resurrection continue to pour out upon all who believe.

This Christmas, we also give thanks for the many blessings that God has bestowed upon our great Nation.  For nearly 250 years, the principles of faith, family, and freedom have remained at the center of our way of life.  As President, I will never waver in defending the fundamental values that make America the greatest country in the history of the world—and we will always remain one Nation under God.

Today, especially, we also remember the brave men and women of our Armed Forces who are unable to be with their families.  While their solemn mission keeps them far from home this Christmas, their service and sacrifice protect our freedom and allow Americans all across our country to celebrate in safety and peace.  We are grateful for their devotion, and we keep them and their loved ones close in our hearts.

During the Christmas season, we pray for an outpouring of God’s abiding love, divine mercy, and everlasting peace upon our country and the entire world.  To every American, and to those celebrating around the globe, we wish you a very Merry Christmas!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-christmas/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-216-s-284-s-2878-h-r-187-h-r-410-h-r-1491-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.216, S.284, S.2878, H.R. 187, H.R. 410, H.R. 1491 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 26, 2025

On Friday, December 26, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 216, the “Save Our Seas 2.0 Amendments Act,” which authorizes appropriations for the Marine Debris Program through Fiscal Year (FY) 2029 and the Marine Debris Foundation for FY 2025; and modifies the administrative requirements of the Program and Foundation;

S. 284, the “Congressional Award Program Reauthorization Act,” which retroactively reauthorizes the Congressional Award Board, which administers the Congressional Awards Program to recognize the achievements of young people, effective as if enacted on October 1, 2023, through October 1, 2028;

S. 2878, the “Great Lakes Fishery Research Reauthorization Act,” which reauthorizes funding to monitor, assess, and research fisheries in the Great Lakes Basin through Fiscal Year 2030;

H.R. 187, the “Modernizing Access to our Public Waters Act of 2025” or the “MAPWaters Act of 2025,” which directs the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior to standardize and publish date relating to public outdoor recreational access of Federal waterways and Federal fishing restrictions;

H.R. 410, the “Alaska Native Vietnam Era Veterans Land Allotment Extension Act of 2025”, which extends the Alaska Native Vietnam Era Veterans Land Allotment Program through December 29, 2030; and

H.R. 1491, the “Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act,” which requires the Department of the Treasury to treat the postponement of the tax return deadline to a federally-declared disaster or certain other events as an extension of such deadline for purposes of calculating the limit on a tax refund.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-216-s-284-s-2878-h-r-187-h-r-410-h-r-1491-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Anniversary of the Battle of Trenton</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-trenton/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Anniversary of the Battle of TrentonThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Anniversary of the Battle of TrentonThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Anniversary of the Battle of TrentonThe White HouseDecember 26, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 26, 2025

On December 26, 1776, the full might of General George Washington’s Continental Army was revealed along the frozen riverbanks of Pennsylvania when the Patriots triumphed at the Battle of Trenton—one of the most legendary battles in American history, which rescued the Revolution and rekindled the cause of independence in the heart of every American.

Just months after the signing of the Declaration of Independence, the Patriots’ rally for freedomhad nearly collapsed.  Driven from New York, beaten across New Jersey, and forced into Pennsylvania, the Continental Army was exhausted, undersupplied, and on the verge of breaking down.  General Washington determined that only a bold and decisive victory could reverse the tides of misfortune.  Across the Delaware River, he saw in the Hessian troops in Trenton, New Jersey—German soldiers fighting for the British—a desperately-needed opportunity to seize back momentum and change the course of the war and the course of history.

On Christmas night, as a fierce winter storm swept across the region, Washington ordered 2,400 weary soldiers into boats and began his epic crossing of the Delaware River—a moment now immortalized in the American imagination.  Despite extraordinary dangers, his men pushed artillery, horses, and provisions through ice-choked waters for 11 hours, then marched 9 gruelingmiles—many without boots on their feet—toward Trenton through unrelenting cold, leaving a trail of blood in the snowy hills.

At dawn, General Washington’s troops gathered in frigid darkness to prepare for a surprise strike against the Hessian auxiliaries hired by the British.  They advanced on the town from two directions.  American cannons opened fire, Patriot infantry pressed forward, and the Hessian defenders— caught off guard—struggled to mount an organized response.  After 2 hours of close fighting, the 900 Hessian mercenaries surrendered, and the Continental Army emerged triumphant.

The crossing of the Delaware and the victory at Trenton—steered by the fearless leadership of General Washington—restored confidence in the American cause and changed the Revolution. The Patriots’ victory proved that courage and determination could overcome fear and despair.  Despite being exhausted, unpaid, under-equipped, and teetering on the edge of defeat, they valiantly showed the world that they were not only capable of winning but also that they would never waver in their righteous crusade for independence and that the American spirit would always triumph over forces of anguish, adversity, and affliction.

In the harsh winter of 1776, our ancestors demonstrated that, when the future of our Nation is threatened, Americans endure and prevail.  Their endurance in the face of cold, hunger, and uncertainty laid the foundation for the country we now uphold.  Today, we salute the valiant men whose victory at Trenton secured our proud inheritance of liberty.  As we approach 250 glorious years of American independence and continue the work of saving our country, we look to their unwavering grit, valor, and patriotism—and in their honor, we vow to never stop fighting for the sacred causes that sustain our Republic, our way of life, and our birthright of freedom.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-trenton/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-pledge-of-allegiance-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance DayThe White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance DayThe White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Pledge of Allegiance DayThe White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 28, 2025

Today, our Nation proudly celebrates the Pledge of Allegiance—a solemn and glorious oath that unites every citizen under one God and our beloved banner of red, white, and blue.  This National Pledge of Allegiance Day, I encourage every American to rededicate themselves to our Flag, our heritage, and the eternal principles that have guided our Republic for nearly 250 years.

The Pledge of Allegiance has been a foundation of American life since it was first written in 1892.  Its words gave our growing Nation a shared expression of duty—reminding students, civic leaders, and new Americans that they were active participants in the American story.  By reciting it aloud, citizens declare their loyalty to our Flag and to the values it embodies:  freedom, the rule of law, the dignity of life, and the duty to serve our country and our communities.

Through the trials of war and economic upheaval, the Pledge has been a steady reminder of the commitments every citizen makes.  Its words have inspired soldiers defending freedom abroad, motivated Americans to safeguard our constitutional way of life here at home, and strengthened the bonds of patriotism that unite communities all across our land.  Every generation recites the Pledge grounded in the recognition that to honor the Flag is to honor the Nation for which it stands.

Today, my Administration is strongly defending the value of American citizenship and respect for the American Flag.  Last summer, I signed an Executive Order to preserve the dignity of our Stars and Stripes, including by vigorously enforcing accountability for acts of Flag desecration tied to violence and lawlessness—because those who hate our Flag resent the history, heritage, and heroes it represents even more.  We are also authorizing the revocation of visas, residency, and naturalization for foreign nationals who desecrate the banner under which millions of American heroes have fought and died.  We will never again allow those who hate our country to openly disrespect our Flag—and we will never waver in defending the sacred heritage that unites the American people beneath its banner.

On this National Pledge of Allegiance Day, we renew our devotion to the ideals that define the United States and to the Flag that symbolizes our shared destiny:  one Nation under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-pledge-of-allegiance-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-1043-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 29, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 29, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 1043 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 29, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 29, 2025

On Monday, December 29, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 1043, the “La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act,” which directs the Department of the Interior to convey approximately 3,400 acres of federally-managed land in La Paz County, Arizona, to the county at fair market value.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-1043-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 504 Vetoed</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-504-vetoed/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 504 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 504 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 504 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 30, 2025

I am returning herewith without my approval H.R. 504, the Miccosukee Reserved Area Amendments Act.

The subject of this bill is a specific area in the Everglades National Park known as the “Osceola Camp.”  In 1998, the Congress passed the Miccosukee Reserved Area Act, which authorized the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida (Tribe) to permanently occupy a certain area within Everglades National Park.  The reserved area did not include the Osceola Camp.  Nonetheless, the Tribe has a residential community in that area, including infrastructure for wastewater treatment and water supply, and is experiencing periodic flooding.  H.R. 504 would require the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Tribe, to take appropriate actions to safeguard structures within the Osceola Camp from flooding events.

The Osceola Camp was constructed in 1935, without authorization, in a low area that was raised with fill material.  It served as a family residence and gift shop initially, and then later a site for air-boat rides.  None of the current structures in the Osceola Camp are over 50 years old, nor do they meet the other criteria to be considered for listing in the National Register of Historic Places.

The previous administration developed a plan to protect and replace unauthorized infrastructure at the Osceola Camp, which could cost up to $14 million.  But despite seeking funding and special treatment from the Federal Government, the Miccosukee Tribe has actively sought to obstruct reasonable immigration policies that the American people decisively voted for when I was elected.

My Administration is committed to preventing American taxpayers from funding projects for special interests, especially those that are unaligned with my Administration’s policy of removing violent criminal illegal aliens from the country.  Ending the massive cost of taxpayer handouts and restoring fiscal sanity is vital to economic growth and the fiscal health of the Nation.  This principle carries especially heavy weight here; it is not the Federal Government’s responsibility to pay to fix problems in an area that the Tribe has never been authorized to occupy.

For these reasons, I cannot support the Miccosukee Reserved Area Amendments Act.  Therefore, it is my duty to return H.R. 504 to the House of Representatives without my approval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-504-vetoed/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 131 Vetoed</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-131-vetoed/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 131 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 131 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 131 VetoedThe White HouseDecember 30, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 30, 2025

I am returning herewith without my approval H.R. 131, the Finish the Arkansas Valley Conduit Act.

The Arkansas Valley Conduit (AVC) is a water pipeline currently being built to provide municipal and industrial water to communities in southeastern Colorado.  It was originally authorized as part of the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project in a bill signed by President Kennedy in 1962.  For decades it was unbuilt, largely because the AVC was economically unviable.  Under the original plan, the costs of the project were to be initially funded by the Federal Government, but repaid by local users, with interest, over a 50-year period following completion of construction.  But participants were unable to comply with that repayment obligation.

In 2009, President Obama signed the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009, which not only reduced the repayment obligation from 100 percent to 35 percent but also provided that miscellaneous revenues from the Fryingpan-Arkansas Project at large would count towards the AVC cost share.  Even then, however, construction did not begin until 14 years later, after the State of Colorado authorized $100 million in loans and grants for the project.

The current bill would now have the Federal Government extend the repayment period (on the already-reduced repayment requirement) for an additional 25 years, creating a 75-year repayment period.  The bill would also cut the interest rate in half.

More than $249 million has already been spent on the AVC, and total costs are estimated to be $1.3 billion.  H.R. 131 would continue the failed policies of the past by forcing Federal taxpayers to bear even more of the massive costs of a local water project — a local water project that, as initially conceived, was supposed to be paid for by the localities using it.

Enough is enough.  My Administration is committed to preventing American taxpayers from funding expensive and unreliable policies.  Ending the massive cost of taxpayer handouts and restoring fiscal sanity is vital to economic growth and the fiscal health of the Nation.

For these reasons, I cannot support the Finish the Arkansas Valley Conduit Act.  Therefore, it is my duty to return H.R. 131 to the House of Representatives without my approval.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-h-r-131-vetoed/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of General George C. Marshall, Jr.</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-general-george-c-marshall-jr/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of General George C. Marshall, Jr.The White HouseDecember 31, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of General George C. Marshall, Jr.The White HouseDecember 31, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of General George C. Marshall, Jr.The White HouseDecember 31, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 31, 2025

Today, we celebrate the birthday of General George C. Marshall, Jr., an American titan whose bold leadership, strategic brilliance, and unceasing devotion to freedom helped save our Nation—and the entire world—from the forces of evil, tyranny, and ruin during the Second World War.

General Marshall was born in Uniontown, Pennsylvania, where from a young age his father instilled in him the noble values of honesty, integrity, and duty—virtues he embodied throughout his life.  General Marshall felt a calling to serve his Nation, graduating from the Virginia Military Institute in 1901 and commissioning into the United States Army as a Second Lieutenant.

He rose to prominence in the military during World War II, where he served as chief of staff of the United States Army and played an indispensable role in securing victory for the Allies.  Through his disciplined leadership and tactical brilliance, he recruited, trained, and equipped the largest ground and air force in our Nation’s history, growing America’s ranks from 200,000 to more than 8 million men and paving the way for the eventual defeat of the Axis powers.

After the war, he cemented his legacy as a world-renowned diplomat, serving as Secretary of State and then Secretary of Defense under President Harry Truman, where he was the chief architect of the “Marshall Plan,” a monumental initiative for postwar European recovery on America’s terms.  This heroic vision solidified America’s global leadership and saved Europe from economic collapse and communist takeover.  As a result of his sweeping actions to recover the European economy, General Marshall was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1953.

Today, my Administration is proudly carrying forth General Marshall’s incredible legacy, including by restoring a foreign policy of peace through strength and rebuilding our Nation’s military.  Already, we have secured a series of major peace agreements between countries marred by decades of conflict, and we have restored our military as the biggest, strongest, most feared, and most lethal fighting force in the world.  As President, I will continue to put American lives, interests, and values first—and I will never stop working to achieve a future free from war.

On what would have been General Marshall’s 145th birthday, we celebrate his heroism, bravery, and acumen.  We proudly remember him as one of the greatest military and diplomatic minds the world has ever seen.  Above all, we recommit to his vision of global peace and prosperity, and we pledge to continue to lead the world with a righteous moral clarity and an unwavering resolve.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-general-george-c-marshall-jr/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation Proclamation</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-emancipation-proclamation/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation ProclamationThe White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation ProclamationThe White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Emancipation ProclamationThe White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 1, 2026

On January 1, 1863, President Abraham Lincoln signed the legendary Emancipation Proclamation—one of the most significant documents in human history and a grand edict that paved the way to the liberation of millions of slaves and the full glory of the American promise.

As the bloody Civil War raged into its second year and the Nation fought to preserve the Union, President Lincoln made a “fit and necessary” military decree that would redefine the entire conflict.  With the Emancipation Proclamation declaring that those held in slavery in the

rebellious states “shall be then, thenceforward, and forever free,” the purpose of the war shifted—and every Union advance now carried with it the blazing torch of liberty, justice, and dignity for all.

The Emancipation Proclamation set the stage for the ultimate abolition of slavery, culminating in the ratification of the Thirteenth Amendment nearly 2 years later.  It endures to this day as a monumental testament to the divine truth that equality is a sacred birthright granted not by government but by the hand of Almighty God.  It signaled the dawn of a new day in our Nation’s journey toward liberty and the inalienable rights of every citizen.  Its signing remains a morally defining moment in our national story and an enduring legacy of President Lincoln’s conviction that our country—which launched a revolution in the pursuit of freedom and human dignity—is “the last best hope of Earth.”

Today, in President Lincoln’s honor, we recommit to the eternal truth that the United States of America is blessed by God; is bound together by justice; and was, is, and will forever be a great Nation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-emancipation-proclamation/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of Princeton</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-princeton/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of PrincetonThe White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of PrincetonThe White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of PrincetonThe White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 3, 2026

On January 3, 1777, General George Washington and his battle-hardened Continental Army secured a decisive victory over the formidable British garrison at the Battle of Princeton—an epic clash that reignited the Revolution and steered the Patriots back on the path to independence.

During the “Ten Crucial Days” following General Washington’s legendary crossing of the Delaware River, Continental soldiers once again answered the call of liberty in extraordinary fashion.  After fending off a hard-pressed British attack at the Second Battle of Trenton, under the cover of darkness, General Washington led thousands of American soldiers in a careful evasion of the British Army, leaving campfires burning and sentries posted to disguise their departure.  In the light of daybreak, the enemy found an empty camp at Trenton—outwitted once again by the cunning and courage of General Washington—while the Continental Army were miles away confronting the British garrison at Princeton.

As battle was joined, the British initially gained the upper hand.  Charging with fixed bayonets, they overran an American position, and viciously stabbed Brigadier General Hugh Mercer, one of Washington’s closest aides, seven times, fatally wounding him.  As fresh Continentals and militia arrived, though, General Washington himself courageously rode to the front lines, rallying his troops to stand firm and press forward, before going on to break the British line and send the enemy reeling back into town and beyond.  Defeated, the British hoisted a white flag of surrender into the cold morning air—signaling that the Continental Army had reigned victorious once again.

That day, General Washington’s men won a crucial victory, revived our national spirit, and breathed new life into the cause of independence throughout the Colonies.  Nearly two and a half centuries later, the patriots’ renewed spirit of determination remains an enduring symbol of American strength, resilience, and grit.  Today, we pledge to continue the work of saving our country with the courage that burned in the hearts of the warriors at Princeton 249 years ago.  We honor their valiant legacy.  We vow to protect our inheritance of liberty against all enemies and to forge a future worthy of their sacrifice.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-princeton/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
