<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:05:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-national-sanctity-of-human-life-day-2026/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

On July 4, 1776, our Declaration of Independence righteously affirmed that every human being is endowed by Almighty God with the unalienable right to life.  In the 250 years since, our commitment to this truth has been the source of our strength and the foundation of our greatness — and it has helped America remain the single greatest force for justice and human flourishing in the history of the world.  This National Sanctity of Human Life Day, we renew our steadfast commitment to fostering a culture that respects, upholds, and cherishes the inherent dignity and infinite worth of every precious human soul.

Today marks the 53rd anniversary ofRoe v. Wade— a moral and constitutional atrocity that silenced the American people and stripped the States of their right to protect the unborn.  Thankfully, in June 2022, the United States Supreme Court corrected this disastrous decision, and decades of left-wing judicial overreach, by returning abortion policy to the American people in the States.  During my first term, I was proud to have appointed three of the Associate Justices who delivered this triumphant victory for life, liberty, and American democracy.

From the moment I returned to office as the 47th President of the United States, I have taken decisive action to protect the unborn and restore a culture that unapologetically defends the sanctity of life.  I was proud to enforce the Hyde Amendment and reinstate the Mexico City Policy — ending taxpayer-funded abortion at home and abroad.  I also pardoned 23 pro-life activists who were unfairly targeted and prosecuted by a weaponized Department of Justice (DOJ) for practicing their faith and living their conscience.  At my direction, the DOJ is now investigating the weaponization of Government against Christians and Americans of faith.

Last summer, I also proudly signed into law the One Big Beautiful Bill — a monumental win for life and the American family that expands the child tax credit, increases access to childcare, makes the paid leave tax credit permanent, protects Medicaid from funding large abortion providers, and establishes Trump accounts for newborn babies for the future of our Nation.  My Administration is also committed to supporting policies that advocate for adoption, promote foster care, and protect pregnant women and mothers.  At every level of the Federal Government, my Administration is boldly advancing policies that protect the most vulnerable among us and promote the growth and success of America’s families.

Today, we uphold the eternal truth that every human being is created in the holy image and likeness of God, blessed with infinite worth and boundless potential.  We celebrate the heroic leaders, parents, students, and everyday citizens — including those gathering for the March for Life in Washington, D.C., this weekend — who have courageously advocated for the most vulnerable and stood up for those who cannot stand up for themselves.  As President, I pledge to always be a voice for the voiceless and to never tire in fighting to protect the intrinsic dignity of every child, born and unborn.

Today, I call on the American people to join me in honoring the dignity of every human life, including those not yet born, to continue to care for women in unexpected pregnancies, and to support adoption and foster care in a more meaningful way so every child can have a loving home.  Finally, I ask every citizen of this great Nation to listen to the sound of silence caused by a generation lost to us and then to raise their voices for all affected by abortion, both seen and unseen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-national-sanctity-of-human-life-day-2026/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock Exchange</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-to-ring-opening-bell-of-the-new-york-stock-exchange/</link>
      <description>Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock ExchangeThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock ExchangeThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock ExchangeThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Office of the first lady

The White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump will ring the opening bell of the New York Stock Exchange on Wednesday, January 28, 2026, following an impactful first year of leadership as First Lady of the United States during the second term of the Trump Administration.

Over the past year, Mrs. Trump has taken action to advance a results-driven agenda that is centered on the well-being of children in the United States and around the world. Some of her achievements include:

More information for media on the New York Stock Exchange opening bell is availablehere.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-to-ring-opening-bell-of-the-new-york-stock-exchange/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-h-r-4323-and-h-r-6938-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

On Friday, January 23, 2026, the President signed into law:

H.R. 4323, the “Trafficking Survivors Relief Act,” which establishes a process to allow human trafficking victims to file motions to vacate their convictions and expunge their arrest records for certain criminal offenses committed as a direct result of their being trafficked; and H.R. 6938, the “Commerce, Justice, Science; Energy and Water Development; and Interior and Environment Appropriations Act, 2026,” which makes consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-h-r-4323-and-h-r-6938-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-international-holocaust-remembrance-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance DayThe White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance DayThe White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance DayThe White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

This International Holocaust Remembrance Day, we remember one of the darkest periods in human history and one of the gravest atrocities the world has ever witnessed.  Today, we pay respect to the blessed memories of the millions of Jewish people, who were murdered at the hands of the Nazi Regime and its collaborators during the Holocaust— as well as the Slavs and the Roma, people with disabilities, religious leaders, persons targeted based on their sexual orientation, and political prisoners who were also targeted for systematic slaughter.  We renew our resolve that freedom, justice, and the dignity of the human person will always conquer the forces of evil, tyranny, and oppression.

On January 27, 1945, 81 years ago today, Allied forces liberated Auschwitz-Birkenau, the Nazi Regime’s largest concentration and death camp in World War II, where over one million people were marched to their senseless deaths.  Within the camp’s barbed-wire electric fence, those imprisoned there were stripped of their clothing, personal possessions, and God-given dignity.  Countless were immediately murdered, and others were subjected to forced labor, starvation, disease, torture, and medical experiments.  The barbaric conditions knew no bounds.

The systematic murder of Jewish people across Nazi-occupied Europe remains an indelible blight on mankind.  In remembrance of all who perished during the Holocaust and in honor of all those who survived and rebuilt their lives from the ashes, we renew our pledge that such evil will never again attain a stronghold in the West.  After I took office as the 47th President of the United States, I proudly made it this administration’s priority directing the Federal Government to use all appropriate legal tools to combat the scourge of anti-Semitism.  My Administration will remain a steadfast and unequivocal champion for Jewish Americans and the God-given right of every American to practice their faith freely, openly, and without fear.

On this solemn day, we remember every man, woman, and child senselessly killed by the evil, depravity, and hate of the Nazi Regime—and we commend the survivors who dedicated their lives to sharing their stories while carrying the unimaginable burden of the seen and unseen scars.  This International Holocaust Remembrance Day, and every day, we honor their enduring resilience, faith, and strength—and we recommit to the sacred truth that every human being is made in the holy image of God.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-international-holocaust-remembrance-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Space Shuttle Challenger Disaster</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-space-shuttle-challenger-disaster/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Space Shuttle Challenger DisasterThe White HouseJanuary 28, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Space Shuttle Challenger DisasterThe White HouseJanuary 28, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Space Shuttle Challenger DisasterThe White HouseJanuary 28, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 28, 2026

On this day 40 years ago, America tragically lost 7 brilliant, visionary, and courageous titans of space exploration aboard the Space Shuttle Challenger.  On this solemn anniversary, we acknowledge that their legacies will remain forever etched upon our Nation’s memory—and we recommit to advancing mankind’s journey beyond the stars with unwavering strength and an unyielding commitment to excellence.

On the morning of January 28, 1986, millions of Americans sat in anticipation as a historic launch unfolded on live television.  Aboard the spacecraft were seven remarkable Americans—scientists, engineers, aviators, and a high school teacher chosen to help inspire the next generation of students.  Just 73 seconds after liftoff, that anticipation was shattered when mechanical failures caused the shuttle to disintegrate into the cold morning air, transforming wonder and hope into devastation and disaster in a mere instant.  Yet, from the smoke-filled sky rose a lasting resolve to honor these fallen American heroes by continuing their work and advancing the causes they cherished with greater care and unshakable purpose.

Every day, my Administration is propelling their mission forward by unleashing the full force of American innovation and technology into the next era of space exploration.  Last month, I signed an Executive Order on Ensuring American Space Superiority, which calls for a return to the Moon by 2028, lays the groundwork for a permanent American lunar presence, and will help make the United States the first nation to land an astronaut on Mars.  Under my leadership, we are empowering innovation in the commercial space industry to increase capabilities and encourage a vibrant American space economy—because American leadership in space is crucial to America’s strength, security, and future.

As we celebrate 250 years of American independence, this work is just the beginning of our next great chapter as we chart the course for a glorious American future in space.

On the day of this tragedy four decades ago, the great President Ronald Reagan declared:  “The Challenger crew was pulling us into the future, and we will continue to follow them.”  Today, under my leadership, we will continue to abide by this promise—leading boldly on Earth and beyond—as we carry their lasting legacy into a new Golden Age of American exploration and discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-space-shuttle-challenger-disaster/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of President William McKinley</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-president-william-mckinley/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of President William McKinleyThe White HouseJanuary 29, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of President William McKinleyThe White HouseJanuary 29, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of President William McKinleyThe White HouseJanuary 29, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 29, 2026

Today, we celebrate the birthday of the legendary President William McKinley—a true American trailblazer and titan of American greatness, who protected our people; expanded our blessings; and secured unprecedented growth, prosperity, and sovereignty for our beloved Nation.

Born and raised in Niles, Ohio, McKinley learned as a child the virtues of faith, duty, and respect, which would go on to define his storied career.  Following his service in the Union Army during the Civil War, he was elected to represent the people of Ohio in the United States House of Representatives, where he famously authored and passed the McKinley Tariff of 1890—a bold legislative effort to protect American workers against foreign exploitation.  He later rose to serve as governor of Ohio, emerging on the national stage as a leading voice for the forgotten men and women of America—our great workers, laborers, and tradesmen.

In 1896, McKinley ran for President and won decisively, becoming the 25th President of the United States.  As Commander in Chief, President McKinley was a fierce advocate for American greatness and heroically led our country to victory in the Spanish-American War—advancing the blessings of freedom beyond our shores.  He was also an unwavering champion for the American worker, and his historic use of tariffs fueled an economic boom that made our country stronger, wealthier, and more prosperous than ever before.

Tragically, President McKinley’s devotion to America First principles ultimately cost him his life when, in 1901, he was viciously assassinated by a deranged left-wing anarchist.  To this day, he lives on in our hearts as a martyr of American freedom.

In honor of President McKinley’s historic legacy, on my first day returning to office, I proudly restored the rightful name of Mount McKinley to America’s highest peak.  Guided by his vision, my Administration is also reestablishing a trade policy that promotes American investment and productivity, enhances our Nation’s industrial and technological advantages, defends our economic and national security, and—above all—puts American workers, manufacturers, and industries first.

On what would have been President McKinley’s 183rd birthday—and as we celebrate 250 years of American freedom and independence—we honor his memory, we remember his courage, and we renew our resolve to protect our workers, to reach further, aim higher, and achieve the full promise and glory of the American Dream.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-president-william-mckinley/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of Our Victory in the Mexican-American War</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-mexican-american-war/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of Our Victory in the Mexican-American WarThe White HouseFebruary 2, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of Our Victory in the Mexican-American WarThe White HouseFebruary 2, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of Our Victory in the Mexican-American WarThe White HouseFebruary 2, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 2, 2026

Today marks the 178th anniversary of our Nation’s triumph in the Mexican-American War—a legendary victory that secured the American Southwest, reasserted American sovereignty, and expanded the promise of American independence across our majestic continent.

Guided by the steadfast belief that our Nation was destined by divine providence to expand to the golden shores of the Pacific Ocean, following the bloody War of 1812, the United States was confidently advancing westward and boldly emerging as a continental superpower unlike anything the modern world had ever seen.  The people of Texas declared independence from Mexico in 1836, and by the spring of 1846, they voted to join the United States—forcing a reckoning over unsettled border disputes.  That April, Mexican forces launched an ambush along the Rio Grande, killing 11 and wounding 6 American troops.

With the promise of Manifest Destiny beating in every American heart, President James K. Polk took swift action to defend our Nation’s security, our dignity, and our sovereign borders.  In May of 1846, the United States declared war on Mexico, with two American titans—Generals Zachary Taylor and Winfield Scott—leading the charge.  Despite being vastly outnumbered in battle, American forces consistently reigned victorious through their superior military strategy, modern military capabilities, and steadfast devotion to protecting the national interest.  After a series of victories in the Mexican territories of California and New Mexico, in a triumphant victory for American sovereignty, the United States heroically captured the capital of Mexico City in September of 1847—paving the way to the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo on February 2, 1848, formally ceding 525,000 square miles of new land to the United States, representing 55% of pre-war territory.

Since taking office as the 47th President of the United States, guided by our victory on the fields of Mexico 178 years ago, I have spared no effort in defending our southern border against invasion, upholding the rule of law, and protecting our homeland from forces of evil, violence, and destruction.  My Administration is halting the flow of deadly drugs entering our country through Mexico, ending the invasion of illegal aliens along our southern border, and dismantling narco-terrorist networks all across the Western hemisphere.  I have secured historic trade deals with El Salvador, Argentina, Ecuador, and Guatemala, allowing greater and more streamlined market access.  We stopped a hostile foreign power from controlling the Panama Canal.  We are reestablishing American maritime dominance.  And we are aggressively pursuing an America First policy of peace through strength and will continue to reassert the Trump Corollary to the Monroe Doctrine to ensure the Hemisphere remains safe, prosperous, and free.  We will never waver in putting our people, our interests, and our country first.

On this anniversary of one of our Nation’s earliest displays of military might—and particularly as we celebrate 250 glorious years of American independence—we honor the memory of the brave men who gave their lives in service to our Nation.  One hundred and seventy-eight years later, their legacy lives on in our enduring strength, our commitment to sovereignty, and the unmatched power of the American spirit.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-mexican-american-war/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 7148 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bill-h-r-7148-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 7148 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 7148 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 7148 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 3, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 3, 2026

On Tuesday, February 3, 2026, the President signed into law:

H.R. 7148, the “Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2026,” which further makes consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bill-h-r-7148-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Women and Girls in Sports Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-national-women-and-girls-in-sports-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Women and Girls in Sports DayThe White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Women and Girls in Sports DayThe White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Women and Girls in Sports DayThe White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

From youth leagues and high school varsity to the Olympic Games and the heights of professional sports, for decades, women and girls have exemplified the very best of American athletics.  This National Women and Girls in Sports Day, we celebrate every female athlete for their devotion to excellence and for their incredible contributions to America’s character, culture, and unwavering competitive spirit.

Emboldened by the promise of the American Dream, through hard work, dedication, and resilience, every citizen can fulfill their God-given potential on any field, court, or track.  More than half a century ago, Title IX of the Education Amendments Act enshrined this promise into federal law, marking a pivotal moment for equal opportunity for women and girls.  Since then, the number of female athletes has grown remarkably—and my Administration remains committed to expanding opportunities for women and girls to compete, grow, and succeed at every level.

Since I took office as the 47th President of the United States, America has once again proudly championed youth athletics, which instills in our Nation’s girls the skills they need to grow stronger, develop healthy habits, and overcome challenges—not only as athletes but as young citizens.  Last year, I proudly signed multiple Executive Orders to uphold Title IX, end the unfair participation of men in women’s sports, and preserve and expand scholarships for collegiate women’s sports.  My Administration’s policy is simple:  Any program that rejects biological reality and deprives women of fair and safe athletic opportunities will not receive federal funds.  Under my leadership, every woman’s safety, dignity, and work ethic will always be protected.

Female athletes go beyond breaking records or winning championships—they redefine what is possible, elevate their sports, and inspire the next generation of girls to achieve greatness.  Today and every day, we recommit to preserving the timeless values that sports provide and to building a future where every young girl, collegiate athlete, and professional competitor pushes further, reaches higher, and dreams bigger.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-national-women-and-girls-in-sports-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Holds Private Meeting with Freed American-Israeli Hostage Keith Siegel After Helping Secure His Release</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-holds-private-meeting-with-freed-american-israeli-hostage-keith-siegel-after-helping-secure-his-release/</link>
      <description>Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Holds Private Meeting with Freed American-Israeli Hostage Keith Siegel After Helping Secure His ReleaseThe White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Holds Private Meeting with Freed American-Israeli Hostage Keith Siegel After Helping Secure His ReleaseThe White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Holds Private Meeting with Freed American-Israeli Hostage Keith Siegel After Helping Secure His ReleaseThe White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

Office of the first lady

The White HouseFebruary 4, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump engaged in a private meeting with freed American-Israeli hostage Keith Siegel in the White House today. The First Lady’s sit-down with Aviva Siegel in January 2025 sparked a series of events that ultimately led to Keith Siegel’s liberation from Hamas.

“That first meeting with Aviva Siegel served as a catalyst to the events leading up to Keith’s freedom. It was clear that day in New York City that Aviva Siegel’s human spirit would move mountains to rescue her husband, Keith,” exclaimed First Lady Melania Trump.

“I was deeply moved to hear from the First Lady about the meetings she held with my wife, Aviva, while I was in captivity, and about the strength and support she gave to the families of the hostages throughout that difficult journey,” Keith Siegel asserted.

Aviva Siegel also participated in today’s White House meeting, saying: “I want to express my deepest gratitude to First Lady Melania Trump. Meeting again today feels profoundly full circle… I am endlessly grateful for Mrs. Trump’s steadfast support over these painful two years.”

During their initial encounter, Aviva Siegel gifted Mrs. Trump a handmade book about her husband Keith Siegel and the brutal events surrounding October 7, 2023. First Lady Melania Trump shared the handmade book and Keith Siegel’s story with President Trump later that evening in January 2025.

Keith Siegel further shared, “I am grateful to the First Lady and to the President for their tremendous efforts to secure the return of the hostages, and my own return.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-holds-private-meeting-with-freed-american-israeli-hostage-keith-siegel-after-helping-secure-his-release/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
