<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 20:06:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Announces 2026 White House Easter Egg Roll</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-announces-2026-white-house-easter-egg-roll/</link>
      <description>Office of the First lADYFirst Lady Melania Trump Announces 2026 White House Easter Egg RollThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Office of the First lADYFirst Lady Melania Trump Announces 2026 White House Easter Egg RollThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Office of the First lADYFirst Lady Melania Trump Announces 2026 White House Easter Egg RollThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Office of the First lADY

The White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump is pleased to announce initial details for the 148th White House Easter Egg Roll. The Easter Egg Roll will take place on Monday, April 6, 2026, on the South Lawn of the White House. Families with children 13 years old and younger are invited to join the President, First Lady, White House staff, and their families for a day of festivities.

The White House Easter Egg Roll is a timeless White House tradition, dating back to 1878 during the Presidency of Rutherford B. Hayes. This year, the White House Easter Egg Roll will honor America’s 250th birthday by incorporating patriotic themes throughout the event. The President and First Lady look forward to continuing this entertaining tradition and making it a truly memorable experience for all.

For more information regarding the 2026 White House Easter Egg Roll, please click here.

ONLINE TICKET LOTTERY

White House Easter Egg Roll tickets are free to the public and can be requested through an online lottery opening on Thursday, February 26, 2026, and closing on Wednesday, March 4, 2026, at 12:00 PM ET. Entering the lottery is free of charge, and winners will be notified via email no later than March 10, 2026. Tickets are not for sale or resale. Those interested in attending may enter the lotteryhere.

VOLUNTEER OPPORTUNITIES

As in previous years, the White House will select volunteers for the Easter Egg Roll through an online application. Prospective volunteers may submit their nameshere. The deadline for applying to become a volunteer is Friday, February 27, 2026.

This year’s official White House Easter Egg Roll commemorative eggs will be available to the general public. More information will be available soon by visiting the lottery’s website.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-announces-2026-white-house-easter-egg-roll/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill S. 3424 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bill-s-3424-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 3424 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 3424 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 3424 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

On Friday, February 6, 2026, the President signed into law:

S. 3424, the “Bankruptcy Administration Improvement Act of 2025,” which increases Chapter 7 Bankruptcy trustees fees, extends Chapter 11 Bankruptcy quarterly fees for an additional five years, and extends certain temporary bankruptcy judgeships for an additional five years.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bill-s-3424-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>United States-India Joint Statement</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/united-states-india-joint-statement/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsUNITED STATES-INDIA JOINT STATEMENTThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsUNITED STATES-INDIA JOINT STATEMENTThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsUNITED STATES-INDIA JOINT STATEMENTThe White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 6, 2026

The United States of America (United States) and India are pleased to announce that they have reached a framework for an Interim Agreement regarding reciprocal and mutually beneficial trade (Interim Agreement). Today’s framework reaffirms the countries’ commitment to the broader U.S.-India Bilateral Trade Agreement (BTA) negotiations, launched by President Donald J. Trump and Prime Minister Narendra Modi on February 13, 2025, which will include additional market access commitments and support more resilient supply chains. The Interim Agreement between the United States and India will represent a historic milestone in our countries’ partnership, demonstrating a common commitment to reciprocal and balanced trade based on mutual interests and concrete outcomes.

Key terms of the Interim Agreement between the United States and India will include:

The United States and India will promptly implement this framework and work towards finalizing the Interim Agreement with a view to concluding a mutually beneficial BTA consistent with the roadmap agreed in the Terms of Reference BTA consistent with the roadmap agreed in the Terms of Reference.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/united-states-india-joint-statement/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Super Bowl LX</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-super-bowl-lx/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Super Bowl LXThe White HouseFebruary 8, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Super Bowl LXThe White HouseFebruary 8, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Super Bowl LXThe White HouseFebruary 8, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 8, 2026

This Super Bowl Sunday, I send my best wishes to the athletes and coaches of the New England Patriots and the Seattle Seahawks as they take the field and to the millions of Americans gathering across the country to watch these two storied franchises compete on one of the grandest and most legendary stages in all of sports.

As our country proudly marks 250 glorious years of American independence, tonight’s game carries special meaning.  In many ways, the story of our country’s most popular sport mirrors our own American journey.  As our Nation industrialized in the early twentieth century, football emerged in working communities and reflected the same values of grit, tenacity, and discipline that defined the American worker.  As our country’s economy expanded, the game grew along with our Nation’s prosperity.  And as advances in technology connected Americans from coast to coast, football entered households everywhere, turning Sundays into traditions shared across generations.

Before kickoff this evening, during the playing of our National Anthem, we remember the patriots who secured our independence 250 years ago through courage, sacrifice, and an unwavering belief in the cause of liberty.  We pause to honor the brave men and women of our Armed Forces who carry that legacy forward, defending and preserving our way of life throughout history and into the future.  Their service makes possible the freedoms we hold dear, including the privilege to gather with family and friends on a Sunday night to watch football and the blessing to live in the strongest and freest Nation the world has ever known.

Tonight’s game is more than just a championship—it’s a uniquely American tradition that reflects the distinct passion and perseverance of our country.  On the field, players and coaches bring years of hard work, preparation, and commitment to football’s biggest night.  Across the country, millions of fans come together to cheer on their teams and share in a moment of history.  Today, every American is a football fan.

Melania and I congratulate both teams on earning their place in Super Bowl LX, and we wish them luck as they compete for the National Football League’s iconic Vince Lombardi Trophy.  May tonight’s game reflect the best of football and the enduring triumph of the American spirit—and may the best team win!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/presidential-message-on-super-bowl-lx/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joint Statement on United States – Bangladesh Agreement on Reciprocal Trade</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-bangladesh-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ONUNITED STATES – BANGLADESH AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseFebruary 9, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ONUNITED STATES – BANGLADESH AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseFebruary 9, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsJOINT STATEMENT ONUNITED STATES – BANGLADESH AGREEMENT ON RECIPROCAL TRADEThe White HouseFebruary 9, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 9, 2026

The United States of America (the United States) and the People’s Republic of Bangladesh (Bangladesh) have agreed to an Agreement on Reciprocal Trade (Agreement) to strengthen our bilateral economic relationship.  The Agreement will provide U.S. and Bangladeshi exporters unprecedented access to each other’s respective markets.  The Agreement will build upon our longstanding economic relationship, including the U.S.-Bangladesh Trade and Investment Cooperation Forum Agreement (TICFA), signed in 2013.

Key terms of the Agreement will include:</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/joint-statement-on-framework-for-united-states-bangladesh-agreement-on-reciprocal-trade/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill S. 269 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bill-s-269-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 269 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 10, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 269 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 10, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill S. 269 Signed into LawThe White HouseFebruary 10, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 10, 2026

On Tuesday, February 10, 2026, the President signed into law:

S. 269, the “Ending Improper Payments to Deceased People Act,” which permanently allows sharing of death data to prevent and recover improper payments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/congressional-bill-s-269-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Thomas Edison</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-thomas-edison/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Thomas EdisonThe White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Thomas EdisonThe White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Thomas EdisonThe White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

Today, we celebrate our Nation’s most prolific inventor and a man who never stopped pushing the spirit of American innovation:  the legendary Thomas Edison.  On what would have been his 179th birthday, we honor his life, determination, and extraordinary legacy of American entrepreneurship and ingenuity and look to his example as we continue building the Golden Age of America.

Born into humble means in Ohio and raised in Michigan, Thomas Edison’s life represents the resilience and determination that it takes to build the American Dream.  Edison had virtually no formal education and was afflicted with deafness at a young age.  Despite these challenges, he was a voracious reader who constantly tinkered with mechanics, electricity, and scientific experiments.  In his early twenties, he received his first patent for an electrical recorder and soon devoted himself entirely to invention and innovation.  He would ultimately go on to develop more than 1,000 patents and design some of the greatest inventions of his time, including the phonograph, the motion picture camera, the alkaline storage battery, and most famously, the incandescent light bulb.  Through constant trial and error, his inventions bettered the lives of everyday Americans and people all around the world.

My Administration is proudly carrying Thomas Edison’s legacy forward into the 21st century, ushering in a new Golden Age of American innovation and ingenuity.  Since returning to office, we have empowered the next generation of innovators by deregulating industries and enacting historic tax cuts for small businesses. And I will always remain committed to ensuring America retains our competitive edge across every sphere.

As we celebrate Thomas Edison’s timeless contributions to our way of life, we are reminded that technological advancement is achieved through hard work, tenacity, and an unwavering commitment to forging a great American future.  On his birthday, I call on every American to dare to dream big, achieve the impossible, and embrace the opportunity to be an outsider because, like Thomas Edison, it is the outsiders who change the world.

Happy birthday, Thomas Edison!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-thomas-edison/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Visits Children with Rare and Serious Diseases at The Children’s Inn at NIH for Valentine’s Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-visits-children-with-rare-and-serious-diseases-at-the-childrens-inn-at-nih-for-valentines-day/</link>
      <description>OFFICE OF THE FIRST LADYFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children with Rare and Serious Diseases at The Children’s Inn at NIH for Valentine’s DayThe White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

OFFICE OF THE FIRST LADYFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children with Rare and Serious Diseases at The Children’s Inn at NIH for Valentine’s DayThe White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

OFFICE OF THE FIRST LADYFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children with Rare and Serious Diseases at The Children’s Inn at NIH for Valentine’s DayThe White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

OFFICE OF THE FIRST LADY

The White HouseFebruary 11, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump visited children with rare and serious diseases at The Children’s Inn at the National Institutes of Health (NIH) for Valentine’s Day. Mrs. Trump joined the children, their families, and staff members for an afternoon of creativity, connection, and encouragement.

“Love reveals itself in many forms, especially in the hardest moments of care and compassion,” said Mrs. Trump. “The Children’s Inn provides important support to children who have been diagnosed with rare and serious diseases. Returning to The Children’s Inn at NIH is a special reminder of warmth that exists here year-round thanks to the profound resilience of these young people and the dedication of those working to provide comfort, hope, and support during clinical trials. I wish them all a very happy Valentine’s Day.”

“We were deeply honored to welcome First Lady Melania Trump back to The Children’s Inn,” said Jennie Lucca, Chief Executive Officer of The Children’s Inn. “Her visit brought joy and comfort to our children and families at a time when compassion and encouragement mean so much. This Valentine’s Day celebration served as a heartfelt reminder that our families are surrounded by care, support, and hope throughout their medical journey.”

During her visit, Mrs. Trump made handmade valentines during arts and crafts activities with children and youth who are receiving care through NIH clinical trials. Mrs. Trump also spent time speaking with families and staff, expressing her appreciation for the compassion and dedication shown to children facing serious medical challenges.

The Children’s Inn at NIH is a nonprofit that provides a free residential “place like home” to reduce the burden of illness, make childhood possible, and help advance medical research. Families with children, teens, and young adults participating in leading-edge studies at the NIH Clinical Center, the nation’s premier biomedical research hospital, have been welcomed at The Inn since 1990.

First Lady Melania Trump previously celebrated Valentine’s Day at The Children’s Inn in 2018, 2019, and 2020, continuing a tradition of highlighting the resilience of children and families and the importance of compassion in healing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-visits-children-with-rare-and-serious-diseases-at-the-childrens-inn-at-nih-for-valentines-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Secures Another Russian – Ukrainian Child Reunification</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-secures-another-russian-ukrainian-child-reunification/</link>
      <description>office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Secures Another Russian – Ukrainian Child ReunificationThe White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Secures Another Russian – Ukrainian Child ReunificationThe White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Secures Another Russian – Ukrainian Child ReunificationThe White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

office of the First Lady

The White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

United States First Lady Melania Trump successfully united Russian and Ukrainian children with their families today. For the third time, the U.S. First Lady has helped facilitate the return of children to their families after they were separated because of the regional conflict.

The American First Lady stated, “I appreciate that Russia and Ukraine are dedicated to bringing back the children who have been displaced because of the circumstances surrounding this conflict. Although all parties are cooperating and our communications remain robust, I urge Russia and Ukraine to intensify their efforts to ensure the safe return of every child to their families and guardians.”

Mrs. Trump and her representative continue to engage in discussions with both countries.  She added, “Today marks the third reunification since I have been working strategically with both nations. I have no doubt more progress will come.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/first-lady-melania-trump-secures-another-russian-ukrainian-child-reunification/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birthday of President Abraham Lincoln, 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/birthday-of-president-abraham-lincoln-2026/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsBirthday of President Abraham Lincoln, 2026The White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsBirthday of President Abraham Lincoln, 2026The White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsBirthday of President Abraham Lincoln, 2026The White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseFebruary 12, 2026

Today, our Nation celebrates the 217th birthday of President Abraham Lincoln—one of the most legendary leaders in American history whose fearless leadership in the Civil War saved our Nation from collapse and reunited a shattered Union under one flag.

Born on February 12, 1809, in a humble one-room log cabin on the Kentucky frontier, Abraham Lincoln’s life represents the incredible potential that is uniquely fostered in America.  Largely self-taught, he educated himself by reading borrowed books by candlelight after long days of labor on his family’s farm.  From those unlikely beginnings emerged a mind of remarkable clarity and depth that would later define his leadership.  Through midwestern grit and determination, Lincoln became an accomplished attorney, a State Representative, a Member of Congress, and a brilliant orator, writer, and debater.  He was undoubtedly one of the most intelligent men of his age.

Yet with every public triumph came personal tragedy, and his life reflected the complex divisions plaguing the country in the early 19th century.  His marriage to Mary Todd brought together a slave-owning family with the man who would eventually bring slavery to an end.  While his marriage flourished, the loss of three of their four beloved children left Lincoln in a dark melancholy for the rest of his life.  He and his wife bore on their face the scars of their own grief and, eventually, the grief of our entire embattled Nation.

As slavery continued to tear the Republic apart in the 1850s, Lincoln’s opposition to the expansion of slavery quickly spread across the land.  He entered the race for the United States Senate, where his legendary debates against pro-slavery Democrat Stephen Douglas made him a nationally known figure.  In 1860, the newly founded Republican Party chose him as its standard bearer, and the American people entrusted him with the presidency of the United States.

Shortly following Lincoln’s election as our 16th president, Southern States began to secede from the Union.  During the course of four grueling years, President Lincoln led the country through its darkest days and fought tirelessly to preserve our Republic during great trial.  He commanded vast armies against the forces of the Confederacy at great cost to human life, issued the Emancipation Proclamation that freed millions from the chains of bondage, and championed the Thirteenth Amendment to expel the scourge of slavery from American soil forever.

Re-elected in triumph in 1864 amid the devastation of civil war, President Lincoln turned to the solemn work of binding up our Nation’s wounds.  Armed with resolute courage, he sought to restore the rule of law, heal the divisions of civil strife, and reclaim the enduring American principles of liberty, freedom, and prosperity—ideals that had been tested to their breaking point by years of bloodshed and bitter division.  In his crusade to restore the Union and renew its founding promises, he spread a message of reconciliation, working to unite a divided Nation around its most deeply-held values.  Tragically, his commitment to justice and peace ultimately cost him his life:  Just over a month into his second term, at the age of 56, he was killed by an assassin’s bullet on April 14, 1865.

Today, more than a century and a half after President Lincoln’s death, my Administration is honoring his legacy by defending the Constitution, enforcing law and order, advancing justice, and ensuring that government of the people, by the people, and for the people shall not perish from the earth.  We are safeguarding American workers from unfair foreign competition with strong tariffs, a principle championed by President Lincoln, who understood that strategic tariffs could strengthen industry and generate great wealth.  We are standing firmly against chaos and division, rebuilding our military to its full strength, and vigorously protecting free speech, religious liberty, and the unique American heritage that has defined us across generations—values that President Lincoln defended throughout his life, even amid the peril of civil war.

As our Republic celebrates its 250th year of independence, we dedicate ourselves to the unfinished work President Lincoln entrusted to the American people.  This historic milestone demands that we once again take up his torch, summon his courage, invoke his vision, and advance the enduring truths of our founding principles.  Guided by President Lincoln’s faith in the American people and grounded in the ideals of liberty, unity, and self-government, we stand ready to chart a new and bold course toward the next 250...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/02/birthday-of-president-abraham-lincoln-2026/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
