<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:15:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American War</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-spanish-american-war/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of our Victory in the Spanish-American WarThe White HouseDecember 10, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 10, 2025

On December 10, 1898, the United States signed a historic peace treaty to end the momentous Spanish-American War.  The treaty reaffirmed the “Monroe Doctrine” by ending the age-old European foothold in the Western Hemisphere and signaled to the entire world that America was emerging as a major superpower not to be underestimated.  Today, we honor the unwavering courage, conviction, and sacrifice of every hero of liberty who fearlessly confronted forces of tyranny to defend our honor, our sovereignty, and our birthright of freedom.

As Cuba’s fight for independence escalated under King Alfonso XIII’s rule—leading to violent unrest that endangered American lives—the United States deployed the battleship USS MAINE to Havana, the capital of Cuba.  On February 15, 1898, a devastating explosion sank the ship, claiming the lives of more than 260 Americans.  This tragedy propelled the United States toward a momentous struggle for justice and ignited our Nation’s righteous determination to defend our interests and maintain our dominance in the Western Hemisphere.

The war swiftly unfolded as American troops and sailors advanced with decisive strength, securing victories from Cuba to the Philippines.  At the Battle of Manila Bay, United States forces destroyed the entire royal Spanish fleet within mere hours.  Additional fighting in Cuba was backed by Theodore Roosevelt’s legendary regiment of “Rough Riders,” a volunteer cavalry made up of cowboys, miners, and college athletes, who embodied the full measure of American strength, resilience, and grit.  These triumphant victories across land and sea brought the Spanish Empire to its breaking point and solidified the United States of America as the greatest military force in the world.

On this day 127 years ago, the Treaty of Paris formally ended the conflict and Spain relinquished its claim to Cuba and ceded Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Philippines to the United States—a pivotal moment that marked not only the conclusion of the war but the dawn of America’s role as a military superpower unlike anything the world had ever seen.

Today, we recognize the territories and partnerships forged by the Treaty of Paris, where the full force of American freedom has taken root.  Above all, we renew our commitment to a simple truth:  Peace is maintained through strength.  My Administration is proudly upholding this America First vision through our negotiations of historic peace deals in regions marked by decades of conflict—proving to nations around the world that we can turn the page on the days of endless wars and usher in a future defined by everlasting peace.

As we commemorate this anniversary of our victory in the Spanish-American War, we stand united in our unwavering commitment to peace, military strength, and the enduring principles that define the American spirit.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-our-victory-in-the-spanish-american-war/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-104-105-106-130-and-131-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res. 104, 105, 106, 130 and 131 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 11, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 11, 2025

On Thursday, December 11, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.J. Res. 104, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Miles City Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan Amendment”;

H.J. Res. 105, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “North Dakota Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan”;

H.J. Res. 106, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Central Yukon Record of Decision and Approved Resources Management Plan”;

H.J. Res. 130, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Buffalo Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resources Management Plan Amendment”; and

H.J. Res. 131, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “Coastal Plain Oil and Gas Leasing Program Record of Decision.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-104-105-106-130-and-131-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John Jay</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-john-jay/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John JayThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John JayThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of John JayThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Today, our Nation celebrates the 280th birthday of John Jay—the first Chief Justice of the United States, a titan of American sovereignty, and a key architect of our laws, our foreign policy, and our glorious American independence.

Born in New York City and raised with the timeless values of faith and civic duty, John Jay answered the call to public service at a moment when America was still fighting for its right to define itself.  As President of the Second Continental Congress, he played a central role in America’s struggle for independence, and after our victory in the Revolutionary War Jay helped to negotiate the Treaty of Paris—freeing us from tyranny and ensuring that American sovereignty was recognized all around the world.

Jay was also a central figure in molding the American constitutional order.  In 1787 and 1788, he took up his pen to author five essays ofThe Federalist Papers, articulating the eternal principles of justice that have defined our federal laws, our system of government, and our foreign policy for nearly 250 years—including his belief in a centralized Federal Government to protect the American people from the influence of nations overseas.  As the first Chief Justice appointed to the Supreme Court, he set in motion a judicial framework grounded in integrity, fairness, and the immortal promise of equal justice under the law.  And as one of our nation’s first great diplomats, the Treaty of Amity, Commerce, and Navigation that he negotiated with Great Britain kept America out of the French Revolutionary Wars and ensured a decade of peace for our fledgling nation.

He carried this same conviction from the national stage and into State governance as the second Governor of New York, where he oversaw the construction of roads and canals that supported the state’s early growth—laying a foundation that would shape major developments and lead to New York’s legendary skyline and resilient character in the generations that followed, a legacy I was proud to build upon.

As we prepare to celebrate 250 glorious years of American independence next year, we recognize John Jay’s lasting contributions to our government, our traditions, and our national character.  My Administration remains committed to preserving the principles he cherished so deeply—including that peace is preserved through strength, that our Nation’s foreign policy must always put America first, and that a nation without the rule of law ceases to be a nation at all.  Today, in John Jay’s honor, we reaffirm our commitment to liberty and justice for all and to carrying his extraordinary vision forward for years to come.

Happy birthday, John Jay!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-john-jay/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 452, H.R. 970, H.R. 983, H.R. 1912 AND S. 616 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 12, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 12, 2025

On Friday, December 12, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 452, the “Miracle on Ice Congressional Gold Medal Act,” which awards three Congressional Gold Medals to members of the 1980 U.S. Olympic Men’s Ice Hockey team;

H.R. 970, the “Fairness for Servicemembers and their Families Act of 2025,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to periodically review the automatic maximum coverage under the Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance program and the Veterans’ Group Life Insurance program;

H.R. 983, the “Montgomery GI Bill Selected Reserves Tuition Fairness Act of 2025,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to disapprove courses of education provided by educational institutions that charge higher than in-state tuition to members of the Selected Reserves living in the state;

H.R. 1912, the “Veteran Fraud Reimbursement Act of 2025,” which improves repayment of veterans’ benefits misused by a fiduciary; and

S. 616, the “Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2025,” which revises the Federal charter for the Foundation of the Federal Bar Association by allowing certain corporate requirements to be determined by the bylaws of the Foundation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Hanukkah</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-hanukkah/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on HanukkahThe White HouseDecember 14, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 14, 2025

I extend my warmest greetings to the Jewish community in the United States and all around the world as they begin their celebration of Hanukkah—the Festival of Lights and a joyous season of reflection and hope.

More than 2,000 years ago, the Jewish people rose up against the forces of tyranny and restored their freedom to worship and live according to their faith, fighting for the inalienable rights endowed by our Creator.  Following their tremendous victory, they sought to rededicate their Holy Temple.  As tradition tells us, although they only had enough oil to light the lamp in the Temple for one night, in a glorious sign of the Almighty’s divine providence, it remained aflame for 8 days.  In remembrance of this great miracle, over the next 8 days, families and loved ones will gather to light the menorah, which serves as an enduring symbol of light’s victory over darkness and the eternal triumph of good over evil.  Hanukkah is a thanksgiving for these miracles.

To this day, the menorah stands as an enduring symbol of liberty, of the idea that each citizen, in the words that George Washington wrote to the Hebrew Congregation in Newport, “shall sit in safety under his own vine and fig tree and there shall be none to make him afraid.”

This holiday season, my Administration continues to stand firmly with the Jewish people and defend the right of every believer to worship freely and without fear of persecution.  The flames of Hanukkah stand as a reminder of the strength and resilience of the Jewish people and of the spirit that continues to guide our Nation toward a brighter future.

Just as the grace of the Almighty brought the Maccabees to victory, it has sustained the miracle of America—a shining light to the entire world—for nearly 250 years.  As we continue to usher in the Golden Age, may the blessings of this season bring renewed peace, joy, and warmth to all those who celebrate.  Happy Hanukkah!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-hanukkah/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the Bulge</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-the-bulge/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Battle of the BulgeThe White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 16, 2025

Today, we commemorate the 81st anniversary of the legendary Battle of the Bulge—the largest and deadliest battle fought by American forces in the Second World War, which culminated in a blistering, brutal, and breakthrough Allied victory that ultimately forced the Nazi regime into total surrender.

After a series of sweeping victories across Western Europe—including the D-Day landings of American, British, and Canadian forces in Normandy, France—Allied forces were confident that the Nazi army was on the brink of collapse.  Desperate to halt the Allied advance and reverse their momentum, Adolf Hitler ordered a massive surprise offensive through the Ardennes Forest, aiming to split the Allied lines, capture a vital port, and force peace negotiations on more favorable terms for Germany.

On the frigid morning of December 16, 1944, Nazi troops numbering approximately 200,000 men launched their full-scale assault on Allied personnel resting in the Ardennes Forest.  Though they initially gained ground, the Germans soon encountered the unbreakable resolve and overwhelming strength of the Allied armies.  With reinforcements pouring in, more than 500,000 German and 600,000 Allied troops—including 500,000 American soldiers—battled in blinding snow and sub-zero temperatures for 41 excruciating days, including Christmas, as soldiers held the front lines in defense of our freedom far away from home.

The American-led Allies held firm and withstood relentless assaults, halting the German advance and inflicting devastating casualties.  They secured a crucial victory, shattering the resources and manpower of the enemy and setting the stage for the Allied invasion of Germany and the eventual collapse and surrender of the Nazi regime.  With 19,000 American soldiers tragically killed during the battle, the Battle of the Bulge stands as the single deadliest American military engagement of World War II—a testament to the indispensable role the United States played in securing the victory of the Allied powers and ending the war.  Without the sacrifice of our American soldiers, the war would not have been won, and our world today would look drastically different.

On the anniversary of the Battle of the Bulge, we honor the legacy of the soldiers who fought to save the world from tyranny, destruction, and evil.  And as we approach 250 years of American independence, we renew our resolve that the blessings of freedom are only secured by the devotion and sacrifices of the patriots willing to defend it.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-battle-of-the-bulge/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on Wright Brothers Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-wright-brothers-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on Wright Brothers DayThe White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 17, 2025

Today our Nation celebrates the heroic moment America took to the skies when Orville and Wilbur Wright launched the first controlled, machine-powered aircraft on December 17, 1903.  This Wright Brothers Day, we honor the genius and bravery of two pioneers from Dayton, Ohio, and we proudly carry their legacy forward by championing the imagination, perseverance, and bold ambition that gave rise to their magnificent achievement.

What the Wright brothers lacked in formal education, they matched with unrelenting drive.  Despite not earning high school degrees, Orville and Wilbur taught themselves the mechanical and engineering skills they needed to build their first aircraft.  They drew inspiration from European gliders and soon after attempted their own leap into the uncharted frontier of powered flight.  After 4 years of relentless research, design, and testing, their work paid off on a cold, gray day near Kitty Hawk when Orville lifted theirFlyerinto the air for 12 seconds, traveling 120 feet at just under 7 miles per hour.  Orville and Wilbur’s feat marked the first time in history that man lifted off the ground in a piloted, mechanized flying machine.

The Wright brothers’ epic feat on the windswept shores of North Carolina opened a new chapter of innovation for all mankind and began a new era of American aviation power that continues to propel our country upwards among the clouds and beyond.  Since that historic day in North Carolina, the United States has remained the world leader in flight and aviation.  Less than seven decades later, the Wright brothers’ triumph at Kitty Hawk led Americans to the moon, and my Administration is focused on returning there, and beyond to Mars.

We are also continuing the Wright brothers’ proud legacy by presiding over a new Golden Age of air travel and innovation.  Shortly after I returned to office, I signed an Executive Order restoring excellence and safety within the Federal Aviation Administration.  We are ending disastrous so-called “Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion” programs that put Americans at risk and restoring the sacred principle of merit to hiring practices.  Through the passage of the One Big Beautiful Bill, we are investing $12.5 billion to modernize air traffic control with cutting-edge technology.

America is also leading the way in supersonic flight.  I have ordered the administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to conduct groundbreaking levels of research and development into commercial supersonic flight, driving new advances in air travel that will incorporate the latest Artificial Intelligence technologies.

In the 122 years since the Wright brothers’ revolutionary flight, our Nation has never stopped gazing upward in wonder and hope.  As we commemorate Orville and Wilbur’s legendary achievement today, we pledge to carry their vision into every new frontier and keep America’s skies bright with the innovation, discovery, and unstoppable spirit that drive our Nation to new heights.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-wright-brothers-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law-ed35/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2283 AND S. 356 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 18, 2025

On Thursday, December 18, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 2283, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 201 West Oklahoma Avenue in Guthrie, Oklahoma, as the Oscar J. Upham Post Office; and

S. 356, the “Secure Rural Schools Reauthorization Act of 2025,” which reauthorizes the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 through fiscal year 2026.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-452-h-r-970-h-r-983-h-r-1912-and-s-616-signed-into-law-ed35/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement by the President</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/statement-by-the-president-7598/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsSTATEMENT BY THE PRESIDENTThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsSTATEMENT BY THE PRESIDENTThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsSTATEMENT BY THE PRESIDENTThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Today, I have signed into law S. 1071, the “National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026” (the “Act”).  The Act authorizes fiscal year appropriations for the Department of War (DoW), the Department of Energy national security programs, the Department of State, the Department of Homeland Security, the Intelligence Community, and other executive departments and agencies.  The Act will enable the DoW to carry out my Peace Through Strength agenda, protect the homeland from domestic and foreign threats, and strengthen the defense industrial base, while eliminating funding for wasteful and radical programs that undermine the warfighting ethos of our Nation’s men and women in uniform.  Importantly, the Act codifies aspects of over a dozen Executive Orders and actions taken by my Administration, including those focused on warfighter lethality, advancing homeland missile defense by fully supporting the Golden Dome for America plan, restoring America’s airspace sovereignty, and providing Federal recognition of the Lumbee Tribe of North Carolina.

Over the next 3 years, the United States will host numerous major events that necessitate new authorities to combat emerging security threats.  The Act includes the critical SAFER SKIES Act, which provides State and local law enforcement with the authority to protect against unmanned aircraft when they present a threat to the public and creates a new felony offense for a second violation of national defense airspace.  In addition, the Act provides key resources to ensure the continued security of the southern border from illegal immigration and transnational criminal organizations.

Although I am pleased to support the critical objectives of the Act, I note that certain provisions of the Act raise concerns.

Certain provisions of the Act, including sections 343, 1032-1035, 1048(d)(4)(B), 1266, 5143, and 8304(a), purport to dictate the position of the United States in external military and foreign affairs.  My Administration will treat these provisions consistent with the President’s constitutional authority as Commander in Chief of the Armed Forces and the President’s constitutional authority to conduct the foreign affairs of the United States, which includes the authority to recognize foreign sovereigns.

Several provisions of the Act, including sections 364(a), 383(d), 737, 851, 1070, 1235, 1245, 1253, 1546, 1622, 1806(c), 3111, 6102(b)(3), 6303, 6502(b), 6521, 6524, 6712, 7213, 8102(b), 8315(1)(A)(iii), 8341(a), 8361(b)(3)(A), 8363(h), and 8521, purport to require the President to submit information to the Congress — such as deliberative process and national security information — protected by long-recognized legal privileges.  My Administration will treat these provisions consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to withhold information, the disclosure of which could impair foreign relations, national security, the deliberative processes of the executive branch, and the performance of the President’s constitutional duties.

Additionally, section 1622 of the Act purports to require my Administration to provide the Congress with sensitive national security information on programs, operations, actions, and activities that become compromised or fail, and section 6504 of the Act purports to require the granting of security clearances to certain persons.  My Administration will implement these provisions only to the extent that they are consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to control the dissemination of sensitive national security information.

Several provisions of the Act, including sections 915(a) and 1046(a), purport to restrict the President’s authority to control the personnel and materiel the President believes to be necessary or advisable for the successful conduct of military missions.  While I share the objectives of the Congress with respect to maintaining the strength and security of the United States, my Administration will implement these provisions consistent with the President’s authority as Commander in Chief.

Other provisions of the Act, including sections 1249, 1268, 1507, 1546, and 1655, purport to require that the Congress receive a certification, notification, or report before the President directs certain military or diplomatic actions, including the withdrawal of troops below a minimum number in particular theaters.  I reiterate the longstanding understanding of the executive branch that such provisions encompass only actions for which such advance certification, notification, or report is feasible and consistent with the President’s constitutional authorities as Commander in Chief and his authority to condu...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/statement-by-the-president-7598/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill S. 1071 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-s-1071-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL S. 1071 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL S. 1071 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCONGRESSIONAL BILL S. 1071 SIGNED INTO LAWThe White HouseDecember 18, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 18, 2025

On Thursday, December 18, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 1071, the “National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026,” which authorizes fiscal year 2026 appropriations principally for Department of War programs and military construction, Department of Energy national security programs, Intelligence programs, and Department of State programs; supports a military basic pay increase and other authorities relating to the United States Armed Forces; and provides authorities related to and makes other modifications to national security, foreign affairs, homeland, commerce, judiciary, and other related programs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bill-s-1071-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
