<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:21:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of Paris</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-1783-treaty-of-paris/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of ParisThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of ParisThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Anniversary of the Ratification of the 1783 Treaty of ParisThe White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 14, 2026

On January 14, 1784, the Second Continental Congress ratified the decisive Treaty of Paris—the binding accord that ended the Revolutionary War, secured American independence, and triumphantly declared all 13 colonies “to be free sovereign and Independent States.”  Today, we celebrate this monumental milestone, and we pay tribute to the grit, greatness, and unyielding resolve of the patriots of 1776 who pledged their lives, fortunes, and sacred honor for freedom’s cause.

The cessation of hostilities with the British Empire, proclaimed on April 11, 1783, ended 8 years of brutal warfare and the most significant struggle for freedom the world had ever seen.  After the fighting ended, the difficult and lengthy peace talks required strategic negotiation, moral clarity, and skillful diplomacy.  To achieve lasting peace, the Second Continental Congress sent a trio of true American titans—Benjamin Franklin, John Jay, and John Adams—who defended American interests and fortified our fledgling Republic.  The treaty, signed on September 3, 1783, nearly 2 years after the epic British surrender at Yorktown, resulted in a glorious affirmation of American sovereignty.

Under the Articles of Confederation, then the governing framework of the United States, ratification of the treaty required a quorum of nine States.  On this day 242 years ago, the delegates convened in a State House in Annapolis, Maryland, and with the final vote from South Carolina, the treaty was unanimously ratified, and our birthright of freedom was finally secured.

This year—our 250th year of glorious American independence—we reaffirm the righteous principles that breathed life into our Republic more than two centuries ago.  We renew our resolve to uphold and defend peace through strength, the rule of law, loyalty to our citizens, and faith in Almighty God.  Above all, we vow that the timeless truths forged by our forefathers will forever remain a mighty beacon of hope, prosperity, and liberty to the entire world.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-anniversary-of-the-ratification-of-the-1783-treaty-of-paris/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career Ambitions</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-inspires-americas-children-to-be-curious-use-ai-to-achieve-their-career-ambitions/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career AmbitionsThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career AmbitionsThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Inspires America’s Children to be Curious, Use AI to Achieve their Career AmbitionsThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump advanced her mission to improve America’s children’s understanding of artificial intelligence (AI) today. Her goal to empower the next generation with AI and education reached thousands of schools nationwide, in partnership with Zoom Communications.

America’s First Lady inspired participants, “The Age of Imagination is a new era, powered by artificial intelligence, where one’s curiosity can be satisfied almost magically, in seconds.”

The First Lady also emphasized that curiosity optimizes AI use, “History reminds us that curiosity is the driving force behind every great achievement. The world’s greatest minds – our writers, architects, scientists, and painters – all had endless interest about human nature, and they all questioned that which was yet to be answered.”

Zoom’s CEO &amp; Founder Eric Yuan, a clear leader in the TechEd space, stressed the need for AI safety, “AI is changing how we learn, work, and connect every day. That’s why it’s so important to help students and educators build AI literacy and feel confident using these tools in thoughtful, creative, and ethical ways.”

Mrs. Trump concluded, “Although artificial intelligence can generate images and information, only humans can generate meaning and purpose. Choose to let your imagination drive your intellectual progress. But never use AI as a quick solution. Be intellectually honest with yourself – use AI as a tool – but do not let it replace your personal intelligence.”

Mrs. Trump called on the international community to join her mission to empower children with technology and education during the 2025 United Nations General Assembly. The First Lady, Melania Trump, will be hosting the inaugural meeting of Fostering the Future Together at the White House this spring.

Remarks by First Lady Melania Trump (as prepared for delivery)

Curiosity For Intellectual Freedom

Thank you, Mr. Yuan, Zoom’s leadership in the TechEd space is unmatched. Your support directly advances my mission to prepare America’s next generation to use AI to enhance their education, and ultimately their careers. Indeed, this is an incredible time.

We are living in the Age of Imagination.

The Age of Imagination is a new era, powered by artificial intelligence, where one’s curiosity can be satisfied almost magically, in seconds. You are fortunate to have the capability to fulfill your dreams through the power of learning, with AI serving as the primary engine for creative exploration.

History reminds us that curiosity is the driving force behind every great achievement.  The world’s greatest minds – our writers, architects, scientists, and painters – all had endless interest about human nature, and they all questioned that which was yet to be answered.

Are you ready to produce your own movie? Do you want to build the next Dress to Impress empire? Have you ever wondered how to become the next master artist? Create your own song?

Every giant, at some point in time, questions the status quo. Their singular vision pushes humanity in a new direction.

Artificial intelligence is changing today’s world, and your curiosity should serve as the driving force. For the first time in history, the young girl dreaming of becoming a fashion designer and the young boy who wants to stand-up his cool animated superhero series can do so, from their own home.

Artificial Intelligence provides all the tools needed to implement your creative vision – today. You can develop movie characters, scripts, fashion, music, art – the entire ecosystem. All with AI.

But, what do you need to start? You need to harness your Imagination. In the new AI era, the most powerful skill is knowing what to ask, why it matters, and how to think beyond the first answer.

I encourage you to be stubbornly curious, think outside the box, and question everything.

Creators must stretch their minds to think differently. The world of possibility is endless, and AI is extending the conceptual in ways never dreamed of before. In the past, memorization unlocked opportunity. Today, your curiosity will open new doors to meaning, innovation, and leadership.

But we must remember, although artificial intelligence can generate images and information, only humans can generate meaning and purpose. Deep thinking, patience, and staying curious are where purpose begins.

Today, I urge you to take action: use AI to unlock new parts of your imagination. Lead with your id...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-inspires-americas-children-to-be-curious-use-ai-to-achieve-their-career-ambitions/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza Conflict</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/statement-on-president-trumps-comprehensive-plan-to-end-the-gaza-conflict/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsStatement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza ConflictThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsStatement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza ConflictThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsStatement on President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza ConflictThe White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 16, 2026

Yesterday, President Donald J. Trump congratulated the formation of the National Committee for the Administration of Gaza (NCAG), a vital step forward in implementing Phase Two of his Comprehensive Plan to End the Gaza Conflict—a 20-point roadmap for lasting peace, stability, reconstruction, and prosperity in the region.

The NCAG will be led by Dr. Ali Sha’ath, a widely respected technocratic leader who will oversee the restoration of core public services, the rebuilding of civil institutions, and the stabilization of daily life in Gaza, while laying the foundation for long-term, self-sustaining governance. Dr. Sha’ath brings deep experience in public administration, economic development, and international engagement, and is widely respected for his pragmatic, technocratic leadership and understanding of Gaza’s institutional realities.

This milestone perfectly aligns with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2803 (2025), which endorsed President Trump’s Comprehensive Plan and welcomed the establishment of the Board of Peace. The Board of Peace will play an essential role in fulfilling all 20 points of the President’s plan, providing strategic oversight, mobilizing international resources, and ensuring accountability as Gaza transitions from conflict to peace and development.

To operationalize the Board of Peace’s vision—under the chairmanship of President Donald J. Trump—a founding Executive Board has been formed, composed of leaders with experience across diplomacy, development, infrastructure, and economic strategy. The appointed members are:

Each Executive Board member will oversee a defined portfolio critical to Gaza’s stabilization and long-term success, including, but not limited to, governance capacity-building, regional relations, reconstruction, investment attraction, large-scale funding, and capital mobilization.

In support of this operating model, the Chairman has appointed Aryeh Lightstone and Josh Gruenbaum as senior advisors to the Board of Peace, charged with leading day-to-day strategy and operations, and translating the Board’s mandate and diplomatic priorities into disciplined execution.

H.E. Nickolay Mladenov, an Executive Board member, will serve as the High Representative for Gaza. In this capacity, he will act as the on-the-ground link between the Board of Peace and the NCAG. He will support the Board’s oversight of all aspects of Gaza’s governance, reconstruction, and development, while ensuring coordination across civilian and security pillars.

To establish security, preserve peace, and establish a durable terror-free environment, Major General Jasper Jeffers has been appointed Commander of the International Stabilization Force (ISF), where he will lead security operations, support comprehensive demilitarization, and enable the safe delivery of humanitarian aid and reconstruction materials.

In support of the Office of the High Representative and the NCAG, a Gaza Executive Board is being established. The Board will help support effective governance and the delivery of best-in-class services that advance peace, stability, and prosperity for the people of Gaza. The appointed members are:

The United States remains fully committed to supporting this transitional framework, working in close partnership with Israel, key Arab nations, and the international community to achieve the objectives of the Comprehensive Plan. The President calls on all parties to cooperate fully with the NCAG, the Board of Peace, and the International Stabilization Force to ensure the swift and successful implementation of the Comprehensive Plan.

Additional Executive Board and Gaza Executive Board members will be announced over the coming weeks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/statement-on-president-trumps-comprehensive-plan-to-end-the-gaza-conflict/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin Franklin</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-benjamin-franklin/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin FranklinThe White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin FranklinThe White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsAmerica 250: Presidential Message on the Birthday of Benjamin FranklinThe White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 17, 2026

Today, we celebrate the towering life and legacy of Benjamin Franklin—printer and philosopher, inventor and diplomat, public servant and patriot, and one of the most consequential Americans to ever live.  On what would have been his 320th birthday, we honor his restless genius, his steadfast devotion to liberty, and his legendary contributions to our national story.

Born on January 17, 1706, in Boston, Massachusetts, Franklin grew up the 15th of 17 children.  Raised with little formal education, he taught himself how to read and write, emerging at age 23 as one of the most successful and influential publishers in the Colonies.  He was also a passionate innovator, always striving to improve the lives of his fellow citizens through public service and the marvels of science.  Throughout his life, he invented the lightning rod and the first bifocal glasses, harnessed the power of electricity with his famous “key and kite” experiment, established the first public library and volunteer fire department, and served as the first Postmaster General, binding the Colonies together with an organized mail system long before they were bound together as one Nation.

Of his countless triumphs and successes, his most epic contributions to our Republic were those that fortified the cause of freedom.  While living in England as an ambassador for the Pennsylvania Assembly, Franklin witnessed firsthand the growing British hostility toward the Colonies.  In 1775, Franklin was selected as a delegate to the Second Continental Congress, where, together with fellow patriots John Adams and Thomas Jefferson, he helped draft the Declaration of Independence, suggesting to Jefferson that he include the immortal phrase:  “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal.”

Franklin’s unshakable commitment to the causes of the Revolution ultimately led him across the Atlantic once more, where he played a pivotal role in securing French support for the patriot cause against the British Empire and acted as a principal negotiator of the 1783 Treaty of Paris, which ended the Revolutionary War.  After American independence was finally won, he played a vital role in rallying support for the ratification of the Constitution in 1788.  Franklin is one of only six men to have signed both the Declaration of Independence and the Constitution.

Benjamin Franklin is often remembered as the “First American”—a title that reflects a life devoted to curiosity, industry, and the cause of human freedom.  His intellect and character helped shape an American identity grounded in courage, self-reliance, and civic duty.  Franklin gave the young country confidence and direction, demonstrating how knowledge and public service could advance the cause of liberty.  His legacy endures in our institutions, our Constitution, and the very character of our Republic—a testament to how one man’s ideas and actions can echo through the history of a nation for 250 glorious years.

Happy birthday, Benjamin Franklin!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/america-250-presidential-message-on-the-birthday-of-benjamin-franklin/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on the College Football Playoff National Championship</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-the-college-football-playoff-national-championship/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the College Football Playoff National ChampionshipThe White HouseJanuary 19, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the College Football Playoff National ChampionshipThe White HouseJanuary 19, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on the College Football Playoff National ChampionshipThe White HouseJanuary 19, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 19, 2026

Tonight, the College Football Playoff National Championship brings a season of dedication, sacrifice, and hard work to a climactic conclusion.  It stands as the final measure of months of preparation, resolve, and competition that have long defined college football—a beloved and uniquely American tradition.

For more than 150 years, college football has been a cherished fixture in American culture.  Every fall and winter, massive crowds flock to stadiums in college towns all across our Nation to witness the epic display of loyalty, rivalry, tradition, and regional identity erupting throughout the stands and on the field below.  From the very first collegiate matchup in 1869, our country’s love of this storied Saturday ritual has been passed down from one generation to the next and endured as an iconic American institution.

At its best, college football reflects our timeless American values of family, freedom, unity, and hard work and represents the pinnacle of our national spirit.  It is seen in the players whose focus, discipline, and unwavering grit are forged in every practice and workout.  It is upheld by the coaches who set high standards, demand greatness, and help cultivate incredible student-athletes—and even better Americans—who stop at nothing to achieve their God-given potential both on and off the field.  And it is sustained by the fans whose dedication gives college football its lasting meaning, passion, and glory.

Melania and I congratulate the Indiana Hoosiers and the Miami Hurricanes on making it to the College Football Playoff National Championship.  God bless the talented players and dedicated coaches, the families who love and support them, and the faithful fans who cheer them on.  May the best team win!</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-the-college-football-playoff-national-championship/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 224, H.R. 1823, H.R. 4446 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-h-r-224-h-r-1823-h-r-4446-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 224, H.R. 1823, H.R. 4446 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 20, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 224, H.R. 1823, H.R. 4446 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 20, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 224, H.R. 1823, H.R. 4446 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 20, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 20, 2026

On Tuesday, January 20, 2026, the President signed into law:

H.R. 224, the “Disabled Veterans Housing Support Act,” which amends section 102(a)(20) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to require the exclusion of service-connected disability compensation when determining whether a person is a person of low and moderate income, a person of low income, or a person of moderate income, and for other purposes;

H.R. 1823, the “VA Budget Shortfall Accountability Act,” which requires a report on certain funding shortfalls in the Department of Veterans Affairs; and H.R. 4446, the “Focused Assistance and Skills Training for Veterans’ Employment and Transition Success Act” or the “FAST VETS Act,” which specifies the conditions under which a veteran’s vocational rehabilitation plan must be redeveloped.

H.R. 4446, the “Focused Assistance and Skills Training for Veterans’ Employment and Transition Success Act” or the “FAST VETS Act,” which specifies the conditions under which a veteran’s vocational rehabilitation plan must be redeveloped.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-h-r-224-h-r-1823-h-r-4446-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-national-sanctity-of-human-life-day-2026/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on National Sanctity of Human Life Day, 2026The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 22, 2026

On July 4, 1776, our Declaration of Independence righteously affirmed that every human being is endowed by Almighty God with the unalienable right to life.  In the 250 years since, our commitment to this truth has been the source of our strength and the foundation of our greatness — and it has helped America remain the single greatest force for justice and human flourishing in the history of the world.  This National Sanctity of Human Life Day, we renew our steadfast commitment to fostering a culture that respects, upholds, and cherishes the inherent dignity and infinite worth of every precious human soul.

Today marks the 53rd anniversary ofRoe v. Wade— a moral and constitutional atrocity that silenced the American people and stripped the States of their right to protect the unborn.  Thankfully, in June 2022, the United States Supreme Court corrected this disastrous decision, and decades of left-wing judicial overreach, by returning abortion policy to the American people in the States.  During my first term, I was proud to have appointed three of the Associate Justices who delivered this triumphant victory for life, liberty, and American democracy.

From the moment I returned to office as the 47th President of the United States, I have taken decisive action to protect the unborn and restore a culture that unapologetically defends the sanctity of life.  I was proud to enforce the Hyde Amendment and reinstate the Mexico City Policy — ending taxpayer-funded abortion at home and abroad.  I also pardoned 23 pro-life activists who were unfairly targeted and prosecuted by a weaponized Department of Justice (DOJ) for practicing their faith and living their conscience.  At my direction, the DOJ is now investigating the weaponization of Government against Christians and Americans of faith.

Last summer, I also proudly signed into law the One Big Beautiful Bill — a monumental win for life and the American family that expands the child tax credit, increases access to childcare, makes the paid leave tax credit permanent, protects Medicaid from funding large abortion providers, and establishes Trump accounts for newborn babies for the future of our Nation.  My Administration is also committed to supporting policies that advocate for adoption, promote foster care, and protect pregnant women and mothers.  At every level of the Federal Government, my Administration is boldly advancing policies that protect the most vulnerable among us and promote the growth and success of America’s families.

Today, we uphold the eternal truth that every human being is created in the holy image and likeness of God, blessed with infinite worth and boundless potential.  We celebrate the heroic leaders, parents, students, and everyday citizens — including those gathering for the March for Life in Washington, D.C., this weekend — who have courageously advocated for the most vulnerable and stood up for those who cannot stand up for themselves.  As President, I pledge to always be a voice for the voiceless and to never tire in fighting to protect the intrinsic dignity of every child, born and unborn.

Today, I call on the American people to join me in honoring the dignity of every human life, including those not yet born, to continue to care for women in unexpected pregnancies, and to support adoption and foster care in a more meaningful way so every child can have a loving home.  Finally, I ask every citizen of this great Nation to listen to the sound of silence caused by a generation lost to us and then to raise their voices for all affected by abortion, both seen and unseen.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-national-sanctity-of-human-life-day-2026/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock Exchange</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-to-ring-opening-bell-of-the-new-york-stock-exchange/</link>
      <description>Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock ExchangeThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock ExchangeThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Office of the first ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump to Ring Opening Bell of the New York Stock ExchangeThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Office of the first lady

The White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

First Lady Melania Trump will ring the opening bell of the New York Stock Exchange on Wednesday, January 28, 2026, following an impactful first year of leadership as First Lady of the United States during the second term of the Trump Administration.

Over the past year, Mrs. Trump has taken action to advance a results-driven agenda that is centered on the well-being of children in the United States and around the world. Some of her achievements include:

More information for media on the New York Stock Exchange opening bell is availablehere.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/first-lady-melania-trump-to-ring-opening-bell-of-the-new-york-stock-exchange/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-h-r-4323-and-h-r-6938-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bill H.R. 4323 and H.R. 6938 Signed into LawThe White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 23, 2026

On Friday, January 23, 2026, the President signed into law:

H.R. 4323, the “Trafficking Survivors Relief Act,” which establishes a process to allow human trafficking victims to file motions to vacate their convictions and expunge their arrest records for certain criminal offenses committed as a direct result of their being trafficked; and H.R. 6938, the “Commerce, Justice, Science; Energy and Water Development; and Interior and Environment Appropriations Act, 2026,” which makes consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes.

H.R. 6938, the “Commerce, Justice, Science; Energy and Water Development; and Interior and Environment Appropriations Act, 2026,” which makes consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/congressional-bill-h-r-4323-and-h-r-6938-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance Day</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-international-holocaust-remembrance-day/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance DayThe White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance DayThe White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

Briefings &amp; StatementsPresidential Message on International Holocaust Remembrance DayThe White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseJanuary 27, 2026

This International Holocaust Remembrance Day, we remember one of the darkest periods in human history and one of the gravest atrocities the world has ever witnessed.  Today, we pay respect to the blessed memories of the millions of Jewish people, who were murdered at the hands of the Nazi Regime and its collaborators during the Holocaust— as well as the Slavs and the Roma, people with disabilities, religious leaders, persons targeted based on their sexual orientation, and political prisoners who were also targeted for systematic slaughter.  We renew our resolve that freedom, justice, and the dignity of the human person will always conquer the forces of evil, tyranny, and oppression.

On January 27, 1945, 81 years ago today, Allied forces liberated Auschwitz-Birkenau, the Nazi Regime’s largest concentration and death camp in World War II, where over one million people were marched to their senseless deaths.  Within the camp’s barbed-wire electric fence, those imprisoned there were stripped of their clothing, personal possessions, and God-given dignity.  Countless were immediately murdered, and others were subjected to forced labor, starvation, disease, torture, and medical experiments.  The barbaric conditions knew no bounds.

The systematic murder of Jewish people across Nazi-occupied Europe remains an indelible blight on mankind.  In remembrance of all who perished during the Holocaust and in honor of all those who survived and rebuilt their lives from the ashes, we renew our pledge that such evil will never again attain a stronghold in the West.  After I took office as the 47th President of the United States, I proudly made it this administration’s priority directing the Federal Government to use all appropriate legal tools to combat the scourge of anti-Semitism.  My Administration will remain a steadfast and unequivocal champion for Jewish Americans and the God-given right of every American to practice their faith freely, openly, and without fear.

On this solemn day, we remember every man, woman, and child senselessly killed by the evil, depravity, and hate of the Nazi Regime—and we commend the survivors who dedicated their lives to sharing their stories while carrying the unimaginable burden of the seen and unseen scars.  This International Holocaust Remembrance Day, and every day, we honor their enduring resilience, faith, and strength—and we recommit to the sacred truth that every human being is made in the holy image of God.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2026/01/presidential-message-on-international-holocaust-remembrance-day/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
