<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
    <link>whitehouse_briefings.xml</link>
    <description>Official Briefings and Statements from the White House</description>
    <atom:link href="whitehouse_briefings.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/selenasun1618/whitehouse-rss-feeds/main/whitehouse-47-logo.webp</url>
      <title>White House Briefings &amp; Statements</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/</link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>144</height>
    </image>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:11:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bills-s-2392-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S. 2392 Signed into LawThe White HouseNovember 25, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseNovember 25, 2025

On Tuesday, November 25, 2025, the President signed into law:

S. 2392, the “Veterans’ Compensation Cost-of-Living Adjustment Act of 2025,” which increases, effective as of December 1, 2025, the rates of compensation for veterans with service-connected disabilities and the rates of dependency and indemnity compensation for the survivors of certain disabled veterans, and for other purposes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/11/congressional-bills-s-2392-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base Andrews</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/flotus_joins_military_spouses_american_red_cross/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base AndrewsThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base AndrewsThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Joins Military Spouses for American Red Cross Holiday Care Package Event at Joint Base AndrewsThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 1, 2025

First Lady Melania Trump visited Joint Base Andrews to celebrate the beginning of the Christmas season and honor the strength and service of America’s military families. Mrs. Trump delivered brief remarks in a base hangar before joining military spouses to assemble holiday care packages for deployed Service members.

“Every package built here today is built with American values. Each represents liberty, love, community, and honor. Each is delivered with heart and love. The foundation of our great nation,” exclaimed America’s First Lady Melania Trump.

The event highlighted the resilience, sacrifice, and unwavering commitment of military families—particularly the spouses who shoulder the unique responsibilities of military life. Mrs. Trump expressed deep gratitude for their service to the Nation and emphasized the importance of supporting those who spend the holidays separated from loved ones.

The care-package project was made possible through a collaboration with the American Red Cross, which provides support to Service members and their families throughout the year.

The First Lady was joined by several Cabinet spouses, including: Mrs. Jennifer Hegseth, Mrs. Kathryn Burgum, Mrs. Cheryl Hines, Mrs. Liz Wright, Mrs. Lisa Collins, and Mrs. Marlo Greer.

The Office of the First Lady shared its appreciation with the leadership and personnel of Joint Base Andrews for facilitating this special event and for their year-round contributions to the mission success of countless trips and engagements by the President and the First Lady.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/flotus_joins_military_spouses_american_red_cross/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOME IS WHERE THE HEART IS – First Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas Theme</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/home-is-where-the-heart-isfirst-lady-melania-trumps-2025-white-house-christmas-theme/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyHOME IS WHERE THE HEART ISFirst Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas ThemeThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyHOME IS WHERE THE HEART ISFirst Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas ThemeThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First LadyHOME IS WHERE THE HEART ISFirst Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas ThemeThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 1, 2025

First Lady Melania Trump’s 2025 White House Christmas theme,Home Is Where The Heart Is, illuminates the heartfelt character of America within the People’s House.

The First Lady’s creative inspiration is drawn from the joys, challenges, and frequent motion derived from motherhood and business. “The constant movement has taught me that home is not merely a physical space; rather, it is the warmth and comfort I carry within, regardless of my surroundings,” America’s First Lady reflects. “This Christmas, let’s celebrate the love we hold within ourselves, and share it with the world around us.  After all, wherever we are, we can create a home filled with grace, radiance, and endless possibilities.”

Fostering the Future Red RoomFirst Lady Melania Trump appointed renowned designer, Hervé Pierre, to oversee the implementation of her creative vision. Blue butterflies illuminate the “Fostering the Future Red Room,” a transformational experience dedicated to the foster-care community, a cause the First Lady has championed since 2021. The striking color combination coupled with the butterflies symbolic meaning of transformation and renewal capture the essence of Christmas.

Mr. Pierre also created a limited-edition tour booklet—an artful keepsake that captures the magic of this year’s White House’s holiday theme for guests to treasure.

Time-Honored TraditionHonoring tradition, 75 of Mrs. Trump’s signature wreaths with classic red bows adorn the White House windows, and more than 50 Christmas trees, 700 feet of garland, 25,000 feet of ribbon, and 10,000 butterflies fill the halls with holiday warmth.

Gold Star FamiliesIn the Blue Room, the official White House Christmas Tree, an 18-foot concolor fir from Sidney, Michigan, commemorates Gold Star Families with gold stars and ornaments representing the official bird and flower of every U.S. state and territory—a tribute to the resilience, bravery, and sacrifice of our military personnel and their families.

250th AnniversaryPatriotic exhibits featuring America’s signature red, white, and blue accentuate the upcoming 250th anniversary of the Nation in the East Room, while two presidential portraits created from over 6,000 puzzle pieces are presented in the Green Room, offering families the chance to be challenged, have fun, and use their imagination together.

120 Pounds of GingerbreadThe 2025 Gingerbread House is prominently displayed in the State Dining Room, highlighting the South Portico and offering a glimpse of the Yellow Oval Room—an artistic culinary triumph, boasting more than 120 pounds of gingerbread. The Grand Foyer features a section of the historic White House Crèche, which is currently undergoing meticulous restoration by the White House Curators. As Americans explore the historic rooms of the White House this holiday season, the 2025 Christmas decorations serve as a reminder that the strength of our Nation is found in its people—in our shared values, valued traditions, and the steadfast belief that home is where the heart is.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/home-is-where-the-heart-isfirst-lady-melania-trumps-2025-white-house-christmas-theme/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-695-and-h-r-2483-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.R. 695 and H.R. 2483 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 1, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 1, 2025

On Monday, December 1, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.R. 695, the “Medal of Honor Act,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to increase the rate of the special monthly pension payable to living Medal of Honor recipients; and

H.R. 2483, the “SUPPORT for Patients and Communications Reauthorization Act of 2025,” which reauthorizes programs related to substance use disorder prevention, treatment, and recovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-r-695-and-h-r-2483-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-133-and-h-r-1512-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 2, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 2, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills H.J. Res 133 and H.R. 1512 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 2, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 2, 2025

On Tuesday, December 2, 2025, the President signed into law:

H.J. Res 133, which requests the Secretary of the Interior to authorize unique and one-time arrangements for displays on the National Mall and the Washington Monument during the period beginning on December 31, 2025, and ending on January 5, 2026; and

H.R. 1512, the “Taiwan Assurance Implementation Act,” which permanently extends existing requirements for the Department of State to review and report on its guidance to Executive Branch agencies and offices on relations with Taiwan.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-h-j-res-133-and-h-r-1512-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification Initiative</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/u-s-first-lady-melania-trump-welcomes-progress-in-russia-ukraine-childrens-reunification-initiative/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyU.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification InitiativeThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First LadyU.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification InitiativeThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First LadyU.S. First Lady Melania Trump Welcomes Progress in Russia – Ukraine Children’s Reunification InitiativeThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Seven additional children—six boys and one girl—have been reunited with their families in Ukraine. The following is a statement from the First Lady of the United States, Melania Trump, regarding the humanitarian efforts of all parties participating in this initiative.

“My dedication to guaranteeing the safe return of children to their families in this region is unwavering.

“I commend the leadership and persistent diplomacy of Russia and Ukraine in the pursuit of the reunification of children and families. Their bridge-building has created a tangible collaborative environment—an anchor for optimism. This cooperation will continue to drive the process forward through the next phase.

“In close partnership, my representative and I have provided humanitarian support from the United States to enhance the reunification initiative’s outcome. My hope is that, ultimately, our collective efforts will lead to broader regional stability.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/u-s-first-lady-melania-trump-welcomes-progress-in-russia-ukraine-childrens-reunification-initiative/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair House</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-emphasizes-the-importance-of-upholding-americas-storied-institutions-at-the-blair-house/</link>
      <description>Office of the First ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair HouseThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair HouseThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First ladyFirst Lady Melania Trump Emphasizes the Importance of Upholding America’s Storied Institutions at the Blair HouseThe White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Office of the First lady

The White HouseDecember 4, 2025

Today, First Lady Melania Trump delivered remarks at the Blair House for a holiday reception by the Blair House Foundation and the Friends of Blair House. The Blair House, originally constructed in 1824, is steeped in American tradition.

“The Blair House has hosted some of the world’s most influential leaders, including kings, queens, presidents, and prime ministers. As America’s 250th anniversary approaches, we must consider the important role our nation’s institutions have played in shaping our core values. The Blair House, in particular, has been a beacon of dignity, cultural awareness, and attention to detail. America’s institutions, including the Blair House, honor legacy while transcending generations,” said First Lady Melania Trump.

Blair House, known as the President’s Guest House, fills a central and historic role in welcoming foreign leaders as they prepare for engagements at the White House. Mrs. Trump emphasized its significant as a place where relationships begin, trust is built, and diplomatic partnerships take shape.

Full Remarks by First Lady Melania Trump, As Prepared for Delivery:

Good afternoon, and thank you all for being here. It is a pleasure to join you during this beautiful Christmas season, and it is an honor to welcome you to Blair House.

Blair House holds a special place in the life of our nation. For generations, this residence has been the quiet, dignified bridge between the White House and the world. It has offered warmth, security, and hospitality to kings and queens, presidents and prime ministers, and leaders from every corner of the globe.

Blair House is an American institution. Built in the 1800’s, this structure’s legacy transcends generations. As we prepare to celebrate America’s 250th anniversary, we should reflect on the important role our institutions play in shaping our nation’s values.  Moreover, we must strive to do more than merely preserve our institutions, we must grow them with innovation so that each can shine for future generations.

Today, we celebrate not only this historic home, but the people who make its mission possible. Your generosity preserves a tradition of American hospitality.

As First Lady, it is a privilege to once again be part of this special chapter of American history. Blair House represents grace, stability, and the confidence of a nation that leads with strength, courtesy and kindness.

I am grateful to each of you – including the Blair House Foundation Board of Trustees and Chair, Sarah Perot, for your dedication to this cause. You help protect a place where diplomacy begins long before the cameras arrive and where friendships between nations can begin to take root.

Thank you again and best wishes to you and your families for a very Merry Christmas, Happy Hannukah, and a joyful and peaceful New Year.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-emphasizes-the-importance-of-upholding-americas-storied-institutions-at-the-blair-house/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-visits-childrens-national-hospital-in-washington-d-c/</link>
      <description>Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First LadyFirst Lady Melania Trump Visits Children’s National Hospital in Washington, D.C.The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First Lady

The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Today, First Lady Melania Trump continued the longstanding annual tradition of first ladies visiting the Children’s National Hospital during the Christmas season. Mrs. Trump spent time with young patients and their families to support the courageous children receiving care.

Mrs. Trump began her visit in the hospital’s atrium and continued on to the Hematology and Oncology Unit. She readHow Does Santa Go Down the Chimney?to a small group of young patients and their families. Throughout her visit, Mrs. Trump spoke with patients, families, doctors, nurses, and administrative staff, offering words of encouragement during this special time of year.

Following her visit, the First Lady remarked, “Visiting Children’s National during the Christmas season is a tradition I cherish, and I am grateful for the opportunity to return again this year. Spending time with these brave children and their families is a reminder of the strength, hope, and love that define the holiday spirit. I want to thank the dedicated doctors, nurses, and staff at Children’s National for the exceptional care they provide during the holiday season and every day.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/first-lady-melania-trump-visits-childrens-national-hospital-in-washington-d-c/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention Month</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-impaired-driving-prevention-month/</link>
      <description>Office of the First ladyPresidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention MonthThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First ladyPresidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention MonthThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First ladyPresidential Message on National Impaired Driving Prevention MonthThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Office of the First lady

The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Every year, thousands of Americans are injured or killed by reckless drivers under the influence of alcohol and drugs.  This National Impaired Driving Prevention Month, we send our prayers and unending support to every American who has lost a loved one—and we reaffirm our commitment to preventing drug and alcohol abuse on our roads, protecting American lives, and making America safe, healthy, and strong.

Drugs and alcohol distort judgment, reduce reaction time, and compromise the ability to make safe decisions behind the wheel.  Impaired driving tragically claims an American life every 42 minutes.  For this reason, my Administration is working tirelessly to end the substance abuse crisis once and for all.

Since I returned to office, I have taken a series of bold and unprecedented steps to halt the flow of illegal drugs into our country by securing our borders and increasing support for law enforcement.  Under my leadership, the Office of National Drug Control Policy is taking action to address and prevent substance use disorders and disrupt the criminal networks that fuel them.  We are investing hundreds of millions of dollars in programs like the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program and the Drug-Free Communities Support Program to dismantle drug trafficking organizations and restore order and safety to our streets.  My Administration is also working to increase access to treatment so that every American battling drug and alcohol use has a path to total recovery and we will continue working with our partners in the states to raise awareness through high visibility enforcement campaigns, such asDrive Sober or Get Pulled Over.

This month, we remember all those whose lives were stolen by impaired drivers.  We extend our gratitude to the heroic police officers, first responders, healthcare workers, and local organizations who are working on the front lines to prevent these catastrophes.  Above all, we recommit to preventing these senseless tragedies—and we renew our resolve to never waver in putting the safety, health, and well-being of the American people first.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/presidential-message-on-national-impaired-driving-prevention-month/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into Law</title>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-j-res-80-signed-into-law/</link>
      <description>Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Briefings &amp; StatementsCongressional Bills S.J.Res. 80 Signed into LawThe White HouseDecember 5, 2025

Briefings &amp; Statements

The White HouseDecember 5, 2025

On Friday, December 5, 2025, the President signed into law:

S.J.Res. 80, which nullifies a Bureau of Land Management rule relating to “National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska Integrated Activity Plan Record of Decision.”</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/2025/12/congressional-bills-s-j-res-80-signed-into-law/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
